<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 2-The Nature of Stock on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 2-The Nature of Stock on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Austerity Versus Public Spending</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-3d/</guid>
      <description>37 Frugality increases the public capital and prodigality reduces it.
Capitals neither increase nor decrease when revenues match expenses. Some modes of expence contribute more to the growth of public opulence than others.
38 The person&amp;rsquo;s revenue may be spent in either:
 non-durable things which are consumed immediately, or The revenue spent this way daily can neither alleviate nor support the next day&amp;rsquo;s expence. durable things which can be accumulated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Notes vs Promissory Notes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2i/</guid>
      <description>95 A paper money consisting in bank notes is equal in value to gold and silver money when it is:
 issued by people of undoubted credit, payable on demand without any condition, always readily paid as soon as presented, and equal in value to gold and silver, since gold and silver money can be had for it at any time.  Whatever is bought or sold for such paper must be bought or sold as cheap as it could have been for gold and silver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Operations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2e/</guid>
      <description>49 Other than the common business expenses, such as the cost of house-rent, wages of servants, clerks, accountants, etc., a bank&amp;rsquo;s expenses consist chiefly in:
The expence of keeping a large amount at all times in its coffers for answering the occasional demands of the holders of its notes.
 This amount pays no interest. The expence of replenishing those coffers as fast as they are emptied when answering those occasional demands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Operations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2g/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2g/</guid>
      <description>Ayr Bank 73 In the midst of this clamour and distress, a new bank was established in Scotland to relieve the country&amp;rsquo;s distress.
The design was generous but the execution was imprudent. It did not understand the nature and causes of the distress it meant to relieve. This bank was more liberal in granting cash accounts and in discounting bills of exchange than any other bank. It discounted all bills equally, including real and circulating bills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central Banks - The Bank of England</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2h/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2h/</guid>
      <description>79 The Bank of England is the biggest bank of circulation in Europe.
It was incorporated by a charter under the Great Seal on July 27, 1694. It then lent to government £1.2 million in exchange for an annuity of £100,000 composed of:
 £96,000 interest or 8% [1.2m * 0.08], and £4,000 annually for management expenses.  The Glorious Revolution established a new government which had a very low credit because it was obliged to borrow at so high an interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circulating Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-1c-circulating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-1c-circulating/</guid>
      <description>18 The third division is the circulating capital.
It only affords a revenue by circulating or changing masters.
It is composed of four parts:
19 The money which circulates and distributes the three other stocks to their proper consumers. 20 The stock of food owned by the butcher, farmer, wheat-merchant, brewer, etc. 21 The unfinished products (clothes, furniture, and building) which remain with the growers, manufacturers, drapers, timber merchants, carpenters and joiners, brick-makers, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computing the Net Domestic Product</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2c/</guid>
      <description>37 When we compute the amount of industry which a society&amp;rsquo;s circulating capital can employ, we must account only the provisions, materials, and finished work.
The circulating capital which consists in money, and which only circulates those three, must always be deducted. Three things are needed to mobilize industry:
 materials to work on, tools to work with, and wages or recompense for the work done.  Money is neither a material to work on, nor a tool to work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discounted Bills of Exchange</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2d/</guid>
      <description>Cash Accounts 44 Scotland’s commerce is not very great at present. It was smaller when the first two banks were established. Those banks would have had little trade had they confined their business to discounting of bills of exchange.
They invented cash accounts &amp;ndash; another method of issuing their promissory notes.
 They give credit (£2,000-3,000 for example) to anyone who could procure two persons of undoubted credit and good landed estate to become surety for him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing and Redrawing</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2f/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2f/</guid>
      <description>65 It is now more than 25 years since the paper money issued by the Scottish banks was more than fully equal to what the national circulation could easily absorb and employ.
Those banks gave more than all the assistance possible to Scottish traders and entrepreneurs. The traders and entrepreneurs had overtraded a little. They brought themselves either a loss or a profit reduction which always results from the smallest degree of overtrading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment of capitals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-5a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-5a/</guid>
      <description>1 The destiny of all capitals is to maintain productive labour.
But the amount of that labour varies extremely according to:
 the diversity of their employment and the value it adds to the national annual produce.  2 A capital may be employed in four ways:
 In procuring the rude produce required for society&amp;rsquo;s use and consumption   Examples are the capitals used in improving or cultivating lands, mines, or fisheries  In manufacturing and preparing that rude produce for immediate use and consumption   Examples are the capitals of all master manufacturers  In transporting the rude or manufactured produce from where they abound to where they are wanted   Examples are the capitals of all wholesale merchants  In dividing portions of rude or manufactured produce into small parcels for those who want them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Trade, Foreign Trade, Carrying Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-5b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-5b/</guid>
      <description>24 Wholesale trade is the buying and selling by wholesale.
It may be reduced to three kinds:
  The home-trade   This is the purchase of local produce in one part of a country to sell in another part of the same country. It includes the inland and the coasting trade.
 The foreign trade of consumption   This is the purchase of foreign goods for home-consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money as Part of the General Stock of Society</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2a-ndp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2a-ndp/</guid>
      <description>1 Book 1 showed that the price of commodities is made up of rent, wages, and profit.
 There are some commodities which has a price made up of wages and profits only. There are very few in which it consists in wages only.  The price of every commodity resolves itself into some one, or other, or all of these three parts. If it goes neither to rent nor wages, then it goes to somebody&amp;rsquo;s profit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productive vs Unproductive Labour</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Production vs Services 1 Productive labour adds value while unproductive labour does not. The labour of a manufacturer adds to:
 the value of the materials which he works on, the value of his own maintenance, and the value of his master&amp;rsquo;s profit.  On the contrary, the labour of a menial servant adds to the value of nothing.
The manufacturing worker costs nothing to his employer even though the employer pays his wages, because the value of his wages is restored with a profit in the improved value of his manufactured products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purchasing Power is Real Wealth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-2b/</guid>
      <description>15 Only the ambiguity of language makes this proposition doubtful or paradoxical. It is obvious when properly understood.
16 When we talk of a sum of money, we sometimes only mean the metal pieces it is made of. Sometimes we include in our meaning some obscure reference to the purchasing power it conveys.
This power is the goods which can be bought with it.
When we say that England&amp;rsquo;s circulating money is £18 million, we only mean the amount of metal pieces which circulate in England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Lent At Interest</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>1 The stock lent at interest is always considered as a capital by its lender.
He expects that:
 it will be restored to him in due time the borrower will pay him a rent for using it  The borrower may use it as a capital or as a stock for immediate consumption. If he uses it as a capital, he employs it to maintain productive labourers.
In this case, he can restore the capital and pay the interest without encroaching on any other source of revenue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Savings and Prudence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-3b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-3b/</guid>
      <description>13 The proportion between industry and idleness is regulated by the proportion between capital and revenue.
Wherever capital predominates, industry prevails. Wherever revenue, idleness.
Therefore, every increase or reduction of capital naturally increases or reduce the real amount of industry.
Capital affects the number of productive hands. The number of productive hands affects the real wealth and revenue of all its inhabitants.
14 Capitals are increased by parsimony and decreased by prodigality and misconduct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Propensity to Save</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-3c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-3c/</guid>
      <description>The Origin of the Propensity to Save 28 Regarding profusion, the passion for present enjoyment is the principle which prompts to spend.
It is sometimes violent and very difficult to restrain. Generally, it is only momentary and occasional. The desire of bettering our condition is the principle which prompts to save. It is a desire which is generally calm and dispassionate. It comes with us from birth and never leaves us until we die.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stock for Consumption and Fixed Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-1b-fixed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-1b-fixed/</guid>
      <description>The Stock for Consumption 12 The first is the part reserved for immediate consumption.
It affords no revenue or profit. It is made up of the stock of food, clothes, furniture, etc. which have been bought but not yet entirely consumed.
Houses The whole stock of houses makes a part of this first division.
The stock laid out in a house ceases from being a capital or from affording any revenue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Divisions of Stock</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-1a-capitals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-2/chapter-1a-capitals/</guid>
      <description>Fixed Capital, Circulating Capital, and Stock for Consumption 1 When a man&amp;rsquo;s stock can only maintain him for a few weeks, he seldom thinks of deriving any revenue from it.
 He consumes it as sparingly as he can. He tries to acquire new supplies before it is consumed.  In this case, his revenue is derived from his labour only. This is the state of most of the labouring poor in all countries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
