<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 3 on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 3 on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Consumption Taxes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-3/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-3/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Taxes on possessions are naturally equal. But taxes on consumptions are naturally unequal. Sometimes they are paid by:
 the merchant the consumer, or the importer, who must be repaid it by the consumer.  In Holland, all goods are deposited in a public warehouse, one key of which is kept by the commissioner of the customs, and another by the owner of the goods. If the goods are exported, no tax is advanced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock-jobbing</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-3/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-3/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>The practice of stock-jobbing is the buying stocks by time.
It also has a very big influence on the rise and fall of stocks. A man who only has £1,000 subscribes for £100,000, which is delivered:
 at several fixed times, and in certain portions.  He hopes to sell these portions at profit by the rising of the stocks before they fall. But since his worth would go down if the stocks fall, he does everything to make them rise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stocks</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-3/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-3/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Soon after the Revolution, the government needed to borrow money from its subjects at a higher rate than common interest.
It had to be repaid in a few years. The funds to pay this interest were taxes on certain commodities. These taxes were at first laid on for a certain number of years, according to the term for which the money was borrowed. But these loans became perpetual by various arts of government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxes on Possessions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-3/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-3/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>After the appropriation of land property, some lands were commonly assigned to maintain the government. The free states of Greece had land set apart for this purpose.
Aristotle thought that private property should surround the royal lands because:
 the people near a city were always for war, they were sure of defence, and the enemy would first come upon those lands near the boundaries  In all barbarous countries, lands are appropriated to the purposes of sovereignty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Influence of Commerce on Manners</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-3/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-3/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>How does commerce influence the people&amp;rsquo;s manners?
Whenever commerce is introduced into any country, probity and punctuality always accompany it. These virtues are almost unknown in a rude and barbarous country.
Of all the European nations, the Dutch are:
 the most commercial, and the most faithful to their word.  The English are more so than the Scotch, but much inferior to the Dutch.
In the remote parts of Britain, they are far less so than in its commercial parts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
