<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Nature of International Commercial Laws on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Nature of International Commercial Laws on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alexander&#39;s Conquest</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>FOUR great events happened in the reign of Alexander, which entirely changed the face of commerce:
 The taking of Tyre The conquest of Egypt The conquest of India The discovery of the Indian Ocean  The empire of Persia extended to the Indus. Darius, long before Alexander, had sent some vessels down this river and passed even into the Red sea.
How then were the Greeks the first who traded to the Indies by the south?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commerce after the Destruction of the Western Empire</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>Commerce was destroyed after the fall of the Roman empire. The barbarous nations at first saw it only as an opportunity for robbery. When they had subdued the Romans, they honoured it no more than agriculture, and the other professions of a conquered people.
Soon, the commerce of Europe almost entirely lost. The nobility, who had every where the direction of affairs, were in no pain about it.
The laws of the Visigoths permitted private people to occupy half the beds of great rivers, provided the other half remained free for nets and boats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Commerce of the Ancients</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Semiramis had immense treasures which could not be acquired in a day. It means that the Assyrians had pillaged other rich nations, as other nations afterwards pillaged them.
 The effect of commerce is riches. The effect of riches is luxury The effect of luxury is the perfection of arts  The arts were carried to great perfection in Semiramis&#39; time. This shows that a considerable commerce was then established.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Commerce of the Greek Kings after the Death of Alexander</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>When Alexander conquered Egypt, they only had an imperfect idea of the Red sea and none of the Indian ocean. They thought it impossible to sail around the Arabian peninsula.
People tried from each side but failed. They said: &amp;ldquo;How can we navigate to the southern coast of Arabia? Cambyses’s army traversed it on the north side and almost entirely perished. Ptolemy, the son of Lagus, sent forces to aid Seleucus Nicator at Babylon and underwent incredible hardships and could march only at night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Commerce of the Greeks</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>THE first Greeks were all pirates.
Minos was a pirate who enjoyed the empire of his own isle. But when the Greeks became a great people, the Athenians obtained the real dominion of the sea; because this trading and victorious nation gave laws to the most potent monarch of that time; and humbled the maritime powers of Syria, of the isle of Cyprus, and Phœnicia.
Xenophon says “Athens rules the sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Commerce of the Romans with the Barbarians</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>THE Romans erected a vast empire in Europe, Asia, and Africa.
The weakness of the people and the tyranny of their laws united this immense body. The Roman policy was then to avoid all communication with those nations whom they had not subdued. The fear of carrying to them the art of conquering, made them neglect the art of enriching themselves. They made laws to hinder all commerce with barbarians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Isle of Delos and Mithridates</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>UPON the destruction of Corinth by the Romans, the merchants retired to Delos island, which was a place of safety. It was extremely well situated for the commerce of Italy and Asia, which, since the reduction of Africa, and the weakening of Greece, was grown more important.
From the earliest times, the Greeks sent colonies to Propontis and to the Euxine sea:
Those colonies retained their laws and liberties under the Persians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The principal Difference between the Commerce of the Ancients and the Moderns</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Commerce has changed through time.
European trade is currently carried on principally from the north to the south. The difference of climate is the cause that the several nations have great occasion for the merchandizes of each other. For example, the liquors of the south, which are carried to the north, form a commerce little known to the ancients. Thus the burden of vessels, which was formerly computed by measures of corn, is at present determined by tons of liquor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Riches which Spain drew from America</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>Spain has derived so many advantages from the American trade.
She drew from the Americas so much gold and silver that we had before. But no one expected that Spain would have misfortunes.
Philip II succeeded Charles V. He was obliged to make the celebrated bankruptcy known to all the world. There never was a prince who suffered more from the murmurs, the insolence, and the revolt of troops constantly ill paid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The wants of the People in the South are different from those of the North</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>In Europe, there is a kind of balance between the southern and northern nations.
Southern nations have every convenience of life, and few of its wants. Nature has given them much, and demands but little.
Northern nations have many wants, and few conveniencies. She has given but little, and demands a lot
The equilibrium is maintained by:
 the laziness of the southern nations, and the industry and activity of the north.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carthage and Marseilles</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>THE law of nations which obtained at Carthage, was very extraordinry: all strangers, who traded to Sardinia and towards Hercules’s pillars, this haughty republic sentenced to be drowned.
Her civil polity was equally surprizing. She forbid the Sardinians to cultivate their lands, upon pain of death. She increased her power by her riches, and afterwards her riches by her power. She extended herself along the ocean. The senate of Carthage ordered Hanno to distribute 30,000 Carthaginians from the Strait of Gibraltar as far as Cerne.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General laws on Commerce; Africa</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Commerce is subject to great revolutions. Yet its nature may be forever fixed by physical causes such as:
 the quality of the soil or the climate  We currently trade with India merely through the silver which we send. The Romans annually had a trade volume with India of about 50,000,000 sesterces in exchange for Indian merchandise
It is Nature itself that produces this effect. The Indians have their arts adapted to their manner of living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Circuit of Africa</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Before the discovery of the compass, four attempts were made to sail round the coast of Africa.
 Necho and Eudoxus of the Phoenicians fled the wrath of Ptolomy Lathyrus   They set out from the Red sea, and succeeded  Sataspes was sent by Xerxes from Gibraltar and failed Hanno was sent by the Carthaginians also set from Gibraltar and failed  They aimed to discover and go around the cape of Good-hope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Commerce broke through Europe&#39;s Barbarism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s philosophy was carried to the west. It pleased the subtile geniuses, who were the virtuosi of those times of ignorance.
The theologians condemned the Jewish notions of lending at interest absolutely and in all cases. Hence commerce, which was the profession only of mean persons, became that of knaves, because whenever a thing is forbidden, which nature permits or necessity requires, those who do it are looked upon as dishonest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Europe was Affected by the Discovery of Two New Worlds</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-21/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>The compass opened the universe.
Asia and Africa were found, of which only some borders were known; and America, of which we knew nothing.
The Portuguese discovered the southernmost point of Africa. They saw a vast sea, which carried them to India.
Camoens writes about:
 their danger on this sea, the discovery of Mozambique, Melinda, and Calcutta  His poems make us feel something of:
 the charms of the Odyssey, and the magnificence of the Æneid.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
