<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Laws Should Be Relative To The Principle Of Government on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Laws Should Be Relative To The Principle Of Government on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Governance Laws should be Relative to the Type of Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-5/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-5/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>The laws of governance should be relative to the principle of each government, just as the laws of education are.
The relation of laws to this principle strengthens the several springs of government. This principle derives from thence, in its turn, a new degree of vigour.
And thus it is, in mechanics, that action is al ways followed by re-action.
We examine this relation in each government, beginning with the republican state, whose principle is virtue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Laws are in Monarchies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-5/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-5/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>AS honour is the principle of a monarchical government, the laws ought to be relative to this principle.
They should endeavour to support the nobility; in respect to whom, honour may be, in some measure, deemed both child and parent.
They should render the nobility hereditary; not as a boundary between the power of the prince and the weakness of the people, but as the link which connects them both.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Laws Should be in an Aristocracy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-5/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-5/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>IF the people are virtuous in an aristocracy, they enjoy very near the same happiness as in a popular government, an d the state grows powerful. But, as a great share of virtue is very rare wh ere mens Edition: current; Pa ge: [64] fortunes are so unequal, the laws must tend as much as possible t o infuse a spirit of moderation, and endeavour to re-establish that equalit y which was necessarily removed by the constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Consequences of the Principles of the three Governments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-5/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-5/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 19: New Consequences of the Principles of the three Governments Question 1: Should the laws oblige a subject to accept of a public employment? They should in a republic, but not in a monarchical government.
In a republic, public employments are attestations of virtue, depositums with which a citizen is entrusted by his country, for whose sake alone he ought to live, to act, and to think; consequently, he cannot refuse them¶.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Communication of Power</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-5/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-5/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 16: The Communication of Power IN a despotic government, the power is communicated entire to the person intrusted with it. The vizir himself is the despotic prince; and each particular officer is the vizir. In monarchies, the power is less immediately applied, being tempered by the monarch as he gives it‡. He makes such a distribution of his authority, as never to communicate a part of it without reserving a greater share to himself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Excellence of a monarchical government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-5/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-5/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 13-18: Despotic Power WHEN the savages of Louisiana are desirous of fruit, they cut the tree to the root, and gather the Edition: current; Page: [74] fruit.* This is an emblem of despotic government.
Chapter 14: How the Laws are relative to the Principles of despotic Government.↩ THE principle of despotic government is fear. A timid, ignorant, and faint-spirited people have no occasion for many laws.
Everything should depend here on two or three ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
