<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Medical Superphysics on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/medical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Medical Superphysics on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/articles/medical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Discover your past life via the internet</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/medical/discover-your-past-life-via-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/medical/discover-your-past-life-via-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>Both Socrates and Hinduism-Buddhism have given proof for reincarnation. We will implement this in a social network timeline that will match its users to its possible past-life user profile, while staying within data retention laws.
If the immortal is also imperishable, then the soul when attacked by death cannot perish. The Simple Phaedo by Plato  It would be easier to find a goal and increase your productivity in this life if you could pick up where you left off in your past life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Smith on Vegetarian Diets</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/medical/adam-smith-on-vegetarian-diets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/medical/adam-smith-on-vegetarian-diets/</guid>
      <description>The recent trend in extreme weather, as seen in El Nino, in the drought in California, and in supertyphoons, has proven that climate change is here and that it can get worse if nothing is done.
Unnatural climate change is caused by excessive greenhouse gases, best represented by carbon dioxide (CO2) from human activity. Though a lot of CO2 emissions come from energy and transportation, food production also contributes greatly to it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
