<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Supersociology is a branch of Social Superphysics and is sociology combined with the metaphysics from Socrates, Adam Smith, and David Hume on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/supersociology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Supersociology is a branch of Social Superphysics and is sociology combined with the metaphysics from Socrates, Adam Smith, and David Hume on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/supersociology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is the Common Interest?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/supersociology/common-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/supersociology/common-interest/</guid>
      <description>A soul manifests in the physical dimension through a physical body which can be thought of as its vehicle. To maintain itself, the soul develops two things:
 an ego which is needed to drive action in physical existence a sense called a conscience to regulate that ego to keep it within its dharma. This sense leads to personal morals or personal do&amp;rsquo;s and dont&amp;rsquo;s while the soul is in the duality of physical existence  Souls can then bind themselves into a new entity called a society which gets its own soul from the individual souls that make it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fourth Branch of Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/supersociology/fourth-branch-of-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/supersociology/fourth-branch-of-government/</guid>
      <description>Ever since the French Revolution, there have been three branches of government:
 Legislative - this branch is the most important branch as it creates the laws Executive - this branch executes laws and is the most visible one Judicial - this branch settles legal conflicts  If we view society as a family and the government as the parents, then the legislative and executive are the father, while the judicial is the mother.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Civilizations Collapse</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/supersociology/how-civilizations-collapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/supersociology/how-civilizations-collapse/</guid>
      <description>Societies are created when indvidual people come together under a common interest to achieve something. For example:
 a group of military countries form an alliance for mutual defense or to attack another country a group of criminals agree to join forces to be a crime syndicate a group of teenagers agree to meet after school to start a rock band  All such alliances, syndicates, and bands are societies that require its members to agree to be part of the group or project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
