<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 5: Leadership on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 5: Leadership on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Female Guardians and their Children</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-5/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-5/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Women Should be Allowed Equal Occupations with Men Such is the good and true City or State. The good and true man has the same pattern. If this is right then every other is wrong. The evil is one which affects not only the order of the State, but also the regulation of the individual soul, and is exhibited in four forms.  I was about to tell how the four evil forms succeed one another, when Polemarchus, sitting just beyond Adeimantus, began to whisper to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Versus Opinion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-5/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-5/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Socrates: Then let us enact this law that our guardians are neither to devastate the lands of Hellenes nor to burn their houses.  Glaucon: Yes, these and all our previous enactments, are very good. But how can it be done? Your citizens will be the bravest of warriors. They will all know one another and will call the other father, brother, son. If the women will join their armies then they will be absolutely invincible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unity of Society and the Training of Children</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-5/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-5/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Unity is the greatest good What should be the chief aim of the legislator of a State? What is the greatest good and the greatest evil? Discord, distraction, and plurality is the greatest evil where there should be unity. The bond of unity is the greatest good. There is unity where there is community of pleasures and pains, where all the citizens are glad or grieved on the same occasions of joy and sorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
