<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yogic Treatments on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/indian/yogic-treatments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Yogic Treatments on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/indian/yogic-treatments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Acidity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/indian/yogic-treatments/acidity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/indian/yogic-treatments/acidity/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms Physical weakness, acidic or watery belching, dizziness, burning stomach, heartburn
Cause Oxygen inhaled in breathing enters the body and eventually turns into carbon dioxide. This carbon dioxide activates the digestive fluid-secreting glands.
It becomes impossible for the digestive fluid to digest the food properly when:
 food is taken irregularly and excessively day after day food is forced down with little or no appetite eating rich food becomes a steady habit  The undigested food turns into poisonous gas and the secreted digestive fluid gradually turns into harmful acid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appendicitis</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/indian/yogic-treatments/appendicitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/indian/yogic-treatments/appendicitis/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms Swelling of the appendix and simultaneous unbearable pain in the abdominal region; fear of eating in spite of appetite or desire for food.
Causes Aversion to physical labour, spending much time indoors, not taking part in sports and exercises, constipation; such short-comings, along with overeating.
Treatment Ásanas, mudrás, diet and dos and don’ts are the same as for dyspepsia patients. With appendicitis, fibrous foods, all types of non-vegetarian foods, atapa rice (a fine-quality, very white type of rice) and all foods that cause constipation are strictly forbidden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dysentery</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/indian/yogic-treatments/dysentery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/indian/yogic-treatments/dysentery/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms Repeated need to defecate but small movement, urge to strain while defecating, pain in the navel region, etc. Causes: Undigested half-cooked or uncooked meat or pulses or such things, when mixed with contaminated air in the stomach, cause an abnormal reaction in the intestine, and when the pitta, in spite of its best efforts, fails to digest these things, they come out in the form of loose movement. But if this loose movement does not take its natural course, then those materials start to decompose inside the colon in an ugly way, and begin to decay the mucous membrane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haemorrhoids (Piles)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/indian/yogic-treatments/haemorrhoids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/indian/yogic-treatments/haemorrhoids/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms “Developed piles” happens when contaminated gas and blood cannot get out of the body. This causes pressure on the veins and capillaries around the anus which becomes swollen. “External piles” are those outside the anus. &amp;ldquo;Internal piles&amp;rdquo; are those inside the anus.
“Bleeding piles” happen when blood oozes out of the developed piles under pressure of the Apána Váyu (vital energy controlling the lower abdominal organs).
“Dry piles” are piles which do not bleed but are instead painful, aching, burning or itching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hernia</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/indian/yogic-treatments/hernia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/indian/yogic-treatments/hernia/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms When undigested food builds up offensive internal gas puts a severe strain on the intestine which gets dislodged from its normal position. It opens a hold in the abdominal wall, and protrudes through it.
“Inguinal hernia” is the dislodged intestine coming out through an opening left in the canal to the scrotum.
“Femoral hernia” happens if it pushes out through the hole in the canal of nerve fibres and the muscular network controlling the legs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rheumatism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/indian/yogic-treatments/rheumatism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/indian/yogic-treatments/rheumatism/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Pain in joints  Cause  Acidity  Dos  20 min sunbathing + wet wipe castor oil with salt on area asofatida + sajane gum on area garlic + ginger + apamarga on area pork on area drink triphala + ginger  Don&amp;rsquo;ts  don&amp;rsquo;t eat breakfast and snacks  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
