<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Section 3 of the Simplified Lectures on Jurisprudence by Adam Smith on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Section 3 of the Simplified Lectures on Jurisprudence by Adam Smith on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10: Quasi-Contract</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>A quasi-contract is founded on the duty of restitution.
If you find a watch, you should give it back by the right of property, because a man does not lose property with possession. But if you and I balance accounts, and you pay me but you afterwards find that you did not owe that sum, how will you claim it? You cannot ask for it because you alienated that sum. You cannot claim it by contract, for there never was one made between us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fourth way of acquiring property: Succession</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Succession has two kinds:
  Testamentary   In testamentary succession, the distribution of goods is done according to the will of the deceased.
 Legal   In legal succession, the law distributes the goods of the deceased to those whom the deceased is presumed to have chosen, according to some lawyers. But this supposes that testamentary succession came before legal succession, which is contrary to experience.
In a rude period, a man rarely had the full property of his goods during his lifetime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 11: Delinquency</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>We come now to the third kind of personal rights, those to wit, ex delicto.
Delicts are of two kinds, as they arise ex dolowhen there is a blameable intention, or ex culpawhen they are done through a culpable negligence.
Injury naturally excites the resentment of the spectator, and the punishment of the offender is reasonable as far as the indifferent spectator can go along with it. This is the natural measure of punishment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contracts</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>The obligation of contract is based on the reasonable expectation from a promise. A promise is a declaration that you want the promisee to depend on you to perform it. A promise produces an obligation. Its breach is an injury. A promise is different from a mere declaration of intention.
If I say that I want to do something for you, but I do not do it, then I am not guilty of a breach of promise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entails as Testamentary Succession</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-4b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-4b/</guid>
      <description>Entails engrossed land the most and therefore, it took the longest to be established.
It was very natural to give a man a right to dispose of his property while he lived.
But a testament supposes that he has this right even after death. This right could not be transferred because the heir does not have the same right. Puffendorf whimsically accounts for this from the soul&amp;rsquo;s immortality.
At Rome, the right of making testaments was introduced gradually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive Privileges</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>Exclusive privileges are the last division of real rights. Among these is the right of inheritance. This is not a creature of the civil law, but arises from nature.
The heir has a privilege of demanding what belonged to the deceased. After he is admitted heir, it is his real property. If a person starts to chase a wild beast, he has an exclusive privilege of pursuing it. Whoever comes in on the chase can be punished because he breaks the exclusive privilege.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fifth way of acquiring Property: Voluntary Transference</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Two things are required in voluntary transference:
 A declaration of the intention of the transferer, and of the transferee The actual delivery of the thing.  In most cases, the first of these is not binding without the latter, because there is no right without possession.
If a man borrowed a thing and afterwards bought it, there is no need of delivery because he already has it.
Before possession you can have no right to the thing, though you may have a right to make the man keep his promise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First way of acquiring Property: Occupation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>We divided acquired rights into:
 personal real  property, servitude, pledge, and exclusive privilege.    1. Property Property is acquired five ways.
 By occupation, or the taking possession of what formerly belonged to nobody. By accession, when a man has a right to one thing in consequence of another, as of a horse’s shoes along with the horse. By prescription, which is a right to a thing belonging to another arising from long and uninterrupted possession.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pledges and Mortgages</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Pledges and mortgages are certain securities for the payment of debts.
At first, they could not be claimed as real rights. Afterwards, the law considered them as such.
Pledges properly regard moveable subjects, and mortgages immoveable. If a pledge be not redeemed at a certain time, it is forfeited.
People in bad circumstances are naturally slothful. The negligence of Romans debtors led to the lex commissaria which empowered the creditor to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second way of acquiring Property: Accession</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>The right of accession is not so much founded in its utility as in the impropriety of not joining it to that object on which it has a dependence.
The milk of a cow I have purchased may not be of great value, but it is very improper that another person should have a right to bring up his calf upon it. The most important accessions are in land property. Land property is founded on division or an assignation by the society to a particular person of a right to sow and plant a certain piece of ground.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Servitudes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>The second kind of real rights is servitudes. These are burdens which one man has on another person&amp;rsquo;s property. These rights were at first personal.
They were entered into by a contract between the persons. I need to have a road to the market town. If a man’s estate lies between me and the town, I must bargain with him to have a road through it.
This contract produces only a personal right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third way of acquiring Property: Prescription</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-3/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Prescription is founded on:
 the supposed attachment of the possessor to what he has possessed for a long time, and the supposed detachment of the old possessor to what he no longer has possessed for a long time.  There are four things needed for a right by prescription:
  Bona fides   If a person&amp;rsquo;s right to a thing is bad, then it is alright to deprive him of it Iustus titulus   Some reasonable foundation that the person thinks that a thing is his own, such as a charter of some kind.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
