<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Material Superphysics on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/material/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Material Superphysics on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/material/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spacetime</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/material/spacetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/material/spacetime/</guid>
      <description>The spacetime layer is the second layer of the Greek five layer model. It manifests as the space, size, and age of the universe. It gives the ideas and energies from the aethereal layer a chance to cross over onto physical reality via gravitation.
The creation of gravitational nodes leads to the mutual repulsion between nodes, leading to the perception of space and time.
In terms of creation, this is the second layer that processes ideas into possible energies and matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Universal Relativity?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/material/universal-relativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/material/universal-relativity/</guid>
      <description>In Superphysics, physical existence is made when the aether arbitrarily creates quanta of spacetime or qost*, which are 1-dimensional points, within itself. Each point is a discrete and unique identity filled with an arbitrary amount of qualities as potentiality. These identities push each other to preserve their identity while innumerable qosts are created. The pushing leads to the creation and expansion of physical space, first as 2-dimensional and then into 3-dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Quantum of Spacetime or Qost?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/material/qost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/material/qost/</guid>
      <description>We all know that physical reality exists inside space and time. But how were space and time created?
According to Physics, it was created through a Big Bang which started out as a Singularity that created matter and energy from nothing. So what is the nature of this Singularity? No one is able to answer this.
Superphysics answers that the whole Big Bang paradigm is flawed in the first place because material creation did not originate from a material cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are the Five Layers of Superphysics?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/material/five-layers-of-superphysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/material/five-layers-of-superphysics/</guid>
      <description>Our Five Layers are derived from the Five Elements of the Greeks, Hindus, and Chinese.
 Rank Name Greek-Asian Physics Force Superphysics Force Sample Particle/s Superphysics name-suggestion     0 Metaphysical Metaphysics ? Yang Yin Soul qoi or quantum of idea   1 Aethereal Aether ? Creative force Higgs boson qoa or quantum of aether   2 Spatial Air Spacetime Gravitational force Discrete matter (stars, planets) qost or quantum of spacetime   3 Radiant Fire Electromagnetism Male-Female force Electron, Photon qoe or quantum of electricity, qol or quantum of light   4 Radioactive Water Weak Radioactive force W Z Bosons qor or quantum of radiation   5 Material Earth Strong Nuclear force Gluons qom or quantum of matter     The five layers solve the mysteries of quantum physics (which is based on the radiant or electromagnetic layer) by extending human knowledge onto the higher gravitational (spatial) and aethereal layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spin is the Reflective Ability of Particles</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/material/spin-reflective-ability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/material/spin-reflective-ability/</guid>
      <description>Physics is based on a materialistic interpretation of reality, which is opposite of the metaphysical interpretation by Superphysics.
For example, physics prefers to view things as particles. This is consistent with the atomic model of Democritus and opposite of the musical model of Pythagoras.
 The atomic model was embraced by Newton and Einstein The musical model was embraced by Socrates and Kepler  We continue this musical paradigm by using waves instead of particles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light-based Computing</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/material/light-based-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/material/light-based-computing/</guid>
      <description>Light, as analog waves, carry more data as &amp;ldquo;R-O-Y-G-B-I-V&amp;rdquo; than electrons that can only carry digital binary data as &amp;ldquo;ON-OFF&amp;rdquo; at a time. This analog light data can then be absorbed by glass or semiconductor crystals to be processed by normal computer logic.
This principle was recently proven to be realizable in Germany. In their experiment, intense light pulses of waves ranging from near-infrared to visible orange were used to generate oscillating currents in a chip made with gallium arsenide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electrons are Positive, Protons are Negative</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/material/electrons-are-positive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/material/electrons-are-positive/</guid>
      <description>Have you wondered why negative ions make us feel positive, and positive ions make us feel negative?
That&amp;rsquo;s because electrons are really positively charged! Benjamin Franklin made a mistake when he called electrons as negative. Rather than confuse everyone by calling the negative as positive, we&amp;rsquo;d rather call the negative as &amp;lsquo;feminine charge&amp;rsquo;, the positive as a &amp;lsquo;masculine charge&amp;rsquo;, and neutral as a &amp;lsquo;bisexual charge&amp;rsquo;.
The attraction between protons, electrons, and neutrons intuitively follow this naming convention, just as Shiva is male and Shakti is female.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
