<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Section 3: The Effect of Chance on Morality on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Section 3: The Effect of Chance on Morality on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Cause of the influence of outcome</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-3/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-3/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
1 The morality of any action is due to:
 The heart&amp;rsquo;s intention, or The resulting physical action caused by the intention or The consequences which actually result from the action  These three:
 constitute the whole nature of the action are the foundation of the action&amp;rsquo;s quality.  2 The action and its consequences obviously cannot be the foundation of any praise or blame. The resulting action is often the same either in the most innocent or the most blamable intention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cause of the Irregularity of our Moral Feelings on the outcome of actions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-3/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-3/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>The irregularity in our moral feelings on the outcome is caused by Nature trying to preserve our physical well-being without the uneeded psychological troubles  Translator&amp;rsquo;s note: This part resembles Socrates&#39; argument in the Republic
 24 Such is the effect of an action&amp;rsquo;s consequences on its doer and on others. Chance:
 governs the world has some influence where we should be least willing to allow her any directs mankind&amp;rsquo;s feelings about themselves and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Extent of the Influence of Outcome</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-3/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-3/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>14 When an action, coming from good intentions:
 fails to achieve its expected outcome, our sense of its merit is also reduced exceeds its expected outcome, our sense of its merit is increased  When an action, coming from bad intentions:
 fails to achieve its expected outcome, our sense of its demerit is also reduced. exceeds its expected outcome, our sense of its demerit is increased.  15 A friend is someone whom we can ask for favors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
