<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 2: The Nature and Origin of the Mind, God and Ideas on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 2: The Nature and Origin of the Mind, God and Ideas on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Definitions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-2/definitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-2/definitions/</guid>
      <description>I now explain the results from God&amp;rsquo;s essence, which are able to lead us, as it were by the hand, to the knowledge of the human mind and its highest blessedness.
Definitions   Body is a mode which expresses in a certain determinate manner the essence of God, in so far as he is considered as an extended thing. (See Pt. 1, Prop. 25, Coroll.)
  A thing&amp;rsquo;s essence is that which inseparable from the thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 1 to 10</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-2/propositions-1-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-2/propositions-1-10/</guid>
      <description>1. Thought is an attribute of God, or God is a thinking thing. 2. Extension is an attribute of God, or God is an extended thing. 3. In God, there is necessarily the idea of his essence and also of all things which necessarily follow from his essence. 4. The idea of God, from which an infinite number of things follow in infinite ways, can only be one. 5. The actual being of ideas owns God as its cause, only as he is considered as a thinking thing, not as he is unfolded in any other attribute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 11 to 20</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-2/propositions-11-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-2/propositions-11-20/</guid>
      <description>11. The first element, which constitutes the actual being of the human mind, is the idea of some particular thing actually existing. 12. Whatsoever comes to pass in the object of the idea, which constitutes the human mind, must be perceived by the human mind, or there will necessarily be an idea in the human mind of the said occurrence. That is, if the object of the idea constituting the human mind be a body, nothing can take place in that body without being perceived by the mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 21 to 30</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-2/propositions-21-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-2/propositions-21-30/</guid>
      <description>21. This idea of the mind is united to the mind in the same way as the mind is united to the body. 22. The human mind perceives not only the modifications of the body, but also the ideas of such modifications. The mind does not know itself, except in so far as it perceives the ideas of the modifications of the body.  The human mind does not involve an adequate knowledge of the parts composing the human body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 31 to 49</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-2/propositions-31-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-2/propositions-31-49/</guid>
      <description>Part 2: Common ideas We can only have a very inadequate knowledge of the duration of particular things external to ourselves.  Corollary: Hence it follows that all particular things are contingent and perishable.
 All ideas, in so far as they are referred to God, are true. Proof: All ideas which are in God agree in every respect with their objects (2.7. Coroll.), therefore (1. Ax. 6) they are all true.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
