<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 2: Society on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 2: Society on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Economics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-2/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-2/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Socrates&#39; Division of Labour I had always admired the genius of Glaucon and his brother Adeimantus. The admirer of Glaucon called them as &amp;ldquo;Sons of an illustrious father, Sons of Ariston divine offspring of an illustrious hero&amp;rdquo; after they had distinguished themselves at the battle of Megara
There is something truly divine in you arguing for the superiority of injustice, and remaining unconvinced by your own arguments. But the greater my confidence in you, the greater is my difficulty in knowing what to say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice Versus Injustice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-2/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-2/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>The Three Kinds of Positives I thought I was ending the discussion. But in reality, it proved to be only a beginning. Glaucon is always the most pugnacious of men. He was dissatisfied at Thrasymachus&#39; retirement and wanted to have the battle out.
Glaucon: Socrates, you have not persuaded us that to be just is always better than to be unjust. There are three kinds of positives:   Those which are desired for their own sakes, and independently of their consequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Moral Education of Guardians</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-2/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-2/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Thus, we have found the desired natures. How are they to be reared and educated? This education can prevent injustice from growing in States.  The State Should Censor Immoral and Untruthful Literature and Arts We shall do this by story-telling, and our story shall be the education of our heroes. The best education is traditional education, which is made up of: - Gymnastics for the body, and - Music and literature, both true and false, for the soul.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
