<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Consequences Of The Three Principles Of Governments With Respect To Sumptuary Laws, Luxury and Women on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-7/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Consequences Of The Three Principles Of Governments With Respect To Sumptuary Laws, Luxury and Women on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Consequences of the Principles of the three Governments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-7/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-7/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>LUXURY indicates the inequality of fortunes.
If the riches of a state are equally divided, there will be no luxury, because luxury is founded merely on the inconveniences from the labour of others.
In order to have this equal distribution of riches, the law should give to each man only what is necessary for nature. If they exceed these bounds, some will spend, and others will acquire. These will lead to inequality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Consequences of the Principles of the three Governments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-7/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-7/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 6: The Luxury of China SUMPTUARY laws might be necessary in some governments.
The population may grow so large because of the climate. The uncertainty of food might render a universal application to agriculture extremely necessary.
Luxury, in such countries, is dangerous. This would cause their sumptuary laws to be very severe.
In order, therefore, to be able to judge whether luxury ou ght to be encouraged or proscribed, we should examine, first, what relation there is between the number of people and the facility they have of procur ing subsistence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Continency</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-7/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-7/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>SO many are the imperfections that attend the loss of virtue in women, and so greatly are their minds depraved when this principal guard is removed, that, in a popular state, public incontinency may be considered as the last of miseries, and as a certain fore-runner of a change in the constitution.
Hence it is that the sage legislators of republican states have ever required of women a particular gravity of manne rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sumptuary Laws among the Romans</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-7/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-7/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>Public incontinence is the inseparable companion of luxury.
If we leave the motions of the heart at liberty, how shall we be able to restrain the weaknesses of the mind?
At Rome, besides the general institutions, the censors prevailed on the magistrates to enact several particular laws for maintaining the frugality of women. This was the design of the Fannian, Licinian, and Oppian laws.
In Livy, the great ferment the senate was in when the women insisted upon the revocation of the Oppian law.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
