<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pantrynomic Analysis on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/analysis/pantrynomics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pantrynomic Analysis on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/analysis/pantrynomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Agricultural America</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/analysis/pantrynomics/agricultural-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/analysis/pantrynomics/agricultural-america/</guid>
      <description>In Book 3 of the Wealth of Nations, Adam Smith advocated that agricultural countries should max out their capital on agriculture first before investing it on industry, specifically to build ships and logistics technology. He gives example of Egypt, India, and China which were technologically backward relative to Rome and Europe.
This implies that Smith preferred the American colonies to stay backward in the short term and source its technology from Britain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>China, Vietnam, and Adam Smith</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/analysis/pantrynomics/vietnam-adam-smith/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/analysis/pantrynomics/vietnam-adam-smith/</guid>
      <description>During the cold war, two flavors of Communism arose:
 The Soviet Stalin flavor The Chinese Mao flavor  Outside of the Soviet Union, the Stalin flavor was implemented in:
 Cuba Vietnam  Outside of China, the Mao flavor was implemented in:
 North Korea Cambodia  The Mao flavor was totally replaced in 1980 with the Deng flavor. The Stalin flavor died in 1991, to be replaced with the Putin flavor in Russia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kishida: New Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/analysis/pantrynomics/kishida/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/analysis/pantrynomics/kishida/</guid>
      <description>Growth strategy Promotion of science and technology nation  Strengthening investment in science and technology / innovation to promote a nation of science and technology 10 trillion yen university fund / university reform  To form the world&amp;rsquo;s highest level research university, a university fund of 10 trillion yen will be set up within this year. In addition, governance is required of research universities that are comparable to the rest of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
