<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 5: National Laws on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 5: National Laws on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: When is War Lawful?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-5/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-5/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>In general, whatever is the foundation of a proper lawsuit may be a just occasion of war.
The lawsuit&amp;rsquo;s foundation is the violation of some perfect right whose performance may be extorted by force.
In modern times, it is decided by the magistrate, lest the society should be disturbed by every person taking justice at his own hands.
The sovereign is bound to demand satisfaction for the following offences:
When one nation:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2: What is Lawful in War?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-5/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-5/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>It is not easy to determine how far a nation may push its resentment against another nation which has injured it.
The practice of ancient and modern nations differs extremely. In general, resentment is necessary and just when an injury:
 is clearly and distinctly done, or is plainly intended and satisfaction refused.  There are a few cases in which it is lawful even without satisfaction being demanded.
If a robber intended to kill you, it would be quite lawful for you to do all you could to prevent him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3: The Rights of Neutral Nations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-5/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-5/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Third, we next show what is due to neutral nations from the belligerent powers.
The rule of justice with respect to neutral nations is, that they should suffer no injury as they have offended no party.
In a war between France and England, the Dutch should have the liberty of trading to both countries, as in peacetime, because they have injured neither. They can trade to them freely unless when they:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4: The Rights of Ambassadors</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-5/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-5/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>When nations came to have a lot of business one with another, it became necessary to send messengers between them. They were the first ambassadors.
Anciently, there was little commerce between nations and ambassadors were only sent on particular occasions.
 They were what we now call &amp;lsquo;ambassadors extraordinary&amp;rsquo;. They returned home after their business was transacted. There were no resident ambassadors in Rome or Greece. Their duty was just to conclude peace, make alliances, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-5/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-5/intro/</guid>
      <description>The rules which nations should observe, or do observe with one another, cannot be treated so accurately as private or public law.
The rules of property are pretty exactly established in every nation. The extent of the sovereign’s power and the subject&amp;rsquo;s duty, so far as justice is concerned, are pretty uniform everywhere. But with respect to the laws of nations, we cannot mention any one regulation: established with the common consent of all nations, and observed at all times.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
