<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Sense Of Duty and Our Judgments On Our Own Feelings on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Sense Of Duty and Our Judgments On Our Own Feelings on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Direct and Indirect Misfortunes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-3b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-3b/</guid>
      <description>Misfortunes make our feelings extreme 54 There are two kinds of private misfortunes which make our feelings go beyond the bounds of propriety:
  Those that affect us only indirectly.   They firstly affect other persons particularly dear to us such as our parents, children, brothers and sisters, intimate friends.
 Those that affect ourselves immediately and directly   They affect our body, fortune, or reputation. Examples are pain, sickness, approaching death, poverty, disgrace, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Nature balances the distribution of prosperity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-5b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-5b/</guid>
      <description>108 The general rules which distribute prosperity and adversity are perfectly suited to mankind&amp;rsquo;s situation. Yet they are not suited to some of our natural feelings. We naturally love some virtues so much that we want to give them honours. On the contrary, we detest some vices so much that we want to give them every disgrace. Magnanimity, generosity, and justice, command so much admiration.
We want to see them crowned with wealth, power, and honours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peace and the freedom from misery</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-3c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-3c/</guid>
      <description>72 The Stoics said that there is no essential difference in the happiness in one permanent situation and another. If there were any difference, it was very little.
It was just enough to render that situation as objects of:
 simple preference, but not of earnest desire, simple rejection, but not of earnest aversion.  The certainty by which our happiness settles to match our permanent situation would make us think that the Stoics were correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Opinion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-2b/</guid>
      <description>23 In all cases, the agreement or disagreement of the feelings and judgments of other people with our own is important to us, proportionally as we ourselves are uncertain about:
 the propriety of our own feelings the accuracy of our own judgments  34 A sensible man may sometimes feel great uneasiness lest he should have yielded too much even to an honourable feeling.
to his just indignation, perhaps, at the injury which may have been done either to himself or to his friend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Authority of the General Moral Rules properly seen as the Laws of the Deity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-5a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-5a/</guid>
      <description>100 The sense of duty is the regard to the general rules of conduct.
It is a principle of the greatest consequence in human life. It is the only principle by which most of mankind can direct their actions. Many men behave very decently. They perhaps never felt the sentiment on propriety. They might have acted merely from a regard to the established rules of behaviour. The man who has received great benefits from another person may feel just a small gratitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Influences and Authority of Conscience</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-3a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-3a/</guid>
      <description>43 The approbation of man&amp;rsquo;s own conscience can content his own weaknesses only during some extraordinary occasions.
The testimony of the impartial spectator cannot always support him alone. Yet its influence and authority is always very great. It is only by consulting this judge within that we can ever: see what relates to ourselves in its proper dimensions, or properly compare between our own interests and those of others.
The Eye of the Impartial Spectator</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Love of Praise and Dread of Blame</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-2a/</guid>
      <description>Praise is different from Praisworthiness, Blame is different from blameworthiness 8 Man naturally desires to be loved and dreads to be hated.
 He wants praise and praiseworthiness, even if he should be praised by nobody He dreads blame and blame-worthiness, even if he should be blamed by nobody  9 The love of praise-worthiness is not all derived from the love of praise. Those two principles resemble, are connected, and often blended with one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Self-deceit and the Origin and Use of General Rule</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>88 The impartial spectator does not always need to be far to pervert our judgments on our own conduct.
When he is near, the violence and injustice of our own selfish feelings are sometimes enough to induce the man within the breast to make a report very different from what our real circumstances can authorise.
89 There are two occasions when we examine our own conduct and try to view it as how the impartial spectator sees it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principle of Self-approbation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
1 In Parts 1 and 2, I explained the origin and foundation of our judgments on the feelings and conduct of others. I will now explain the origin of our judgments on our own feelings and conduct.
2 We use sympathy to judge both the conduct of ourselves and that of other people.
 We judge another man&amp;rsquo;s conduct according to how we sympathize with his feelings. We judge our own conduct according to how we sympathize with our own feelings from another man&amp;rsquo;s viewpoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When the Sense of Duty Should be the Sole Principle of our Conduct; and When it Should Concur with Other Motives</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-3/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>113 Religion affords strong motives to the practice of virtue. It guards us from the temptations of vice through powerful restraints. Many have supposed that religious principles were the sole laudable motives of action. They said that we should not:
 reward from gratitude, punish from resentment, protect our children&amp;rsquo;s helplessness, and afford support to the infirmities of our parents, from natural affection.  Instead, all feelings for objects should be extinguished in our breast.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
