<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Laws Related to Offense on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-10/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Laws Related to Offense on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alexander the Great</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-10/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-10/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>HE did not set out upon his expedition t= ill he had secured Macedonia against the neighbouring barbarians and comple= ted the reduction of Greece; he availed himself of this conquest for no oth= er end than for the execution of his grand enterprize; he rendered the jeal= ousy of the Laced=C3=A6monians of no effect; he attacked the maritime provi= nces; he caused his land forces to keep close to the sea coast, that they m= ight not be separated from his fleet; he made an admirable use of disciplin= e against numbers; he never wanted provisions; and, if it be true, that vic= tory gave him every thing, he, in his turn, did every thing to obtain it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conquests made by a Monarchy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-10/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-10/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>IF a monarchy can long subsist before it is weakened by its increase, it will become formidable; and its strength w ill remain entire while pent up by the neighbouring monarchies.
It ought not, therefore, to aim at conquests beyond the natural limits of its government. So soon as it has passed these limits it is prudence to stop.
In this kind of conquest things must be left as they were found; the same courts of judicature, the same laws, the same customs, the same privileges: there ought to be no other alteration th an that of the army and of the name of the sovereign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conquests made by a Republic</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-10/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-10/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>IT is contrary to the nature of things, that, in a confederate government, one state should make any conquest over another, as in our days we have seen in Switzerland.
In mixed confederate republics, where t he association is between petty republics and monarchies of a small extent, this is not so absurd.
Contrary it is also to the nature of thi ngs that a democratical republic should conquer towns which cannot enter in to the sphere of its democracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Methods of preserving a Conquest</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-10/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-10/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>The Mongols, who now govern China, has ordained that every military corps in the provinces, as well as the courts of judicature, should be composed half of Chinese and half Mongols. Their goal is to:
 end the jealousy between the Chinese and Mongols prevent the Chinese, the vanquished nation, from falling into despair prevent the Mongols, the victors, from growing insolent and proud the government from becoming military contain the two nations within their duty  This is an amirable policy for monarch that has subdued a large country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offensive Force</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-10/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-10/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>OFFENSIVE force is regulated by the law of nations; which is the political law of each country, considered in its relation to every other.
Chapter 2: War THE life of governments is like that of man.
I have a right to kill for natural defence because my life is, in respect to me, what the life of my an tagonist is to him.
A government has a right to wage war for its own preservation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
