<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 6: Inherent Morality as Virtue on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 6: Inherent Morality as Virtue on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/conclusion/</guid>
      <description>54 Prudence is recommended to us by the concern for our own happiness.
Justice and beneficence are recommended to us by the concern for the happiness of others. Justice restrains us from hurting that happiness. Beneficence prompts us to promote it. Prudence is originally recommended to us by our selfish affections. Justice and beneficence are recommended to us by our benevolent affections. These are recommended to us independent of any regard to: what are, what should be, or what would be the sentiments of other people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excessive Ego (Self-esteem, Pride, and Vanity)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-4/</guid>
      <description>31 In prosperity, the man with excessive self-esteem might have some advantage over the modest man. The people&amp;rsquo;s applause is often louder in favour of the man with excessive self-esteem than for the modest man. Yet with all things fairly computed, the real advantage is perhaps always greatly:
 in favour of the modest man, and against the man of excessive self-esteem.  A man fears no humiliation if he does not ascribe to himself any other merit besides that which really belongs to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prudence - The Individual&#39;s Character, so far as it affects his own Happiness</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction 1 We naturally view an individual&amp;rsquo;s character under two aspects:
 As it may affect his own happiness As it may affect the happiness of others  2 Nature first recommends the body&amp;rsquo;s preservation and healthful state to every individual&amp;rsquo;s care. Hunger and thirst, pleasure and pain, heat and cold, etc. are lessons delivered by the voice of Nature herself. Nature directs him what he should choose and avoid. Most of his first lessons from his parents also teaches him how to keep out of harm&amp;rsquo;s way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-command</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-3a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-3a/</guid>
      <description>1 A man is said to be perfectly virtuous if he acts according to the rules of:
 perfect prudence, strict justice, and proper benevolence.  But the perfect knowledge of those rules alone will not enable him to act in this way. His own passions:
 are very apt to mislead him, and sometimes drive and seduce him to violate all the rules which he himself approves of in all his sober and cool hours  The perfect knowledge will not always enable him to do his duty if it is not supported by the most perfect self-command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-estimation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-3c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-3c/</guid>
      <description>22 The principle of self-estimation may be too high or too low.
It is so very agreeable to think highly or meanly of ourselves. To the person himself, some excess must be less disagreeable than any defect. But to the impartial spectator, things must appear quite differently. To him, the defect must always be less disagreeable than the excess. in our companions, we much more frequently complain of the excess than the defect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Point of Propriety</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-3b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-3b/</guid>
      <description>14 The point of propriety is the degree of any passion which the impartial spectator approves of. This point is differently situated in different passions.
 In some passions, the excess is less disagreeable than the shortage.
 In such passions, the point of propriety seems to stand high, or nearer to the excess than to the shortage.
 In other passions, the shortage is less disagreeable than the excess.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
