<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Section 1 of the Simplified Lectures on Jurisprudence by Adam Smith on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Section 1 of the Simplified Lectures on Jurisprudence by Adam Smith on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Citizenship</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>The laws of different countries vary much with regard to the right of citizenship. In most of the Swiss republics, the right of citizenship only belongs to those born of a citizen.
In Rome, a family might be peregrina for four or five generations.
At Athens, no man was a citizen unless both father and mother were Athenians. The Athenians were particularly sparing in giving the right of citizenship, because it entitled them to very great privileges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Liberty was lost</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>We have shown:
 how republics arose, and how they again became democratic.  We next show how:
 this liberty was lost, and how monarchy was introduced.  The republics mentioned must either:
 confine themselves within their ancient boundaries, or enlarge their territory by conquest.  They must either be a defensive republic or a conquering one. The Greek states are a good example of a defensive republic. Rome and Carthage are examples of conquering republics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Military Monarchy was dissolved</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>We have considered:
 how the dissolution of small states was brought about, and what form of government succeeded them, how an imperial government was introduced into conquering republics, and what kind of administration this was.  We now show how this military monarchy was dissolved, like every state and constitution.
During the imperial governments at Rome, their arts and commerce were improved. The people become acquainted with arts, commerce and consequently, domestic luxury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Republican Governments were introduced</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Early societies had democratic governments. How were republican governments introduced?
Generally, a country&amp;rsquo;s location and its improvement in agriculture and trade make it favourable to the introduction of a republican government.
There is little probability that republican governments will ever be introduced into Mongolia or Arabia, because their country cannot be improved.
 Most part of its lands are hills and deserts and is only fit for pasture They are generally dry and do not have any big rivers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the English Government became Absolute</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>The House of Commons became considerable. But how did the nobility’s power decrease and how did the government become arbitrary?
Previously by their ancient rustic hospitality, all the European courts could easily maintain 1,000 retainers. Richard, Earl of Warwick was styled as a King. He maintained 40,000 people everyday besides tenants.
But when luxury took place, he was unable to do this. Thus, the nobility&amp;rsquo;s power was reduced before the House of Commons had established its authority through an arbitrary king.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How was Liberty restored?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>How was liberty was restored in Britain?
 Period Leader     1533 Henry 7th   1558 Elizabeth   1603 James I   1649 Charles I     Henry 7th allowed the nobility to dispose of their estates. This placed them on a level with the commons.
Elizabeth was a popular leader and so she was continually unwilling to impose taxes on her subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Military Monarchy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>What form of government succeeded the republican?
When small republics were conquered by another state, monarchy, or whatever government the conquerors wanted was established. They generally followed the model of their own country.
 The Athenians always established democracy. The Spartans established aristocracy. The Romans more prudently divided their conquests into provinces.  These were governed pretty absolutely by persons appointed by the Senate. The case is somewhat different when a state is conquered by its own people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Allodial Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>The government which succeeded the fall of the Roman Empire was similar to Mongols. Germans and other groups conquered the the western countries. Compared to the Mongols, they:
 had better notions of property, and were a little more used to the division of lands.  The conquering king and the other chieftains would naturally:
 take more land and distribute it among their vassals and dependents, and leave only a tiny share to the ancient inhabitants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The English Courts of Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>In England and Europe after the feudal law was introduced, governance was done in the same way as a baron in his jurisdiction. The baron was a steward who managed all affairs in his lord&amp;rsquo;s county.
The grand justiciary managed all justice in the kingdom.
 He appointed sheriffs and other inferior officers. He was himself a great lord. He became as powerful as the king in every country except in England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The English Parliament</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>We shall next show:
 how each person got a share in the government what share of it was allotted to each of them.  Every person who had an estate great or small, had a right:
 to sit in the king’s court, and to consult and advise with him on public matters.  In William Rufus&#39; reign, 700 sat in parliament.
In Henry III’s time, it was enacted that the smaller barons, who could not afford to attend in parliament, should send a representative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Feudal System</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>How was the allodial government overturned to give way to the feudal system?
These great lords were continually making war on one another. In order to secure their tenants&#39; attendance, they gave them leases of the lands which they possessed from year to year. They afterwards came to be held for life.
The great lords usually engaged in very hazardous enterprises with their vassals. They extended this right to the land to their son and grandson&amp;rsquo;s life so that:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The little Republics in Europe</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>What is the origin of the little European republics and the rights of sovereign and subject?
The Origin of Republics In some countries, the provinces far from the seat of government sometimes became independent. This was the case in most of Germany and France during Charlemagne&amp;rsquo;s time.
Hugh Capet was chief justiciary. He got the government into his hands, but took only the title of the King of France.
The Pope raised disturbances in Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature Of Government And Its Progress In The First Ages Of Society</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>We shall now explain:
 the nature of government, its different forms, what circumstances gave occasion for it, and how it is maintained.  There are three forms of government:
 Monarchical - the supreme power is vested in one who can do what he pleases, make peace and war, impose taxes, etc. [tyranny] Aristocratical - the state is run by magistrates chosen by a class of people, such as the wealthy or known families, [oligarchy + aristocracy] Democratical - the state is run by the people together [democracy]  Aristocratical and democratical governments may be called republican.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Original Principles of Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Two principles induce men to enter into a civil society:
 Principle of authority Principle of utility  The four things that give one man authority over another are:
 Superior abilities of body and of mind Superior age and long possession Superior wealth Ancient family  Principle of Authority   Superior abilities   At the head of every small society, or association of people, is a person of superior abilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rights of Sovereigns</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>What is the duty of the sovereign? What is the proper punishment of disobedience?
Every attempt to overturn this power is considered as the greatest crime in every nation. It is called high treason. There is a great difference between treason in monarchies and treason in republics.
 In monarchies, treason is an attempt on the king. In republics, treason is an attempt on the people&amp;rsquo;s liberties.  This is why the maxim of assassination came to be established in republics, and not in monarchies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rights of Subjects</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-1/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>The limitations of the sovereign&amp;rsquo;s power It is impossible to be precise regarding this branch of public law. The duties of one subject to another are sufficiently ascertained by the laws of every country and the courts of justice. But there are no judges to determine when sovereigns do wrong. [No world government yet] To suppose a sovereign subject to judgement, supposes another sovereign.
In England it can be exactly ascertained when the king encroaches on the people&amp;rsquo;s privileges, or the people on the king&amp;rsquo;s privileges.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
