<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 1 on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 1 on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>National Characters</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/21-national-characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/21-national-characters/</guid>
      <description>1 Shallow people often carry all national characters to extremes. They categorize everyone and think that any people are knavish, cowardly, or ignorant without exception.
Men of sense condemn these undistinguishing judgments. But at the same time, they say that each nation has:
 a peculiar set of manners, and some particular qualities are more frequently seen among one people than others.  The common people in Switzerland are probably more honest than those Ireland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Argument for and Against Divorce</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/19b-divorce/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/19b-divorce/</guid>
      <description>Monogamy How long should monogamous marriages last? Should we allow voluntary divorces, which were customary among the Greeks and Romans?
Arguments for Divorce  Loveless marriages just increase hate and pain  Disgust and aversion often arises after marriage from:
 the most trivial accidents, or incompatibility  Time can add new quarrels and reproaches which makes their mutual wounds fester more every day instead of curing them. Let us separate hearts which were not made to associate together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polygamy and Marriage</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/19-polygamy-divorce/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/19-polygamy-divorce/</guid>
      <description>Marriage is an engagement entered into by mutual consent for the propagation of the species. It is susceptible of all the conditions, which consent establishes, provided they be not contrary to this end.
A man, in conjoining himself to a woman, is bound to her according to the terms of his engagement.
In begetting children, he is bound, by all the ties of nature and humanity, to provide for their subsistence and education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity And Refinement In Writing</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/20-simplicity-in-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/20-simplicity-in-writing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Platonist</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/17-platonist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/17-platonist/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise And Progress Of The Arts</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/14b-the-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/14b-the-arts/</guid>
      <description>Monarchies get their foundation from a superstitious reverence to priests and princes who have commonly abridged the liberty of reasoning on religion, and politics, and consequently metaphysics and morals. All these form the most considerable branches of science. Mathematics and natural philosophy, which only remain, are not half so valuable.
Among the arts of conversation, no one pleases more than mutual deference or civility, which leads us to resign our own inclinations to those of our companion, and to curb and conceal that presumption and arrogance, so natural to the human mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Skeptic</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/18-skeptic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/18-skeptic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eloquence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/13-eloquence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/13-eloquence/</guid>
      <description>The revolutions and periods in human history are full of variety and surprize in the manners, customs, and opinions.
Civil history has more uniformity than the history of learning and science. The wars, negotiations, and politics of one age resemble more those of another, than the taste, wit, and speculative principles.
Interest and ambition, honour and shame, friendship and enmity, gratitude and revenge, are the prime movers in all public transactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>British Political Parties</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/9-british-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/9-british-parties/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civil Liberty</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/12-civil-liberty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/12-civil-liberty/</guid>
      <description>Political writers who are free from party-prejudices cultivate a science that contributes most to public utility, of all sciences. They get a private satisfaction from it. However, I suspect that the world is still too young to establish many general universal truths in politics.
We still have not experienced 3,000 years and so the art of reasoning is still imperfect in this science, as in all others. We even lack sufficient materials to reason on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is The British Government An Absolute Monarchy Or a Republic?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/7-britain-monarchy-republic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/7-britain-monarchy-republic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Parties</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/8-political-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/8-political-parties/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Politics May Be Reduced To a Science</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/3-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/3-politics/</guid>
      <description>It is wrong to say that all governments are alike, and that their only difference is in the character and conduct of the governors. If this were true, then most political disputes would end and there would be just one constitution for all. I condemn the idea that human affairs are merely caused by the casual humours and characters of particular men.
The goodness of all government is in the goodness of the administration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Principles of Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/4-first-principles-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/4-first-principles-government/</guid>
      <description>The most surprizing about human affairs is:
 the ease with which the many are governed by the few. the implicit submission of men to their rulers.  What causes this?
We see:
 that the subjects always have the force to overturn their leader is always on the that the public opinion is the only thing that supports their leaders  Thus, government is founded only on opinion.
This maxim extends to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dignity and Meanness Of Human Nature</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/11-dignity-of-human-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/11-dignity-of-human-nature/</guid>
      <description>Intellectual sects and political factions secretly form. Sometimes they do not come to an open rupture. But they give a different turn to the ways of thinking of those who have taken part on either side.
Are Humans Inherently Divine or Evil? The most remarkable are those founded on the feelings on the dignity of human nature. This has divided philosophers, poets, and divines of the past to the present. Some exalt our species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Superstition and Enthusiasm</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/10-superstition-enthusiasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/10-superstition-enthusiasm/</guid>
      <description>A maxim states that the corruption of the best things produces the worst things. This is true in the corruptions of true religion into superstition and enthusiasm.
These two kinds of false religion are both pernicious, yet very different and even contrary. Human minds are subject to many terrors and apprehensions coming from:
 the unhappy situation of affairs, ill health, a gloomy and melancholy disposition, or the concurrence of all these circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origin of Governments: Obedience, Justice, Liberty</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/5-origin-of-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/5-origin-of-government/</guid>
      <description>A man, who is born in a family, is compelled to maintain society from:
 necessity natural inclination, and habit  To further progress, he establishes political society in order to administer justice. Without justice, there can be no peace, safety, nor mutual intercourse among them. Therefore, the only purpose of the vast apparatus of our government is to distribute justice, or, in other words, support the 12 judges.
The following are needed for their part of administration:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Indepdendence of Parliament</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/6-independence-of-parliament/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/6-independence-of-parliament/</guid>
      <description>Political writers have a maxim: In contriving any system of government and fixing the checks and controls of the constitution, every man should be supposed a knave, and have only private interest in all his actions.
By this interest we must:
 govern him make him co-operate to public good despite his insatiable avarice and ambition  Without this, we shall:
 in vain boast of the advantages of any constitution find, in the end, that we have no security for our liberties or possessions, except the good-will of our rulers; that is, we shall have no security at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Freedom of the Press</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/2-freedom-of-the-press/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/2-freedom-of-the-press/</guid>
      <description>The extreme liberty that we enjoy in Britain surprises foreigners the most.
We can say whatever we want to the public and openly censure every measure by the king or his ministers. If the administration resolves to go to war, they either wilfully or ignorantly mistake the interests of the nation.
Peace, in the present situation, is infinitely preferable. If our ministers prefer peace, our political writers breathe nothing but war and devastation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensitive People</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/1-sensitive-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/1-sensitive-people/</guid>
      <description>Some people are extremely sensitive to all the accidents of life. It gives them joy on every prosperous event, as well as grief on misfortunes and adversity. Favours and good acts easily engage their friendship, while the smallest injury provokes their resentment. Any honour or mark of distinction elevates them above measure. But they are as sensibly touched with contempt.
Such people have more lively enjoyments, and more pungent sorrows than sedate men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Epicurean</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/15-epicurean/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/15-epicurean/</guid>
      <description>It is a great mortification to the vanity of man, that his utmost art and industry can never equal the meanest of nature’s productions, either for beauty or value.
Art is only the under-workman,° and is employed to give a few strokes of embellishment to those pieces, which come from the hand of the master.
Some of the drapery may be of his drawing; but he is not allowed to touch the principal figure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stoic</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/16-stoic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/16-stoic/</guid>
      <description>Nature has endowed man with a sublime celestial spirit and an affinity with superior beings. She allows not such noble faculties to lie lethargic or idle.
She urges him, by necessity, to employ, on every emergence his utmost art and industry.
Animals have many of their necessities supplied by nature. They are clothed and armed by Nature.
Their own industry is requisite on any occasion, nature, by implanting instincts, still supplies them with the art, and guides them to their good, by her unerring precepts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise And Progress Of The Sciences</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/14a-the-sciences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-1/14a-the-sciences/</guid>
      <description>In human affairs, the discernment of what comes from chance and what comes from causes requires the most refinement. An author will likely deceive himself by false subtilties and refinements in this.
Any enquiry about an event is cut when we declare it to be derived from chance. It leaves the writer in the same state of ignorance with the rest of mankind. But when the event comes from certain and stable causes, he may then display his ingenuity in assigning these causes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
