<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 8: The Four Cycles of Governments on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-8/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 8: The Four Cycles of Governments on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-8/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aristocracy, Oligarchy, Democracy, Tyranny</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-8/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-8/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Socrates: In the perfect State:  the wives and children of guardians are to be in common, all education and war and peace are also to be common, the best philosophers and the bravest warriors are to be their kings, the governors, when appointed themselves, will take their soldiers and place them in common houses and contain nothing private.  None of them are to have any of the ordinary possessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democracy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-8/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-8/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>How Oligarchy Turns Into Democracy Next comes democracy. How does oligarchy change into democracy? Is it wise or not? Oligarchy aims at a good of becoming as rich as possible. The rulers are aware that their power rests on their wealth. They will refuse to curtail by law the extravagance of the spendthrift youth because they gain from their ruin. They take interest from them. They buy up their estates and increase their own wealth and importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oligarchy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-8/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-8/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>How the Timocracts Become Oligarchs An oligarchic government is one resting on a valuation of property, in which the rich have power and the poor man is deprived of it. The rulers are elected for their wealth. I shall explain the transition from timocracy to oligarchy.
The accumulation of gold in private individuals is the ruin of timocracy. They invent illegal modes of expenditure because they do not care about the law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tyranny</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-8/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-8/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>From Democracy to Tyranny Last of all comes the most beautiful of all, man and State alike, tyranny and the tyrant. How does tyranny arise? Does tyranny spring from democracy in the same way as democracy from oligarchy?
The excess of wealth was the good which oligarchy proposed to itself. Oligarchy was maintained by that wealth. The insatiable desire of wealth and the neglect of all other things for the sake of money-getting was also the ruin of oligarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
