<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simplified Progress and Poverty on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/george/progress-poverty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Simplified Progress and Poverty on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/george/progress-poverty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ineffective Solutions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/george/progress-poverty/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/george/progress-poverty/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>The current solutions are:
 More efficient government Better education and work habits Unions or associations Cooperation Government regulation Redistribution of land  1.More efficient government Social distress are due to:
 huge public debts, military establishments, general extravagance especially in large cities the robbery of protective tariffs, which take $1 or more from consumers for every $0.25 they put in the treasury.  Reducing this enormous burden would not ease the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cause of Interest</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/george/progress-poverty/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/george/progress-poverty/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>I have already warned of confusing profits with interest. Interest includes all returns from using capital, not just payments from borrower to lender.
The economic meaning excludes compensation for risk — which makes up a great part of interest. But compensation for risk is merely an equalization of return between different uses of capital.
Rates also vary considerably in different countries and at different times. Interest generally has been higher in the United States than in England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Root Cause of Recessions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/george/progress-poverty/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/george/progress-poverty/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>Depressions and recessions are caused by:
 Land speculation which inflates land values, reduces wages and interest, and thereby checks production. The complexity and interdependence of production Problems with money and credit The artificial barriers of protective tariffs.  Nonetheless, land speculation is the primary cause producing recessions.
As population grows and technology advances, land values rise. This steady increase leads to speculation which anticipates future increases. This raises Land values beyond the point at which labor and capital would receive their customary returns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The True Remedy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/george/progress-poverty/chapter-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/george/progress-poverty/chapter-25/</guid>
      <description>The unequal distribution of wealth is caused by private land ownership. As long private property exists, no increase in production will permanently benefit the masses. On the contrary, any improvements must depress their condition further.
Poverty deepens as wealth increases. Wages fall while productivity grows. This is all because land, the source of all wealth and the field of all labor, is monopolized.
Unequal ownership of land causes unequal distribution of wealth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Traditional Theories of Wages Are Wrong</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/george/progress-poverty/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/george/progress-poverty/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Why does poverty persist despite increasing wealth?
The decline of wages also leads to poverty. So why do wages decrease to subsistence level, even when productive power increases?
Current theory explains that:
 wages are set by the ratio between the number of workers and the amount of capital available for labor population increases faster than the increase in capital therefore, wages always move toward the lowest level that the workers will tolerate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
