<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Laws on Population on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-23/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Laws on Population on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-23/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Remedy a Depopulation; Healthcare Policy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-23/chapter-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-23/chapter-28/</guid>
      <description>WHEN a state is depopulated by particular accidents, by wars, pestilence, or famine, there are still resources left. The men who remain may preserve the spirit of industry; they may seek to repair their misfortunes, and calamity itself may make them become more industrious. This evil is almost incurable, when the depopulation is prepared before-hand by interior vice and a bad government. When this is the case, men perish with an insensible and habitual disease: born in misery and weakness, in violence, or under the influence of a wicked administration, they see themselves destroyed, and frequently without perceiving the cause of their destruction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infanticide and Healthcare Policy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-23/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-23/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>THE Roman policy was very good, in respect to the exposing of children. Romulus, says Dionysius Halicarnasseus*, laid the citizens under an obligation to educate all their male children, and the eldest of their daughters. If the infants were deformed and monstrous, he permitted the exposing them, after having shewn them to five of their nearest neighbours.
Romulus did not suffer† them to kill any infants under three years old: by which means he reconciled the law that gave to fathers the right over their children of life and death, with that which prohibited their being exposed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population Policy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-23/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-23/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>Population policy depend greatly on circumstances. There are countries, in which nature does all.
There is no need to encourage propagation when a fruitful climate yields enough people. Sometimes, the climate is more favourable than the soil. The people multiply, and are destroyed by famine.
This is the case of China. Hence a father sells his daughters, and exposes his children. In Tonkin, the same causes produce the same effects. so we need not, like the Arabian travellers mentioned by Renaudot, search for the origin of this in their sentiments on the metempsychosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Population Growth of Humans and Animals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-23/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-23/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Female animals have an almost constant fecundity. But in the human species, the manner of thinking, the character, the passions, the humour, the caprice, the idea of preserving beauty, the pain of childbearing, and the fatigue of a too numerous family, obstruct propagation a thousand different ways.
Chapter 2: Marriage THE natural obligation of the father to provide for his children has established marriage, which makes known the person who ought to fulfil this obligation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Romans Needed to make Laws to increase their Population</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-23/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-23/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>THE Romans, by destroying others, were themselves destroyed. Through incessant action they wore out like a weapon kept constantly in use.
How did the Romans increase their population?
Chapter 21: Roman Population Laws THE ancient laws of Rome tried hard to get people to marry. Dio says that Augusus said:
Dionysius Halicarnasseus† cannot believe that after the death of 305 of the Fabii, exterminated by the Veientes, there remained no more of this family but one child; because the ancient law, which obliged every citizen to marry and to educate all his children‡, was still in force.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
