<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Hume on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in David Hume on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Academic (Skeptical) Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s12/</guid>
      <description>Part 1 The most philosophical reasonings have been on proving the existence of a Deity, and refute the fallacies of Atheists.
Yet most religious philosophers still dispute whether anyone can be so blinded as to be a speculative atheist. How shall we reconcile these contradictions? The knights-errant wandered about to clear the world of dragons and giants. They believed in them. The skeptic is another enemy of religion.
He naturally provokes the indignation of all divines and graver philosophers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association of Ideas</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s3/</guid>
      <description>There is a connection between the different thoughts or ideas of the mind, and that, in their appearance to the memory or imagination
They introduce each other with a certain degree of method and regularity. In our more serious thinking or discourse this is so observable that any particular thought, which breaks in upon the regular tract or chain of ideas, is immediately remarked and rejected. Even in our wildest and most wandering reveries, nay in our very dreams, we shall find, if we reflect, that the imagination ran not altogether at adventures, but that there was still a connexion upheld among the different ideas, which succeeded each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different Kinds of Philosophies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s1/</guid>
      <description>Moral philosophy is the science of human nature.
It can be treated in two ways. Each way has its own merit and can contribute to the entertainment, instruction, and reformation of mankind:
  One way treats humans chiefly as born for action.   Humans are influenced by taste and feelings. They pursue some objects and avoid others, depending on the value of those objects as they present themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doubts on the Mind&#39;s Operations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s4/</guid>
      <description>All the objects of human reason or enquiry may naturally be divided into two kinds, to wit, Relations of Ideas, and Matters of Fact. Of the first kind are the sciences of Geometry, Algebra, and Arithmetic; and in short, every affirmation which is either intuitively or demonstratively certain. That the square of the hypothenuse is equal to the square of the two sides, is a proposition which expresses a relation between these figures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom and Consequence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s8/</guid>
      <description>We would expect that in most disputed questions since the first origin of philosophy, that the meaning of all the terms, at least, should have been agreed upon among the disputants.
and our enquiries, in the course of two thousand years, been able to pass from words to the true and real subject of the controversy.
For how easy may it seem to give exact definitions of the terms employed in reasoning, and make these definitions, not the mere sound of words, the object of future scrutiny and examination?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miracles</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s10/</guid>
      <description>The doctrine of miracles is not significant.
But Dr. Tillotson argues against the real presence of miracles. His argument is the most concise, elegant, and strong against miracles.
The authority of Christian scripture or tradition is founded merely in the testimony of the apostles.
 They were the eye-witnesses to the miracles of our Saviour.  Those miracles proved his divine mission.    Our evidence, then, for the truth of the Christian religion is less than the evidence for the truth of our senses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s6/</guid>
      <description>Though there be no such thing as Chance in the world; our ignorance of the real cause of any event has the same influence on the understanding, and begets a like species of belief or opinion.
There is certainly a probability, which arises from a superiority of chances on any side; and according as this superiority encreases, and surpasses the opposite chances, the probability receives a proportionable encrease, and begets still a higher degree of belief or assent to that side, in which we discover the superiority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Providence and a Future State</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s11/</guid>
      <description>I was lately engaged in conversation with a friend who loves sceptical paradoxes; where, though he advanced many principles, of which I can by no means approve, yet as they seem to be curious, and to bear some relation to the chain of reasoning carried on throughout this enquiry, I shall here copy them from my memory as accurately as I can, in order to submit them to the judgement of the reader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reason of Animals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s9/</guid>
      <description>All our reasonings concerning matter of fact are founded on a kind of Analogy, which leads us to expect from any cause the same events, which we have observed to result from similar causes.
Where the causes are entirely similar, the analogy is perfect, and the inference, drawn from it, is regarded as certain and conclusive: nor does any man ever entertain a doubt, where he sees a piece of iron, that it will have weight and cohesion of parts; as in all other instances, which have ever fallen under his observation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skeptical Solution to these Doubts</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s5/</guid>
      <description>The passion for philosophy, like that for religion, seems liable to this inconvenience, that, though it aims at the correction of our manners, and extirpation of our vices, it may only serve, by imprudent management, to foster a predominant inclination, and push the mind, with more determined resolution, towards that side which already draws too much, by the bias and propensity of the natural temper.
It is certain that, while we aspire to the magnanimous firmness of the philosophic sage, and endeavour to confine our pleasures altogether within our own minds, we may, at last, render our philosophy like that of Epictetus, and other Stoics, only a more refined system of selfishness, and reason ourselves out of all virtue as well as social enjoyment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Idea of Consequential Connection</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s7/</guid>
      <description>Math&amp;rsquo;s great advantage over the moral sciences is that its ideas are sensible.
This makes them always clear and determinate. The smallest distinction between them is immediately perceptible. The same words express the same ideas, without ambiguity or variation. An oval is never mistaken for a circle, nor an hyperbola for an ellipsis. The isosceles and scalenum are distinguished by boundaries more exact than vice and virtue, right and wrong. If any term be defined in geometry, the mind readily, of itself, substitutes, on all occasions, the definition for the term defined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin of Ideas</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/enquiry/s2/</guid>
      <description>There is a considerable difference between the perceptions of the mind, when a man feels the pain of excessive heat, or the pleasure of moderate warmth, and when he afterwards recalls to his memory this sensation, or anticipates it by his imagination.
These faculties may mimic or copy the perceptions of the senses; but they never can entirely reach the force and vivacity of the original sentiment. The utmost we say of them, even when they operate with greatest vigour, is, that they represent their object in so lively a manner, that we could almost say we feel or see it: But, except the mind be disordered by disease or madness, they never can arrive at such a pitch of vivacity, as to render these perceptions altogether undistinguishable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
