<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Religious Laws on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-24/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Religious Laws on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-24/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Catholicism is Best for a Monarchy, and the Protestant is Best for a Republic</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-24/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-24/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>WHEN a religion is introduced and fixed in a state, it is commonly such as is most suitable to the plan of government there established; for those who receive it, and those who are the cause of its being received, have scarcely any other idea of policy, than that of the state in which they were born.
When the Christian religion, two centuries ago, became unhappily divided into Catholic and Protestant, the people of the North embraced the Protestant, and those of the south adhered still to the Catholic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Laws of Religion correct the Inconveniencies of a political Constitution</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-24/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-24/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>ON the other hand, religion may support a state, when the laws themselves are incapable of doing it.
Thus, when a kingdom is frequently agitated by civil wars, religion may do much, by obliging one part of the state to remain always quiet. Among the Greeks, the Eleans, as priests of Apollo, lived always in peace.
In Japan*, the city of Meaco enjoys a constant peace, as being a holy city: religion supports this regulation, and that empire which seems to be alone upon earth, and which neither has, nor will have, any dependence on foreigners, has always, in its own bosom, a trade which war cannot ruin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortal Sins</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-24/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-24/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>IT appears from a passage of the books of the pontiffs, quoted by Cicero*, that they had amongst the Romans unpardonable crimes.
it is on this that Zozymus founds the narration so proper to blacken the motives of Constantine’s conversion; and Julian, that bitter raillery on this conversion in his Cæsars.
The Pagan religion prohibited only some of the grosser crimes, and which stopped the hand, but meddled not with the heart, might have crimes that were inexpiable:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion in General</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-24/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-24/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>AS amidst several degrees of darkness we may form a judgment of those which are the least thick, and among precipices, which are the least deep; so we may search among false religions for those that are most conformable to the welfare of society; for those which, though they have not the effect of leading men to the felicity of another life, may contribute most to their happiness in this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religious Festivals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-24/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-24/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>WHEN religion appoints a cessation from labour, it ought to have a greater regard to the necessities of mankind, than to the grandeur of the being it designs to honour.
Athens* was subject to great inconveniencies from the excessive number of its festivals. These powerful people, to whose decision all the cities of Greece came to submit their quarrels, could not have time to dispatch such a multiplicity of affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Laws of Perfection in Religion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-24/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-24/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>HUMAN laws are made to direct the will. These should give precepts, not counsels.
Religion is made to influence the heart. It should give many counsels and few precepts. It gives rules:
 not for what is good, but for what is better not to direct to what is right, but to what is perfect  Religious teachings should be counsels, and not laws, for perfection can have no relation to the universality of men or things.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
