<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Expense and Revenue of Government on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Expense and Revenue of Government on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ancient Educational Institutions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3n/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3n/</guid>
      <description>166 Different educational institutions were established in other ages and nations.
167 In the ancient Greek republic, every free citizen was instructed in gymnastic exercises and music, under the public magistrate.
Gymnastic exercises were intended to:
 harden his body, sharpen his courage, and prepare him for war.  The Greek militia was one of the best in the world. Their public education completely answered its purpose. Music was intended to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annuities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3c/</guid>
      <description>Translator&amp;rsquo;s note: To make large number simpler, the shillings and pences have been removed in some amounts.
 29 Besides borrowing by anticipations and perpetual funding, there are two other methods in between them:
 borrowing on annuities for terms of years borrowing on annuities for lives  30 During the reigns of King William and Queen Anne, large sums were frequently borrowed on annuities for terms of years which varied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticipations and Perpetual Funding</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3b/</guid>
      <description>13 In Great Britain, the land and malt taxes are regularly anticipated every year by a borrowing clause.
This clause is constantly inserted into the acts which impose those taxes. The Bank of England advances to government the total amount of those taxes at 3-8% interest. It receives payment as the taxes come in. Any deficiency is offset by the tax proceeds of the next year. The only remaining unmortgaged public revenue is thus spent before it comes in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appendix to Articles 1 and 2-Capital Taxes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2g-appendix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2g-appendix/</guid>
      <description>Taxes On The Capital Value of Land, Houses, and Stock 113 While property remains with the same person, its taxes never aim to reduce or take away its capital value.
Such taxes only aim to reduce or remove some part of its revenue. Property changes hands when it is transmitted from: the dead to the living, or the living to the living The taxes on such property aim to take away part of its capital value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Armies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1c/</guid>
      <description>Superiority of Armies vs Militia 27 History shows the superiority of a well-regulated standing army over a militia.
28 The army of Philip of Macedon is one of the first standing armies documented. In the beginning, his troops were probably a militia. Frequent wars with the Thracians, Illyrians, Thessalians, and some Greek cities near Macedon gradually formed his troops to the exact discipline of a standing army. He was careful not to disband that army when he was at peace, which was very seldom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article 2-Educational Institutions for the youth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3l/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3l/</guid>
      <description>130 The educational institutions for the youth may generate a revenue sufficient for defraying their own expence.
The fee or honorary which the scholar pays the teacher is naturally a revenue of this kind.
131 Even if the teacher&amp;rsquo;s reward does not come from this natural revenue, it still is unnecessary that it should be derived from the society&amp;rsquo;s general revenue.
In most countries, the collection and application of the society&amp;rsquo;s general revenue is done through the executive power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article 2-Educational Subjects</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3m/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3m/</guid>
      <description>Language Learning 148 When Christianity was first established by law, a corrupted Latin had become the common language of Western Europe.
Church services and the Bible translations read in churches were both in that corrupted Latin. After demise of the Roman empire, Latin gradually ceased to be the language of Europe. But the people&amp;rsquo;s reverence naturally preserves the established forms and ceremonies of religion long after the reasons for their establishment have disappeared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article 3-Moral Education for People of all Ages</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3p/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3p/</guid>
      <description>190 The educational institutions for people of all ages are chiefly those for religious instruction.
It aims to prepare them for a better world in a life to come. Its teachers may depend on: their students&#39; voluntary contributions, a fund from their country such as: a landed estate, a tithe or land-tax, an established salary or stipend. Their exertion, zeal, and industry, will be much greater with voluntary contributions than a fixed fund.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article 3-Wage Taxes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2h-article-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2h-article-3/</guid>
      <description>131 Book 1 showed that the wages of lower class workers are regulated by two circumstances:
The demand for labour This demand requires an increasing, stationary, or declining population. It regulates the worker&amp;rsquo;s subsistence, whether liberal, moderate, or scanty. The ordinary or average price of goods This determines the amount of money which must be paid to the worker for his subsistence.
While the demand for labour and the price of goods remain the same, a direct tax on wages raises wages higher than the tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article 4-General taxes -- Capitation Taxes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2i-article-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2i-article-4/</guid>
      <description>138 The taxes which should fall indifferently on every different species of revenue, are:
 Capitation taxes Taxes on consumable commodities  These must be paid indifferently from rent, wages, or profits.
Capitation Taxes 139 Capitation taxes* become arbitrary if it is proportioned to the fortune or revenue of each taxpayer.
A man&amp;rsquo;s fortune varies daily. Without an intolerable annual inquisition, it can only be guessed at. His assessment must depend on the good or bad humour of his assessors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article 4-General Taxes -- Customs Duties</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2k-article-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2k-article-4/</guid>
      <description>The History of Customs Duties 165 Customs duties are much more ancient than excise duties.
They were called &amp;lsquo;customs&amp;rsquo; to denote customary payments which used from time immemorial. They were originally taxes on merchants&#39; profits. During the times of feudal anarchy, merchants were: a little better than emancipated bondmen, despised like all other burgh inhabitants. Merchants&#39; gains were envied. The nobility consented that the king should tallage the profits of: their own tenants, and the merchants who they were not interested in protecting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article 4-General Taxes -- French Taxation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2n-article-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2n-article-4/</guid>
      <description>215 In France, the different revenue laws in the different provinces require many revenue officers to:
 prevent the importation of certain goods, or subject imported goods to certain duties.  These interrupt France&amp;rsquo;s interior commerce.
Some provinces are allowed to compound for the gabelle or salt-tax. Others are exempted from it altogether. Some provinces are exempted from the exclusive sale of tobacco The farmers-general enjoy this exemption through most of France.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article 4-General Taxes -- Liquor Taxes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2l-article-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2l-article-4/</guid>
      <description>190 In Great Britain, liquors for private use are not liable to any excise duties.
This exemption aims to save private families from the tax-gatherer&amp;rsquo;s odious visit. It causes those duties to fall much lighter on the rich than the poor. Distilling for private use is not very common. But in the countryside, many middle class and almost all rich families brew their own beer. Their strong beer costs them 96 pence a barrel less than it costs the common brewer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article 4-General Taxes -- Taxes on luxuries</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2m-article-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2m-article-4/</guid>
      <description>205 Taxes on luxuries generally are paid piecemeal. In the time and mode of payment they are the most convenient of all taxes. On the whole, such taxes are against the fourth maxim, but agree with the other three.
206 Such taxes always take out or keep out from the people&amp;rsquo;s pockets more than almost any other taxes in four different ways:
 207 1. Their levying requires many custom-house and excise officers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Austere vs Liberal Morals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3q/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3q/</guid>
      <description>199 In every civilized society which has the distinction of ranks, there were always two systems of morality.
The strict or austere This is generally admired and revered by the common people. The liberal or loose system The loose is commonly more esteemed and adopted by people of fashion. The vices of levity is apt to arise from great prosperity.
It leads to the excess of gaiety and good humour. Our disapproval of levity is the principal distinction between those two opposite systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2g, Part 2-Article 2-Taxes on Profit</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2e-article-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2e-article-2/</guid>
      <description>86 Profits on stock naturally divides itself into two:
The part that pays the interest This part belongs to the owner of the stock The part that is in excess of what is needed to pay the interest.
87 This latter part of profit is not taxable directly.
It is the very moderate compensation for the risk and trouble of employing the stock. The employer must have this compensation, otherwise he cannot continue this employment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3D Bad Effects of Funding</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3d/</guid>
      <description>54 Land and capital stock are the two original sources of all private and public revenue.
Capital stock pays the wages of productive labour, whether employed in agriculture, manufactures, or commerce. The management of those two original sources of revenue belong to two sets of people:
 the proprietors of land, and the owners or employers of capital stock.  55 The proprietor of land is interested to keep his estate in as good condition as he can, for the sake of his own revenue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commercial Institutions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3c/</guid>
      <description>90 Particular institutions are necessary to facilitate particular branches of commerce.
These require a particular and extraordinary costs.
91 The commerce done with uncivilized nations needs extraordinary protection.
An ordinary counting-house gives little security to the goods of the merchants trading to the African west coast. Their warehouses should be fortified against the barbarous natives. The Indian government&amp;rsquo;s disorders rendered such fortifications necessary even among that mild and gentle people. The English and French East India Companies were allowed to build their first forts in India under pretence of securing their persons and property from violence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educational Fees</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3t/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3t/</guid>
      <description>227 The church benefices cannot be very big if they are all nearly equal.
This mediocrity of benefice may be carried too far but has very agreeable effects. Only the most exemplary morals can give dignity to a man of small fortune. Levity and vanity render him ridiculous. They are as ruinous to him as they are to common people. He must follow the moral system respected by the common people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Taxation Maxims</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2a-tax-maxims/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2a-tax-maxims/</guid>
      <description>23 Book 1 has shown that private revenue comes from rent, profit, and wages.
Every tax must ultimately be paid from any or all of those three kinds of revenue. Part 2 is about the taxes imposed on rent, profit, wages, and on all those three revenues. These three taxes have subdivisions. Many of those taxes are not ultimately paid by the source of revenue it is charged to.
24 Below are the four general maxims on taxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to solve religious conflicts</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3r/</guid>
      <description>202 There state can use two very easy and effective remedies to peacefully correct the disagreeably rigorous morals of little sects.
Remedy 1: 203 The study of science and philosophy. The state could make it universal among those of middling rank and fortune.
It could institute a probationary period for anyone who wished to: exercise any liberal profession, or be a candidate for any honourable office of trust or profit. It should not give salaries to teachers that would make them negligent and idle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellectual Property and Corporation Rules</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3k/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3k/</guid>
      <description>119 When a mercantile company establishes a new trade with a barbarous nation at their own risk and expence, it may be reasonable to:
 incorporate them into a joint stock company, and grant them a monopoly for a certain number of years in case of their success.  It is the easiest and most natural way the state can recompense them for hazarding a dangerous and expensive experiment.
The public will afterwards reap the benefit of their experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International barter taxation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3g/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3g/</guid>
      <description>79 It has been said that the Americans have no gold or silver money.
Their interior commerce is done by a paper currency. Its gold and silver are all sent to Great Britain for the commodities they receive from us. Without gold and silver it is impossible to pay taxes. We already get all their gold and silver. How can we draw from them what they do not have?
80 The current scarcity of gold and silver money in America is not the effect of the inability of the Americans to buy those metals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Militias</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1b/</guid>
      <description>Armies are Dominated by the Soldier Mentality 15 The state can use two methods for the public defence.
16 1. It may enforce military exercises.
It may oblige some citizens of military age to become soldiers, in addition to their current profession. It may do this through a very rigorous police, despite the people&#39;s contrary interest, genius, and inclinations. 18 This method forms a militia  17 2. It may separate the soldier&amp;rsquo;s profession from all other professions by maintaining and employing some citizens in constant military exercises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monetary Devaluation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3e/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3e/</guid>
      <description>Money Adulteration and Augmentation 61 The raising of the coin&amp;rsquo;s denomination has been the most usual way a real public bankruptcy is disguised under the appearance of a pretended payment.
For example, if an Act of Parliament doubled a coin&amp;rsquo;s denomination, the person who borrowed a coin worth four ounces of silver in the old denomination, would pay it back with a new coin worth only two ounces of silver. The capital of the funded and unfunded debt of Great Britain is about £128 million.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2, Article 1-Taxes on Land Rent</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2b-article-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2b-article-1/</guid>
      <description>30 A tax on land rent may be based on a valuation which is fixed and does not change with the actual rent which can fluctuate with its cultivation&amp;rsquo;s improvement or decline.
31 A land-tax assessed on each district according to an invariable rule becomes unequal after some time according to the lands&#39; unequal degrees of improvement or cultivation.
The tax becomes unequal even if it were equal at the start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2a-Expenses on Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-2a/</guid>
      <description>44 The second duty of the sovereign is to protect every member of society from the injustice or oppression of every other member.
The administration of justice requires very different costs in the different periods of society.
45 A nation of hunters has:
no property that exceeds the value of two or three days labour, and no established magistrate or any regular administration of justice.
Men who have no property can only injure one another in their persons or reputations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2b-Fees on Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-2b/</guid>
      <description>55 The second period of society is the age of shepherds.
The inequality of fortune first begins in this period. This period introduces a new degree of authority and subordination. It introduces some civil government necessary for its own preservation. It seems to do this naturally and independent of that necessity. The consideration of that necessity comes afterwards. It contributes very much to maintain and secure that authority and subordination. The rich are necessarily interested to support those who secure them in their own advantages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 3a</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3a/</guid>
      <description>69 The sovereign&amp;rsquo;s third and last duty is building and maintaining advantageous public works and institutions for society.
The profit from these works and institutions could never repay the expence to any few individuals. Individuals cannot be expected to build or maintain them. This duty costs very differently in the different periods of society.
70 The public institutions and public works necessary for society are those:
 for defence, for administering justice, for facilitating commerce, and for promoting public education  This chapter will be divided into three articles examining how their costs may be most properly defrayed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 3b</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3b/</guid>
      <description>81 A big revenue might be gained but probably not near as the projectors of this plan have supposed.
The plan itself is liable to very important objections:
82 1. If the turnpike tolls should be a resource for supplying state exigencies, the tolls would be increased as those exigencies required.
According to British policy, they would probably be increased very fast. This great revenue would probably encourage the government to very frequently recur to this resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copartneries vs Joint Stock Companies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3g/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3g/</guid>
      <description>104 Joint stock companies, established by royal charter or by act of parliament, differ from regulated companies and private copartneries.
105 1. In a private copartnery, no partner without the consent of the company can:
 transfer his share to another person, introduce a new member into the company.  Upon proper warning, each member may:
 withdraw from the copartnery, and demand payment for his share of the common stock from the copartnery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rent and sale of government lands</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-1b/</guid>
      <description>14 Land is a fund more naturally stable and permanent.
The rent of public lands was the main source of the public revenue of many great nations above the shepherd state. The ancient Greek and Italian republics derived most of the government revenue from the rent of public lands. The ancient European sovereigns for a long time derived their revenue from the rent of the crown lands.  15 War and the preparation for war create most of the expence of all great modern states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solutions -- Tax Reform</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3f/</guid>
      <description>68 The revenue might be very much increased without increasing the burden on the people through:
 a more equal land-tax, a more equal tax on house rents, and changes in the current customs and excise system, as those mentioned in (Chapter 2n)  It would distribute the burden more equally on all. This increase would not totally liberate the public revenue.
Adam Smith&amp;rsquo;s World Government 69 A much bigger revenue can be earmed by extending the British tax system to all the empire&amp;rsquo;s provinces inhabited by people of British or European descent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxes on Consumable Commodities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2j-article-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2j-article-4/</guid>
      <description>147 The impossibility of taxing people according to their revenue by any capitation led to the invention of taxes on consumable commodities.
The state, not knowing how to directly and proportionally tax the revenue of its subjects, taxes it indirectly by taxing their expence. Their expence is supposed to be proportional to their revenue. It is taxed by taxing the consumable commodities that they buy.
148 Necessities are commodities needed to support life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxes on House and Ground Rent</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2d-article-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2d-article-1/</guid>
      <description>66 House rents have two parts:
 The Building-rent The Ground-rent  67 The building-rent is the interest or profit on the capital spent in building the house.
To put the builder&amp;rsquo;s trade at level with other trades, this rent should be enough to: Pay him the same interest which he would have gotten if he lent out his capital Maintain the house or to replace the capital employed in building it within a certain term of years The building-rent is the ordinary profit of building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxes on the produce of land</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2c-article-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2c-article-1/</guid>
      <description>57 Taxes on the produce of land are really taxes on rent.
They are finally paid by the landlord even if they are originally paid by the farmer. When a part of the produce is paid as tax, the farmer computes the yearly value of that part.
 He makes a proportional abatement in the rent to pay to the landlord. All farmers compute beforehand what the yearly church tithe will amount to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxes on the Profit of Particular Employments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2f-article-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2f-article-2/</guid>
      <description>100 In some countries, extraordinary taxes are imposed on profits when employed:
 in particular trades, and in agriculture  101 The extraordinary taxes on particular trades in England are on:
 hawkers and pedlars, hackney coaches and chairs, and keepers of ale-houses who pay for a licence to retail liquors.  During the recent war, a similar tax was proposed on shops.
The war was entered to defend the trade of the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The African Company of Merchants (1752-1821)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3f/</guid>
      <description>101 Long after the time of Sir Josiah Child, in 1750, a regulated company was established, the present company of merchants trading to Africa.
The 23rd of George 2nd chapter 31 established this company.
It had two objects:
 To restrain the oppressive and monopolizing spirit natural to the directors of a regulated company, andand To force them to be attentive in maintaining forts and garrisons, something unnatural to them.  At first, it was expressly charged with the maintenance of all the British forts and garrisons between Cape Blanc and the Cape of Good Hope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The British East India Company</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3j/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3j/</guid>
      <description>115 The old English East India Company was established in 1600 by a charter from Queen Elizabeth.
It traded as a regulated company in its first 12 voyages to India. It had separate stocks only in the general ships of the company. In 1612, it united into a joint stock. Its charter was not confirmed by act of parliament and conveyed an exclusive privilege. For many years, it was not much disturbed by interlopers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Decline of the Church</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3s/</guid>
      <description>214 The gradual improvements of arts, manufactures, and commerce which destroyed the power of the great barons destroyed the whole temporal power of the clergy in Europe.
In the produce of arts, manufactures, and commerce, the clergy, like the great barons, found something for which they could exchange their rude produce. They discovered ways of spending their whole revenues on their own persons without sharing with other people. Their charity became gradually less extensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Development of Militaries</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1a/</guid>
      <description>Part 1: Defence Expenditures The first duty of the sovereign is to protect society from the violence and invasion of other societies.
It can only be performed through a military force. The cost of employing this military force in peacetime and wartime is very different in the different states and periods of the improvement of society.
The Development of Militaries 1 The hunting nation is the lowest and rudest state of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Expense of supporting the Dignity of the Sovereign</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-4/</guid>
      <description>232 The sovereign also needs a certain expence to support his dignity. This expence varies with:
 the different periods of improvement the different forms of government  233 In an opulent society, all the orders of people are everyday growing more expensive in their houses, furniture, dress, etc.
The sovereign should not be left out.
 He naturally becomes more expensive in all those articles too. His dignity even requires that he should become more expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The funds which belong to the sovereign or commonwealth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-1a/</guid>
      <description>1 The revenue which pays for national defense and supporting the dignity of the chief magistrate may be drawn:
 from some fund of the commonwealth, independent of the revenue of the people; or from the revenue of the people  Part 1 The funds which belong to the sovereign or commonwealth 2 The funds which belong to the sovereign must consist in stock or land.
3 The sovereign, like any other owner of stock, may derive a revenue from it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hamburgh Company</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3d/</guid>
      <description>98 The terms of admission into the Hamburgh Company are now quite easy.
The directors have not yet subjected the trade to any burdensome regulations. It was not always so. In the mid-17th century, the fine for admission was £50. At one time it was £100. The company&amp;rsquo;s conduct was extremely oppressive.
In 1643, 1645, and 1661, the clothiers and free traders west of England complained them to parliament as monopolists who:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hudson&#39;s Bay Company and South Sea Company</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3i/</guid>
      <description>110 Before their misfortunes in the recent war, the Hudson&amp;rsquo;s Bay Company was much more fortunate than the Royal African Company.
Their necessary expence is much smaller. They maintained up to 120 persons in their settlements and habitations, which they named as forts. 120 persons are sufficient to prepare the cargo of furs and other goods for their ships beforehand. Their ships can seldom remain more than eight weeks in those seas because of the ice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Royal African Company (1660-1752)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3h/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3h/</guid>
      <description>108 The Royal African Company is the predecessor of the present African Company.
It had an exclusive privilege by charter which was not confirmed by an act of parliament. After the declaration of rights after the revolution, the trade was opened to all his majesty&amp;rsquo;s subjects. The Hudson&amp;rsquo;s Bay Company is in the same situation as the Royal African Company in their legal rights. Their exclusive charter was not confirmed by an act of parliament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Turkey Company (1581-1825)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3e/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3e/</guid>
      <description>99 The fine for admission into the Turkey Company was formerly:
 £25 for all persons under 26 years old, and £50 for all persons above 26 years old.  Only mere merchants could be admitted.
This restriction excluded all shop-keepers and retailers. By a bylaw, no British manufactures could be exported to Turkey except in the company&amp;rsquo;s ships. Those ships always sailed from the expensive port of London. This restriction confined the trade to London and its traders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ways to pay public debts-Personal treasure or credit of ruler</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3a/</guid>
      <description>1 In Book 3, I showed that the person who has a large revenue in the rude state of society can enjoy that revenue only by maintaining as many people as possible. A large revenue then might consist in basic necessities such as:
 plain food coarse clothing corn and cattle wool and raw hides  When no commerce or manufactures is available to allow him to exchange his surplus, he can only use it to feed and clothe as many people as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women&#39;s Education and Basic Educational Institutions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3o/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3o/</guid>
      <description>175 There are no public educational institutions for women.
There is accordingly nothing useless, absurd, or fantastic in their common education. They are taught what their parents judge necessary or useful for them to learn and nothing else. Their education is used to: improve the natural attractions of their person, form their mind to reserve, modesty, chastity, and economy, make them the mistresses of a family, and make them behave properly when they have become such.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
