<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fallacies of Unenlightened Philosophy on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/fallacies/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fallacies of Unenlightened Philosophy on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/fallacies/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The A Priori Fallacy of Kant</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/fallacies/philosophy/kant-apriori-fallacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/fallacies/philosophy/kant-apriori-fallacy/</guid>
      <description>Dialectics was the most important part of Socrates&#39; philosophy, of which the Socratic dialogue is the only part that is understood by academics. Its most important parts are the metaphysical laws that he established, such as:
 the immortality of the soul and its reincarnation the pantheist God (Brahma) as the source of all souls the superiority of the metaphysical over the physical and so on  Nowadays, dialectics seems to be understood to be an exercise in logic, without any reference to metaphysical truths, God, or to finding solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who the Heck Created the Is-Ought Problem?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/fallacies/philosophy/is-ought-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/fallacies/philosophy/is-ought-problem/</guid>
      <description>While reviewing my simplification of David Hume’s Treatise of Human Nature Book 3, I came upon a strange wiki article called Hume’s Is-Ought Problem
 Hume calls for caution against such inferences in the absence of any explanation of how the ought-statements follow from the is-statements. But how exactly can an “ought” be derived from an “is”? The question, prompted by Hume’s small paragraph, has become one of the central questions of ethical theory, and Hume is usually assigned the position that such a derivation is impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
