<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Laws Of Education Should Be Relative To The Principles Of Government on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Laws Of Education Should Be Relative To The Principles Of Government on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ancient vs Modern Education. Education in a Republic</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-4/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-4/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 3: Education in a despotic Government AS education in monarchies tends to raise and ennoble the mind, in despotic governments its only aim is to debase it. Here it must necessarily be servile: even in power such an education will be an advantage, because every tyrant is at the same time a slave.
Excessive obedience supposes ignorance in the person that obeys. The same it supposes in him that Edition: current; Page: [42] commands; for he has no occasion to deliberate, to doubt, to reason; he has only to will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greek Institutions and Manners</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-4/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-4/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 6: Some Institutions among the Greeks THE ancient Greeks, convinced of the necessity that people who live under a popular government should be trained up to virtue, made very singular institutions in order to inspire it. Upon seeing, in the life of Lycurgus, the laws that legislator gave to the Lacedæmonians, I imagine I am reading the history of the Sevarambes. The laws of Crete were the model of those of Sparta; and those of Plato reformed them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Laws of Education</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-4/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-4/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1: Education in Monarchy and Despotism The laws of education are the first impressions we receive. They prepare us for civil life, every private family ought to be governed by the plan of that great household which comprehends them all.the people in general have a principle, their constituent parts, that is, the several families, will have one also. The laws of education will be therefore different in each species of government: in monarchies, they will have honour for their object; in republics, virtue; in despotic governments, fear.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
