<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The General Theory of Employment, Interest and Money on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The General Theory of Employment, Interest and Money on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Appendix on User Cost</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-7appendix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-7appendix/</guid>
      <description>I
The Classical theory of value has an important concept called the USER cost, which has been overlooked.
U = A1 + (G&#39; - B&#39;) - G
 U: An entrepreneur’s user cost A1 is the amount of our entrepreneur’s purchases from other entrepreneurs G the actual value of his capital equipment at the end of the period G&#39; the value it might have had at the end of the period if he had refrained from using it and had spent the optimum sum B&#39; on its maintenance and improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appendix to Chapter 14</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-14appendix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-14appendix/</guid>
      <description>THERE is not much discussion of the rate of interest in the works of Marshall, Edgeworth or Professor Pigou.
Alfred Marshall: Interest is the price of capital Principles of Economics **Interest is the price paid for the use of capital in any market.** It tends towards an equilibrium level such that the aggregate demand for capital in that market, at that rate of interest, is equal to the aggregate stock forthcoming there at that rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appendix to Chapter 14</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter14appendixdel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter14appendixdel/</guid>
      <description>Appendix on the Rate of Interest in Marshall’s “Principles of Economics” Book 6 p. 534 and p. 593, Ricardo’s “Principles of Political Economy”, and elsewhere
I
THERE is not much discussion of the rate of interest in the works of Marshall, Edgeworth or Professor Pigou.
Marshall’s position on the rate of interest
Interest is the price paid for the use of capital in any market. It tends towards an equilibrium level such that the aggregate demand for capital in that market, at that rate of interest, is equal to the aggregate stock forthcoming there at that rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appendix to Chapter 19-Professor Pigou’s Theory of Unemployment</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-19appendix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-19appendix/</guid>
      <description>PROFESSOR PIGOU makes the volume of employment to depend on two factors:
  The real rates of wages for which workpeople stipulate
  The shape of the Real Demand Function for Labour
  His work determines the shape of the latter function.
The fact that workpeople in fact stipulate, not for a real rate of wages, but for a money-rate, is not ignored; but, in effect, it is assumed that the actual money-rate of wages divided by the price of wage-goods can be taken to measure the real rate demanded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expectation Determines Output and Employment</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>ALL production is for the purpose of ultimately satisfying a consumer. Time usually elapses, however — and sometimes much time — between the incurring of costs by the producer (with the consumer in view) and the purchase of the output by the ultimate consumer. Meanwhile the entrepreneur (including both the producer and the investor in this description) has to form the best expectations[1] he can as to what the consumers will be prepared to pay when he is ready to supply them (directly or indirectly) after the elapse of what may be a lengthy period; and he has no choice but to be guided by these expectations, if he is to produce at all by processes which occupy time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sundry Observations on the Nature of Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>I
AN act of individual saving means — so to speak — a decision not to have dinner to-day. But it does not necessitate a decision to have dinner or to buy a pair of boots a week hence or a year hence or to consume any specified thing at any specified date.
Thus it depresses the business of preparing to-day’s dinner without stimulating the business of making ready for some future act of consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Choice of Units</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Chapters 4 to 7 are a digression on three perplexities:
  The choice of the units of quantity for an economic system as a whole
  The part played by expectation in economic analysis
  The definition of income
  The units of an economist are unsatisfactory, as proven by the National Dividend, the stock of real capital and the general price-level:
 The National Dividend  This was defined by Marshall and Professor Pigou.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Classical Theory of the Rate of Interest</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>1
Investment is the use of assets (circulating or fixed) to earn profits.
Interest is the revenue from lending those circulating assets to someone else for them to earn a profit from. Interest rate is the rate of revenue in lending. Savings are the assets that are taken out of one&amp;rsquo;s own circulation to be circulated by someone else.
According to the Classical Theory
Investment is the demand for investable resources Savings represents the supply for investable resources The rate of interest is the “price” of investable resources at which the two are equated</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Definition of Income, Saving and Investment</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>I. Let:
 A be an entrepreneur&amp;rsquo;s income from a sale of a product. A1 is his expense in buying that product from his supplier. G is his expense for capital equipment  This includes his unfinished goods (working capital) and finished goods    Some part, however, of A + G - A1 will be attributable, not to the activities of the period in question, but to the capital equipment which he had at the beginning of the period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Essential Properties of Interest and Money</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>I
The interest rate of money sets a standard to which the marginal efficiency of a capital-asset must attain if it is to be newly produced. This makes it play a part in limiting the level of employment.
At first sight, this is most perplexing. It is natural to enquire wherein the peculiarity of money lies as distinct from other assets, whether it is only money which has a rate of interest, and what would happen in a non-monetary economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The General Theory of the Rate of Interest</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 11 shows that there are forces causing the rate of investment to rise or fall so as to keep the rate of return on investments equal to the rate of interest.
Yet the rate of return on investments is, in itself, a different thing from the rate of interest.
The investment-demand curve governs how loanable funds are turned to new investment.
The rate of interest governs how funds are being currently supplied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marginal Efficiency of Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>When a man makes an investment, he buys the right to prospective returns.
I call this &amp;ldquo;the prospective yield of the investment&amp;rdquo;.
This prospective yield has a supply price which is the cost to create that investment.
This supply price is not the market price at which it is bought. The relation between the prospective yield and its supply price gives us its marginal efficiency of capital. It is equal to that rate of discount which would make the present value of the series of annuities given by the returns expected from the capital-asset during its life just equal to its supply price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marginal Efficiency of Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 18. The General Theory of Employment Re-Stated I WE have now reached a point where we can gather together the threads of our argument. To begin with, it may be useful to make clear which elements in the economic system we usually take as given, which are the independent variables of our system and which are the dependent variables. We take as given the existing skill and quantity of available labour, the existing quality and quantity of available equipment, the existing technique, the degree of competition, the tastes and habits of the consumer, the disutility of different intensifies of labour and of the activities of supervision and organisation, as well as the social structure including the forces, other than our variables set forth below, which determine the distribution of the national income.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marginal Efficiency of Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>Book V Money-Wages and Prices
Chapter 19. Changes in Money-Wages
I
IT would have been an advantage if the effects of a change in money-wages could have been discussed in an earlier chapter. For the Classical Theory has been accustomed to rest the supposedly self-adjusting character of the economic system on an assumed fluidity of money-wages; and, when there is rigidity, to lay on this rigidity the blame of maladjustment. It was not possible, however, to discuss this matter fully until our own theory had been developed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marginal Efficiency of Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 20. The Employment Function
[1] I IN Chapter 3 (p 25) we have defined the aggregate supply function Z = φ(N), which relates the employment N with the aggregate supply price of the corresponding output. The employment function only differs from the aggregate supply function in that it is, in effect, its inverse function and is defined in terms of the wage-unit; the object of the employment function being to relate the amount of the effective demand, measured in terms of the wage-unit, directed to a given firm or industry or to industry as a whole with the amount of employment, the supply price of the output of which will compare to that amount of effective demand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marginal Efficiency of Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>h1 Chapter 21. The Theory of Prices p | The Theory of Value has traditionally been based on supply and demand, particularly in changes in marginal cost and the elasticity of short-period supply. ul li | But when they pass to the Theory of Money and Prices, value becomes governed by ul li the quantity of money, li its income-velocity, li the velocity of circulation relative to the volume of transactions li hoarding, li forced saving, li inflation and deflation et hoc genus omne.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marginal Efficiency of Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>Book VI Short Notes Suggested by the General Theory
Chapter 22. Notes on the Trade Cycle
SINCE we claim to have shown in the preceding chapters what determines the volume of employment at any time, it follows, if we are right, that our theory must be capable of explaining the phenomena of the Trade Cycle. If we examine the details of any actual instance of the Trade Cycle, we shall find that it is highly complex and that every element in our analysis will be required for its complete explanation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marginal Efficiency of Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>Book VI Short Notes Suggested by the General Theory
Chapter 23. Notes on Mercantilism) The Usury Laws, Stamped Money and Theories of Under-Consumption
I FOR some two hundred years both economic theorists and practical men did not doubt that there is a peculiar advantage to a country in a favourable balance of trade, and grave danger in an unfavourable balance, particularly if it results in an efflux of the precious metals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marginal Efficiency of Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 24. Concluding Notes on the Social Philosophy towards which the General Theory might Lead
I THE outstanding faults of the economic society in which we live are its failure to provide for full employment and its arbitrary and inequitable distribution of wealth and incomes. The bearing of the foregoing theory on the first of these is obvious. But there are also two important respects in which it is relevant to the second.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marginal Propensity to Consume and the Multiplier</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Book 3 The Propensity to Consume
Chapter 8 established that employment can only increase pari passu with investment.
We can now carry this line of thought a stage further. For in given circumstances a definite ratio, to be called the Multiplier, can be established between income and investment and, subject to certain simplifications, between the total employment and the employment directly employed on investment (which we shall call the primary employment).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Saving and Investment Further Considered</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chaper-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chaper-7/</guid>
      <description>I
IN the previous chapter Saving and Investment have been so defined that they are necessarily equal in amount, being, for the community as a whole, merely different aspects of the same thing.
Several contemporary writers (including myself in my Treatise on Money) have, however, given special definitions of these terms on which they are not necessarily equal. Others have written on the assumption that they may be unequal without prefacing their discussion with any definitions at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principle of Effective Demand</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>In a given state of technique, resources and costs, the employment of a given volume of labour by an entrepreneur involves him in two kinds of expense:
  The amounts which he pays out to the factors of production (exclusive of other entrepreneurs) for their current services, which we shall call the factor cost of the employment in question
  The amounts which he pays out to other entrepreneurs for what he has to purchase from them together with the sacrifice which he incurs by employing the equipment instead of leaving it idle, which we shall call the user cost of the employment in question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principle of Effective Demand</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>I
We need, to start with, a few terms which will be defined precisely later. In a given state of technique, resources and costs, the employment of a given volume of labour by an entrepreneur involves him in two kinds of expense: first of all, the amounts which he pays out to the factors of production (exclusive of other entrepreneurs) for their current services, which we shall call the factor cost of the employment in question; and secondly, the amounts which he pays out to other entrepreneurs for what he has to purchase from them together with the sacrifice which he incurs by employing the equipment instead of leaving it idle, which we shall call the user cost of the employment in question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Propensity to Consume</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>I.
The Objective Factors I WE are now in a position to return to our main theme, from which we broke off at the end of Book I in order to deal with certain general problems of method and definition. The ultimate object of our analysis is to discover what determines the volume of employment. So far we have established the preliminary conclusion that the volume of employment is determined by the point of intersection of the aggregate supply function with the aggregate demand function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Propensity to Consume</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>II. The Subjective Factors I THERE remains the second category of factors which affect the amount of consumption out of a given income, namely, those subjective and social incentives which determine how much is spent, given the aggregate of income in terms of wage-units and given the relevant objective factors which we have already discussed. Since, however, the analysis of these factors raises no point of novelty, it may be sufficient if we give a catalogue of the more important, without enlarging on them at any length.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Psychological and Business Incentives To Liquidity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>h2 1
p | What are the motives for liquidity-preference? ul li This is the same as what was discussed in the Demand for Money. li | It is also closely connected with what is called the income-velocity of money. ul li The income-velocity of money merely measures what proportion of their incomes the public chooses to hold in cash, so that an increased income-velocity of money may be a symptom of a decreased liquidity-preference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Long-Term Expectation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>I
Chapter 11 explained that the scale of investment depends on the relation between:
 the rate of interest and the schedule of the marginal efficiency of capital corresponding to different scales of current investment  The marginal efficiency of capital depends on the relation between:
 the supply price of a capital-asset its prospective yield.  What are the factors which determine the prospective yield of an asset?
These may be:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
