<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 2 on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 2 on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Convents and Orphanages as Population Control</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/11b-convents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/11b-convents/</guid>
      <description>Convents and Orphanages as Population Control Modern convents are bad institutions. These are popish institutions which should be condemned as:
 nurseries of superstition, burdensome to the public, and oppressive to their poor prisoners  Do they reduce a state&amp;rsquo;s population size?
Anciently, every great family was a kind of convent. If a convent&amp;rsquo;s lands were given to a nobleman, he would spend its revenue on dogs, horses, footmen, and house-maids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faulty Ancient Records</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/11e-ancient-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/11e-ancient-records/</guid>
      <description>Upon comparing the whole, it is impossible why the world should have been more populous in ancient than in modern times.
The equality of property among the ancients, liberty, and the small divisions of their states, were favourable to their population growth. But:
 their wars were more bloody and destructive, their governments more factious and unsettled, commerce and manufactures more feeble and languishing, and the general police more loose and irregular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leniency and Inequality Leading to Disorder and Decline of Commerce</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/11d-leniency-inequality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/11d-leniency-inequality/</guid>
      <description>The Leniency of the Romans The refined Greeks were violent, so it means that the barbarous commonwealths of Africa, Spain, and Gaul were so much more. An exception is the Roman commonwealth wherein no blood was ever shed in any sedition at Rome, until the murder of the Gracchi.
Dionysius Halicarnassæus, observed the singular humanity of the Roman people and which makes him believe that they were originally of Greek extraction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Population of Ancient Rome and Italy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/11g-roman-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/11g-roman-population/</guid>
      <description>Ancient Housing Halicarnassæus says that:
The ancient walls of Rome were nearly of the same compass with those of Athens, but that the suburbs ran out to a great extent. It was difficult to tell, where the town ended or the country began.  Halicarnassæus, Juvenal, and other ancient writers say that the Roman houses were high and families lived in separate storeys, one above another.
But these were probably only the poorer citizens in a few streets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Populousness Of Ancient Nations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/11-ancient-population-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/11-ancient-population-size/</guid>
      <description>The world is not eternal nor incorruptible.
The following prove the mortality of this world, its passage, by corruption or dissolution, from one state or order to another:
 the continual and rapid motion of matter, the violent revolutions with which every part is agitated, the changes remarked in the heavens, the plain traces as well as tradition of an universal deluge, or general convulsion of the elements  Society must therefore have its infancy, youth, manhood, and old age, similar to that each individual form which it contains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Populousness Of Ancient Nations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/11f-greek-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/11f-greek-population/</guid>
      <description>Let us now examine the numbers of inhabitants assigned to particular cities in antiquity; and omitting the numbers of Nineveh, Babylon, and the Egyptian Thebes,
The more I look into this, the more I doubt the great populousness of the ancient times.
Plato says:
Athens was the greatest of all the Greek cities, except Syracuse, which was nearly about the same size in Thucydides’s time, and afterwards encreased beyond it.  Cicero mentions Athens as the greatest of all the Greek cities in his time, excluding Antioch or Alexandria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War Prevented Ancient Populousness</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/11c-ancient-wars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/11c-ancient-wars/</guid>
      <description>There are commonly compensations in every human condition. These are not always perfectly equal, yet they restrain the prevailing principle.
The ancient republics were almost in perpetual war. It was a natural effect of:
 their martial spirit, their love of liberty and mutual emulation, and that hatred among neighbouring nations the equality    Martial Spirit   Now, war in a small state is much more destructive than in a great one because:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commerce</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/1-commerce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/1-commerce/</guid>
      <description>General vs Specific Principles People may be divided into two:
 Shallow thinkers who fall short of the truth Abstruse thinkers, who go beyond it. This is the most rare and by far the most useful and valuable.  Abstruse thinkers suggest hints. Sometimes, they start difficulties if they lack the skill to pursue an idea. At worst, abstruse thinkers say uncommon things, which are hard to understand but at least are new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Luxury?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/2-luxury/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/2-luxury/</guid>
      <description>Luxury is an ambiguous word, being used both in a good and a bad sense. In general, it means great refinement in the gratification of the senses.
Any degree of it may be innocent or blameable, according to the age, country, or condition of the person. Its virtue and vice cannot here be exactly fixed, more than in other moral subjects.
Religious fervor sees that the gratification and indulgence in meat, drink, or apparel, is of itself a vice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/3-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/3-money/</guid>
      <description>Money is not a subject of commerce. It is only the instrument which men have agreed upon to facilitate the exchange of one commodity for another.
It is not the wheel of trade. It is the oil which renders the motion of the wheels more smooth and easy.
The amount of money is of no consequence in any country since the prices of commodities are always proportional to the amount of money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interest</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/4-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/4-interest/</guid>
      <description>The lowness of interest is the most certain sign of a nation&amp;rsquo;s prosperity. Lowness of interest is generally ascribed to plenty of money.
Interest Rates are Not Caused by Money Supply But this is not true since the only effect of the plenty of money is to raise the price of labour. Silver is more common than gold. You receive more of it for the same commodities. But do you pay less interest for it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Balance Of Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/5-balance-of-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/5-balance-of-trade/</guid>
      <description>Export Bans Nations who are ignorant of the nature of commerce usually prohibit the exports of valuable and useful commodities.
They do not consider that:
 this prohibition acts directly contrary to their intention. the more they export, the more will be raised at home, of which they themselves wil l always have the first offer  The ancient laws of Athens criminalized the exportation of figs. Theydeemed it too delicious for the palate of any foreigner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Balance Of Power</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/7-balance-of-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/7-balance-of-power/</guid>
      <description>Is the idea of the balance of power created by modern policy? Or is it a new invention?
Xenophon&amp;rsquo;s Institution of Cyrus writes about the combination of the Asiatic powers from a jealousy of the encreasing force of the Medes and Persians. This proves that the balance of power was a prevailing notion in the ancient times.
This balance is in the anxiety of Greek politics. Thucydides writes that the league formed against Athens leading to the Peloponnesian war was caused by this principle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Jealousy of Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/6-jealousy-of-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/6-jealousy-of-trade/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay 8: Taxes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/8-taxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/8-taxes/</guid>
      <description>There is a prevailing maxim that:
 every new tax creates a new ability in the subject to bear it each encrease of public burdens proportionally encreases the people&amp;rsquo;s industry  This maxim is most likely to be abused. It is so much more dangerous, because it cannot be denied. It has some foundation in reason and experience when kept within certain bounds.
When a tax is laid on commodities consumed by the common people, the poor must :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor Theory of Value</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/1b-labor-theory-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/1b-labor-theory-value/</guid>
      <description>*Translator&amp;rsquo;s Note: These are mirrored by Book 1 Chapter 5 and Book 3 of The Wealth of Nations by Adam Smith
 Everything in the world is purchased by labour. The only cause of our labour are our passions. When a nation abounds in manufactures and mechanic arts, the proprietors of land and the farmers study agriculture as a science. They redouble their industry and attention.
The superfluity from their labour is exchanged with manufactures now coveted by men’s luxury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passive Obedience</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/13-passive-obedience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/13-passive-obedience/</guid>
      <description>What are the practical consequences, deduced by each party, with regard to obedience to sovereigns?
Justice is founded entirely on the interests of society, which require mutual abstinence from property, in order to preserve peace. Whenever law enforcement has very pernicious consequences during emergencies, justice must be suspended and give way to public utility.
The maxim &amp;lsquo;let justice be performed, even if it destroys the universe&amp;rsquo; is false. It sacrifices the end to the means and shews a preposterous idea of the subordination of duties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Credit</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/9-public-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/9-public-credit/</guid>
      <description>In ancient times, the common practice was to hoard up treasures during peacetime for paying conquest or defence during wartime. They did not resort to taxation or borrowing in times of disorder and confusion.
 The Athenians, Ptolemies, and the other successors of Alexander amassed immense large sums. Plato says that the frugal Spartans had also collected a great treasure. Arrian and Plutarch took notice of Alexander&amp;rsquo;s riches from the conquest of Susa and Ecbatana, which came from the time of Cyrus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Remarkable Customs</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/10-remarkable-customs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/10-remarkable-customs/</guid>
      <description>Three remarkable customs in three celebrated governments prove:
 that all general maxims in politics should be established with great caution that irregular and extraordinary appearances are frequently discovered in the moral and physical world  1. We think that all the members of a supreme council should have freedom of speech. After a motion has been voted and approved by that assembly, its proposer must forever be exempted from future trial or enquiry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coalition Of Parties</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/14-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/14-parties/</guid>
      <description>In a free government, the abolition of all distinctions of party may not be practicable, perhaps not desirable, .
The only dangerous parties are those that aim to change the:
 essentials of government, succession of the crown, or considerable privileges of several members of the constitution  They prefer violence over compromise.
The parties in England had this animosity for over the last 100 years, which caused civil war sometimes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ideal System of Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/16-the-ideal-system-of-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/16-the-ideal-system-of-government/</guid>
      <description>Great Britain and Ireland, or any territory of equal extent would be divided into 100 counties. Each county has 100 districts, leading to 10,000 districts.
 Country A  County 1  District 1-1 District 1-2 .. District 1-100   County 2  District 2-1 District 2-2 .. District 2-100   County 3 .. County 100    If the country is smaller, we can reduce the number of counties, but never below 30.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Original Contract</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/12-original-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/12-original-contract/</guid>
      <description>No party in the present age can support itself without philosophical principles annexed to its political or practical one.
Thus all factions in England have thought of speculative principles to protect and cover their scheme of actions.
The people are commonly very rude builders, especially in this speculative way. This is more true when actuated by party-zeal. Their projects become a little unshapely, with marks of that violence and hurry, in which it was raised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Protestant Succession</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/15-protestant-succession/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-2/15-protestant-succession/</guid>
      <description>When the Protestant Succession was still uncertain during the reign of Queen Anne, A member of parliament asked which party he would choose.
He would easily perceive the great advantage resulting from the restoration of the Stuart family; by which we should preserve the succession clear and undisputed, free from a pretender, with such a specious title as that of blood, which, with the multitude, is always the claim, the strongest and most easily comprehended.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
