<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 6: Philosophy on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-6/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 6: Philosophy on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Versus Pleasure, Science Versus Dialectics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-6/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-6/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Good is Not Pleasure The person who wants to see the soul in its perfect beauty must take a longer route to find such beauty in it. But beauty is the same as opinion which needs a measure common to all. Indolent people use measures based on their own limited perceptions.
This would be the worst fault in a guardian and of the laws.
The guardian then must be required to take the longer circuit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophical Education</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-6/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-6/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>The Characteristics of Guardians Adeimantus: Which of the current governments are adapted to philosophy?  None of them. The exotic seed which is sown in a foreign land becomes denaturalized. Similarly, philosophy grown in a bad soil degenerates and receives another character.
But if philosophy ever finds perfection in a State, then she will be seen in truth divine and that all other things, whether natures of men or institutions, are but human.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The True Philosopher</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-6/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-6/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>The true philosophers have knowledge, while the false philosophers only have opinion. Only true philosophers are able to grasp the eternal and unchangeable. Those philosophers who are best able to guard the laws and institutions of our State should be our guardians. The following people are simply blind, those who:
 lack the knowledge of the true being of each thing, have no clear pattern in their souls, are unable as with a painter&#39;s eye to look at the absolute truth and repair to the original, are unable to have a perfect vision of the other world, order the laws about beauty, goodness, justice, and guard and preserve their order.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
