<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 3: The Ideal Policies on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 3: The Ideal Policies on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moral Literature</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-3/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-3/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Fear-based ideas Such as Hell Should Be Removed Such are our principles of theology. Some tales should be told, others should not be told to our disciples from their youth upwards, if we value friendship and mean them to honour the gods and their parents. But if they are courageous, they must learn other lessons, like those that will remove the fear of death. A man can be fearless of death if he does not believe that the world below is real and terrible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proper Food and Medicine</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-3/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-3/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Food and Medicine are Connected What about their food?  The men are training for the great contest of all. I am afraid that their bodily habits are rather perilous to health. These athletes:  sleep away their lives, and are liable to the most dangerous illnesses if they depart from their customary regimen.  A finer sort of training will be required for our warrior athletes, who are:
 to be like wakeful dogs, and to see and hear with the utmost keenness amid the many changes of water and food, of summer heat and winter cold, which they will have to endure when on a campaign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proper Music</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-3/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-3/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Sad Music Should not be Promoted by the State A song or ode has three parts:  the words, the melody, and the rhythm  There is no difference between words set to music and those not set to music. Both will conform to the same laws. The melody and rhythm will depend on the words. We had no need of lamentation. The harmonies which express sorrow are the mixed or tenor Lydian, and the full-toned or bass Lydian, and those similar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Natural Order of Society</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-3/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-3/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Lawmakers and Lawyers Must Be Virtuous All that, Socrates, is excellent. But I shouldn&#39;t there be good physicians in a State who will treat the people, both healthy and unhealthy?  The best judges know all sorts of moral natures. The most skilful physicians have the greatest experience with diseases, from their youth upwards. They should have had all manner of diseases in themselves. They cure their body with their mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rules for Guardians</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-3/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-3/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Adeimantus: A person might say:  that you are making these Guardians miserable, that they are the cause of their own unhappiness, that the city in fact belongs to the Guardians yet they gain nothing form it, whereas other men acquire lands, build large houses, and have everything handsome about them, offering sacrifices to the gods and practising hospitality, that the Guardians have non-physical wealth, but are just as poor as our citizens, and that they are no better than mercenaries who are quartered in the city and are always mounting guard.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
