<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medical Superphysics on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/medical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Medical Superphysics on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/medical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Viruses are in-between Life and Ideas</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/medical/viruses-are-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/medical/viruses-are-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Viruses are not living organisms, but are merely bad idea-waves, manifesting as RNA-particles or code, which infect the code or DNA of actual living organisms. They expand exponentially, just like rumors and fashion trends, as long as there are many minds that are susceptible to fake news, rumors, and fashion. Fake news easily infects minds that have low resistance to information and are far from the truth, just as viruses easily infect those that put anything into their bodies, and are far from their natural state of health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Stop COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/medical/how-to-stop-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/medical/how-to-stop-covid/</guid>
      <description>The Corona virus disease began in January in Wuhan, China just before the Lunar New Year. At that time, it bore all the signs of SARS and so the world was not so alarmed, as China and Hongkong already had experience with such an epidemic.
This all changed from February 20 when it spread into Iran and Italy. By March 11, the World Health Organization declared it as a pandemic. As of May 26, or 5 months in, there have been 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancers and diseases have already been cured</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/medical/diseases-have-been-cured/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/medical/diseases-have-been-cured/</guid>
      <description>Wave-based treatments from Ayurveda, Traditional Chinese Medicine, Natural Treatment, and Homeopathy have been curing diseases for a long time. For example:
 the Chinese doctor checks the patient&amp;rsquo;s pulse the Homeopath checks the patient&amp;rsquo;s electrical current  These provide the doctor with wave-data that is not present to the Western doctor. These are not studied by Western medicine as these are not chemical based nor observable by sight under a microscope or MRI machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Hume&#39;s Idea of the Self</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/medical/idea-of-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/medical/idea-of-self/</guid>
      <description>In Book 1 of A Treatise of Human Nature, David Hume laid out his principle of the self.
According to him, &amp;lsquo;identity&amp;rsquo; is a perception of something that is separate from another perception. For example, the identity of a car&amp;rsquo;s tire is a separate identity from the car because our minds can perceive them as separately existing.
If our minds cannot separate them, then their identity is one. An example is the balloon of a hot air balloon which cannot be separated without destroying its vehicle&amp;rsquo;s identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Medical Democracy?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/medical/medical-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/medical/medical-democracy/</guid>
      <description>The current medical system is derived from the Western system which took off after the invention of the microscope. That device allowed Westerners to see new things like bacteria and cells, as well as their effect on each other. This led to antibiotics, chemical-based medicines, pasteurization, and early vaccines.
Colonization by the Europeans, allowed them to spread their knowledge and culture to the world. These have allowed most of the world to:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
