<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Harmonies on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/kepler/harmonies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Harmonies on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/kepler/harmonies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Ratios of Planetary Movements as Spectators Of The Sun As Notes Of The Musical Scale</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/kepler/harmonies/5-movement-as-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/kepler/harmonies/5-movement-as-music/</guid>
      <description>Through numbers, I have proven that
gotten on one side from astronomy and on the other side from harmonics that, taken in every which way,
harmonic ratios hold between these 12 termini or movements of the six planets revolving around the sun or that they approximate such ratios within an imperceptible part of least concord.
In Book 3, Chapter 1, we first built up the single harmonic consonances separately, and then joined together all the consonances—as many as there were—in one common system or musical scale, or, rather, in one octave of them which embraces the rest in power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do Planetary Movements Show the Harmonic Consonances of The Creator?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/kepler/harmonies/4-planetary-movements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/kepler/harmonies/4-planetary-movements/</guid>
      <description>Accordingly, if the image of the retrogradation and stations is taken away and the proper movements of the planets in their real eccentric orbits are winnowed out, the following distinct things still remain in the planets:
 The distances from the sun. The periodic times. The diurnal eccentric arcs. The diurnal delays in those arcs. The angles at the sun, and the diurnal arcs apparent to those as it were gazing from the sun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Astronomical Doctrine For The Celestial Harmonies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/kepler/harmonies/3-celestial-harmonies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/kepler/harmonies/3-celestial-harmonies/</guid>
      <description>The ancient astronomical hypotheses of Ptolemy should be completely removed for they do not convey the true lay out of the bodies of the world and the polity of the movements.
I would like to persuade everyone instead of Copernicus’ opinion. But his idea is still new among the mass of the intelligentsia. The doctrine that the Earth is one of the planets that move among the stars around a motionless sun sounds very absurd to most of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kinship Between The Harmonic Ratios And The Five Figures</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/kepler/harmonies/2-kinship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/kepler/harmonies/2-kinship/</guid>
      <description>This kinship [cognatio] is various and manifold, but there are 4 degrees of it.
For either the sign of kinship is taken from the outward form alone which the figures have, or else ratios which are the same as the harmonic arise in the construction of the side, or result from the figures already constructed, taken simply or together; or, lastly, they are either equal to or approximate the ratios of the spheres of the figure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Five Regular Solid Figures</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/kepler/harmonies/1-five-solid-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/kepler/harmonies/1-five-solid-figures/</guid>
      <description>Book 2 explained:
 how the regular plane figures are fitted together to form solids the five regular solids, among others, on account of the plane figures. why the Platonists designated 5 as the figures of the world what element any solid was compared on account of what property.  I will now explain these figures by themselves and not on account of the planes, as much as suffices for the celestial harmonies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
