<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Section 2: The Causal Feelings That Affect the Ego-judgment on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Section 2: The Causal Feelings That Affect the Ego-judgment on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Bodily Sensations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-2/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-2/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction 1 The spectator can go along with our feelings which lie in a certain middle. If it is too high or too low, he cannot enter into it. For example, grief for private misfortunes and injuries may easily be too high in many people. They may also be too low, but rarely.
 We call excessive grief as &amp;lsquo;weakness&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;fury&amp;rsquo;. We call the shortage of grief as &amp;lsquo;stupidity&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;insensibility&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;lack of spirit&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Feelings from the Imagination</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-2/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-2/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Romantic love is natural but is not commonly expressed because it might be odious or ridiculous 15 The habitual feelings from the imagination are perfectly natural. But they are little sympathized with because other people might not have the same habits to be able to sympathize with them. Thus, such passions are always somewhat ridiculous.
An example is strong romantic attachment. We are unable to imagine what lovers experience, so we are not as eager as they are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Selfish  Feelings</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-2/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-2/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>The Selfish feelings are in between the Social and Unsocial feelings 32 Our grief and joy of our own fortune makes up the feelings which are in between the social and unsocial ones.
These selfish feelings are:
 never so graceful as the social feelings never so odious as the unsocial feelings.  When excessive, the selfish feelings are never so disagreeable as the unsocial feeling of excessive resentment.
 This is because no opposing sympathy is created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Social Feelings</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-2/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-2/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>The Amiable Virtues are Social Feelings 29 A divided sympathy makes anger and resentment so disagreeable. The social and benevolent feelings are opposite to these. They cause a redoubled sympathy which almost always render them agreeable.
The indifferent observer is almost always pleased with:
 Generosity Humanity Kindness Compassion Mutual friendship Esteem  The observer&amp;rsquo;s sympathy with the subject-person generating those feelings exactly coincides with his sympathy for the object-person who is receiving those feelings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unsocial feelings</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-2/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-2/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Hatred, Anger, and Resentment 21 Hatred and resentment must always be regulated before we can enter into them.
Our sympathy with them is divided between:
 its subject, or the person who feels them, and its object, or the person whom he is angry at.  The interests of these two are directly opposite.
 Our sympathy with the subject-person would prompt us to wish for fear.  Our sympathy with him is less than the anger which he feels:  because all sympathetic passions are inferior to the original ones, and beause of our opposite sympathy with the object-person.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
