<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Section 1: Sympathy as the Cause for Morality on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Section 1: Sympathy as the Cause for Morality on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How we judge Relative to Our Ego</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-1/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-1/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>When can we make moral judgements on others? 30 We may make moral judgments on two occasions.
1. When the cause of such feelings are unrelated to us or the other person 31 In this case, we ascribe goodness to the other person if his feelings correspond to ours. The following are unrelated to the ourselves nor to the other person:
 the beauty of a plain the greatness of a mountain the ornaments of a building the expression of a picture the conduct of a third person all the subjects of science and taste  He and I both look at them from the same point of view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we judge the feelings of others</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-1/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-1/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Our own feelings is the measure or decider of our sympathy or non-sympathy with the feelings of others 20 When the feelings of the observee perfectly concords with the observer&amp;rsquo;s sympathies, they appear suitable to the observer.
 On the contrary, when the observer finds that the observee&amp;rsquo;s feelings do not match his, they appear improper to him.  Therefore, approving another&amp;rsquo;s feelings is the same thing as entirely sympathizing with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sympathy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-1/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-1/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Compassion 1 However selfish man may be, his nature has pity or compassion which:
 interest him in the fortune of others, and render the happiness of others necessary to him, even if he only gets the pleasure of seeing that happiness  Pity or compassion is our feeling for the misery of others. We often derive sorrow from the sorrow of others. The virtuous and humane feel it most sensibly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Amiable and Respectable Virtues</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-1/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-1/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>40 Two sets of virtues are founded on these two efforts:
 The observer&amp;rsquo;s effort to enter into the observee&amp;rsquo;s feelings  On this effort is founded:
 the soft, gentle, amiable virtues, and the virtues of candid condescension and indulgent humanity.  The observee&amp;rsquo;s effort to bring down his emotions to what the observer can go along with  From this effort originates the respectable virtues of self-denial and self-control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pleasure of Mutual Sympathy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-1/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-1/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>The Pleasure from Mutual Sympathy is not based on Self-Love, but from the similarity of the resonance of feelings 14 Regardless of the cause of sympathy, we are most pleased when other people have a fellow-feeling with our own emotions. We are shocked by the opposite.
Some people say that all our feelings arise from self-love. They think:
 that our pleasure and pain from fellow-feeling come from self love that man always needs the assistance of others, and this is why:  he rejoices whenever others adopt his own passions, as it ensures him of that assistance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
