<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Nature of Commercial Laws on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Nature of Commercial Laws on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Improper Customs Destroys Commerce</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 13: How Improper Customs Destroys the Freedom of Commerce WHEREVER commerce subsists, customs are established.
 Commerce is the exportation and importation of merchandise with a view to the state&amp;rsquo;s advantage. Customs are a right over this exportation and importation, founded also on the state&amp;rsquo;s advantage.  The state should be neutral between its customs and its commerce. These two should not interfere with each other. After this, the people enjoy a free commerce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Prince should not engage himself in Commerce</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 19: A Prince should not engage in Commerce Theophilus saw a vessel laden with merchandises for his wife Theodora and ordered it to be burnt. He said: “I am Emperor, and you make me the master of a galley. How shall these poor men gain a livelihood, if we take their trade out of their hands?”
He might have added:
 &amp;ldquo;Who shall regulate us, if we monopolize all to ourselves?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commerce in different Governments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>TRADE has some relation to forms of government.
A monarchy is generally founded on luxury. Its principal view is to procure everything that can contribute to the pride, pleasure, and capricious whims of the nation.
A republic is commonly founded on economy. Its merchants have an eye to all the nations of the earth. They bring from one what is wanted by another. The republics of Tyre, Carthage, Athens, Marseilles, Florence, Venice, and Holland, engaged in commerce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Institutions for Commerce: Banks, Freeports, Trade Rules</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10: Banks IN economical commercial states, they have luckily established banks which have created a new kind of wealth by their credit. But it would be wrong to introduce banks into governments whose commerce is founded only in luxury.
In an absolute monarchy, only the prince or can have treasure. If wealth is created by others then it is seized by the prince. Thus, banks in an absolute monarchy would suppose money on one side but without any power, and power on the other side but without any means to procure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Law in Geneva and Rhodesia, Commercial Judges</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 16: An excellent Law of Rhodes Geneva has an admirable law which excludes the children of bankrupts from the magistracy and even from the admittance into the great council until they have discharged their father’s debts.
It gives a confidence in:
 the merchants the magistrates, and the city itself  There, the credit of the individual still has all the weight of public credit.
Chapter 17: A Law of Rhodes THE Rhodesians went further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spirit of Commerce and Two Types of Poor</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1: How Commerce Improves and Corrupts Morals Commerce is a cure for the most destructive prejudices.
 whereever we find agreeable manners, there commerce flourishes wherever there is commerce, there we meet with agreeable manners.  Our manners are now less savage because of commerce. It has everywhere diffused a knowledge of the manners of all nations. These are compared one with another, and from this comparison arise the greatest advantages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To what Nations Commerce is prejudicial</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-20/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 23: To what Nations Commerce is prejudicial Riches consist either in lands, or in moveable effects.
The soil of every country is commonly possessed by the natives. The laws of most states render foreigners unwilling to purchase their lands; Only the presence of the owner improves them: this kind of riches therefore belongs to every state in particular. But moveable effects, as money, notes, bills of exchange, stocks in companies, vessels, and all merchandises, belong to the whole world in general.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
