<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Material Superphysics Solutions on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/material/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Material Superphysics Solutions on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/solutions/material/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix Einstein&#39;s General Relativity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/material/how-to-fix-general-relativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/solutions/material/how-to-fix-general-relativity/</guid>
      <description>While collating the works of Socrates in order to unify them with the works of David Hume and harmonize Superphysics, I came upon his maxims on astrophysics that referred to the proper way to judge the movement of heavenly bodies:
The spangled heavens should be used as a pattern and with a view to that higher knowledge. Any geometrician who saw them would appreciate the exquisiteness of their workmanship. But he would never think that there is a true equal, true double, or true proportion in the spangled heavens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Solve Global Warming</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/material/how-to-solve-global-warming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/solutions/material/how-to-solve-global-warming/</guid>
      <description>The lashing of Hurricane Ida, the floods in China, and forest fires in Siberia and Europe has made the impact of global warming obvious to all. Unfortunately, policymakers seem to have no other solution to it other than:
 reducing CO2 emissions through a carbon tax, anti-emission regulations, or green energy building infrastracture as new dams, roads, and bridges that can withstand natural disasters better  However, despite lobbying by various parties and governments, such solutions still are not implemented due to their cost or impracticality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
