<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 1: God on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 1: God on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>APPENDIX</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-1/appendix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-1/appendix/</guid>
      <description>I have explained God&amp;rsquo;s nature and properties, showing that he:
 necessarily exists is one is and acts solely by the necessity of his own nature is the free cause of all things how he is so that all things are in God, and so depend on him that without him they could neither exist nor be conceived  All things are predetermined by God, from his infinite power and not from his free will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Definitions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-1/definitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-1/definitions/</guid>
      <description>Part 1: God Definitions:   Self—caused means something of which the essence involves existence.
  A thing is finite when it can be limited by another thing of the same nature.
  For instance, a body is finite because we always conceive another greater body. A thought is limited by another thought. But a body is not limited by thought, nor a thought limited by a body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 1 to 20</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-1/propositions-1-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-1/propositions-1-21/</guid>
      <description>Propositions 1. Substance is by nature prior to its modifications. 2. Two substances, whose attributes are different, have nothing in common.  For each must exist in itself, and be conceived through itself. In other words, the conception of one does not imply the conception of the other.  3. Things which have nothing in common cannot be one the cause of the other. 4. Two or more distinct things are distinguished one from the other, either:  by the difference of the attributes of the substances, or the difference of their modifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 22 to 29</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-1/propositions-22-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-1/propositions-22-29/</guid>
      <description>22. Whatsoever follows from any attribute of God, in so far as it is modified by a modification, which exists necessarily and as infinite, through the said attribute, must also exist necessarily and as infinite. 23. Every mode, which exists both necessarily and as infinite, must necessarily follow either from the absolute nature of some attribute of God, or from an attribute modified by a modification which exists necessarily, and as infinite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 30-36</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-1/propositions-30-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-1/propositions-30-36/</guid>
      <description>30. Intellect, in function (actu) finite, or in function infinite, must comprehend the attributes of God and the modifications of God, and nothing else. 31. The intellect in function, whether finite or infinite, as will, desire, love, etc., should be referred to passive nature and not to active nature. 32. Will cannot be called a free cause, but only a necessary cause. 33. Things could not have been brought into being by God in any manner or in any order different from that which has in fact obtained.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
