<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Section 1: Direct Sympathy as Gratitude and Resentment on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Section 1: Direct Sympathy as Gratitude and Resentment on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Objects of gratitude appear to deserve reward. Objects of resentment appear to deserve punishment</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-1/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-1/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction 1 Merit and Demerit are another set of qualities ascribed to mankind&amp;rsquo;s actions and conduct, distinct from propriety or decency.
 Merit is the quality deserving reward. Demerit is the quality deserving punishment.  These are the objects of a distinct species of approbation.
2 Feelings have two aspects or relations:
 In relation to the cause which excites it   An action&amp;rsquo;s propriety or decency depends on the suitableness of the feeling, which creates the action, to the cause which excites it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recapitulation of the foregoing chapters</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-1/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-1/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>18 We only thoroughly sympathize with Person A&amp;rsquo;s gratitude to Person B if we totally go along with the motives of Person B. We must go along with Person B&amp;rsquo;s feelings, before we can entirely sympathize with Person A&amp;rsquo;s gratitude.
19 When we sympathize with Person B&amp;rsquo;s feelings, and if it matches Person A&amp;rsquo;s gratitude, then our love for Person B enhances our fellow-feeling with Person A&amp;rsquo;s gratitude. Person B&amp;rsquo;s actions seem then to call aloud for a proportional recompense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sympathy with Gratitude and Resentment</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-1/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-1/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>When there is no approval of the Benefactor&amp;rsquo;s conduct, there is little sympathy with the Beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s gratitude. When there is no disapproval of the Erring Person&amp;rsquo;s motives, there is no sympathy with the Sufferer&amp;rsquo;s resentment 15 A benefactor&amp;rsquo;s action merits little reward if his good motives were misplaced, no matter how beneficial it was. The lack of a proper motive prevents us from having sympathy with his beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s gratitude. In this case, little gratitude is due.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The analysis of the sense of Merit and Demerit</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-1/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-1/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>The Sense of Merit arises from sympathy 22-23 The sense of merit is a compounded feeling made up of two distinct feelings:
 A direct sympathy with the subject-person&amp;rsquo;s feelings An indirect sympathy with its object-person&amp;rsquo;s gratitude  24 Many times, we can plainly distinguish these two feelings uniting in our sense of merit of a character or action. After we read about beneficent actions, we:
 are animated by their high-spirited generosity become keen for their success and grieve at their disappointment imagine that we are the subject-person and bring ourselves to those adventures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Proper objects of Gratitude and Resentment</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-1/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-1/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>10-12 The gratitude and resentment that I mention is the natural gratitude and resentment and not the fake one.
13 We sympathize with the joy of our loved ones when in prosperity. When we see one man assisted, protected, relieved by another, our sympathy with the beneficiary&amp;rsquo;s joy animates our fellow-feeling with his gratitude to his benefactor. We therefore readily sympathize with his gratitude and applaud the returns he makes to his benefactor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
