<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 1-Productivity and the Distribution of Revenue on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 1-Productivity and the Distribution of Revenue on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agreeableness or cost of job</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10a/</guid>
      <description>1 The advantages and disadvantages of the different employments of labour and stock must be perfectly equal or continually tending to equality in the same neighbourhood.
If there was advantageous employment, so many people would crowd into it in the one case, and so many would desert it in the other, that its advantages would soon be at level with other employments. This would happen where:
 there was perfect liberty things were left to follow their natural course everyone was free to choose and change their occupation as they saw fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constancy &amp; Trust</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10b/</guid>
      <description>14 Wages vary with the constancy or inconstancy of employment.
15 &amp;ldquo;Employment is much more constant in some trades than in others.&amp;rdquo;
In most manufactures, a journeyman may be sure of employment almost every day. A mason or bricklayer, on the contrary, cannot work in bad weather. His employment depends on the calls of his customers. He frequently has no work. His earnings must maintain him while he is idle and compensate his anxiety and despondence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grains versus Silver in terms of the temporal aspect of value</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-5b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-5b/</guid>
      <description>15 At distant times, equal amounts of labour will be bought more nearly with equal amounts of wheat, the worker&amp;rsquo;s subsistence, than with perhaps any other commodity.
At distant times, equal amounts of wheat will enable its possessor to buy or command nearly the same amount of the labour of other people. Although equal amounts of wheat will not do it exactly.
The worker&amp;rsquo;s subsistence &amp;amp; enjoyments depend on the advancing, stagnant, or reversing state of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productivity from the Division of Labor</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-1c-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-1c-productivity/</guid>
      <description>10 The division of labour greatly increases productivity. This productivity in a well-governed society creates the universal opulence which extends to the poor.
Every worker produces a lot more goods than what he himself needs. This allows all workers to exchange their excess goods among each other, creating a general plenty that diffuses itself through the different ranks of society.
11 The accommodation of a common day-labourer in a civilized country involves a small part of the industry of so many people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10c/</guid>
      <description>Insurance Risk 31 The chance of loss is frequently under-valued and rarely valued more than it is worth.
 This is proven by the very moderate profit of insurers.  To be successful in insurance, the common premium must: be sufficient to compensate the common losses pay the expence of management afford a profit equal or bigger than other businesses using the same capital. Paying this premium pays the real value of the risk or the lowest price of insurance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Division of Labour</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-1-division/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-1-division/</guid>
      <description>1 Division of labour causes improvements in:
 productivity, and  The greatest improvement is in this.   the skill, dexterity, and judgment in work.  2 The effects of division of labour is carried furthest in very trifling manufactures. These manufactures:
 supply the small wants of a few people have a few workers who can often be:  collected into the same workhouse, and placed under the spectator&amp;rsquo;s view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Real and Nominal Price of Commodities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-5a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-5a/</guid>
      <description>Translator&amp;rsquo;s note: I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed the core of the misunderstanding of Smith&amp;rsquo;s Labour Theory of Value is the ambiguity of the word &amp;lsquo;labour&amp;rsquo;, so I replace it with &amp;lsquo;toil and trouble&amp;rsquo; to equate it more to psychology, emotions, and subjectiveness, instead of physical force or objectiveness. Toil and trouble is more related to suffering and non-suffering. A link to the original translation with the word &amp;lsquo;labour&amp;rsquo; will be posted in the bottom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Causes the Increase in Productivity?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-1b-causes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-1b-causes/</guid>
      <description>5 This great increase in productivity from the division of labour is due to three circumstances:
 The increase of dexterity in every worker The time savings commonly lost in passing from one species of work to another The invention of many machines which:   facilitate and abridge labour, and enable one man to do the work of many.  Increase in Skill 6 1. The improvement of the worker&amp;rsquo;s dexterity increases the amount of the work he can do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
