<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Section 2: Cheapness and Plenty on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Section 2: Cheapness and Plenty on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>All the Arts are subservient to the Natural Wants of Mankind</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Those qualities, which are the ground of preference, and which give occasion to pleasure and pain, are the cause of many insignificant demands, which we by no means stand in need of.
The industry of human life is not employed in procuring food, clothes and lodging. It is employed in procuring those conveniences according to the nicety and delicacy of our taste. To improve and multiply the materials, which are the principal objects of our necessities, creates all the variety of the arts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange (Forex and Trade Financing)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>Exchange is a method invented by merchants to facilitate the payment of money at a distance.
Suppose I am in Glasgow and owe £100 to Merchant A in London. I apply to a banker in Glasgow for a bill upon another Merchant B in London, payable to Merchant A. For this, I must give the banker £100 and reward him for his trouble. This reward is called the value or premium of exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Division of Labour multiplies Productivity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>We shall next show how this division of labour multiplies productivity, or, which is the same thing, how opulence arises from it.
Let us observe the effect of the division of labour in some manufactures. If all the parts of a pin were made by one man, it would take him a whole year to make one pin.
He would:
 dig the ore, smelt it, and split the wire.  Therefore, this pin must be sold at the expense of his maintenance for that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interest</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>It is commonly supposed that the premium of interest depends on the value of gold and silver. The value of these are regulated by their quantity. As the quantity increases, the value diminishes. As the quantity decreases, the value rises.
However, the premium of interest is regulated by the quantity of stock.
Around the time of the discovery of the West Indies, the common interest was at 10% or 12%. Since that time, it has gradually diminished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money as the Measure of Value and Medium of Exchange</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>Measures of value and measures of quantity
We now consider money as:
 The measure of value, and then The medium of exchange.  When people deal in many kinds of goods, one of them must be considered as the measure of value. Suppose there were only three commodities, sheep, corn, and oxen.
We can easily remember them comparatively. But if we have 100 different commodities, there are 99 values of each, arising from a comparison with each of the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Law&#39;s Scheme</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>The last bad effect of the idea that public opulence consists in money is the notion of Mr. Law, a Scotch merchant.
He thought that:
 the value of gold and silver is arbitrary and depends on constitution and agreement. the idea of value can be brought to paper and preferred to money.  If this could be done, he thought it would be a great convenience. The government could then do what it pleased:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Opulence Does Not Consist In Money</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>But labour, not money, is the true measure of value. Therefore, national opulence consists in:
 the quantity of goods and the facility of barter  The more money that is needed to circulate the goods of any country, the fewer the goods.
Suppose Scotland&amp;rsquo;s total stock of corn, cattle, money, etc. amounts to 20 million.
 If 1 million in cash is needed to circulate it, there will only be 19 million of food, clothes, and lodging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Balance of Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>The idea of public opulence consisting in money has led to the most pernicious regulations. These think:
 that the commerce which drain us of our money are disadvantageous and so such commerce is prohibited and that the commerce which increase money are beneficial and is encouraged  France is thought to produce more of the elegancies of life than England. We take much from them and they need little from us and so the balance of trade is against us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ban on coin exportation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Because of these tenets, the government banned coin exportation.
This ban has been extremely hurtful to the country&amp;rsquo;s commerce. Because whatever amount of money there is in any country above what is needed for circulation is merely a dead stock.
In King William’s time, there were two species of coin:
 milled unmilled  The unmilled was frequently clipped while in circulation. This caused frequent disorders among the people. The parliament ordered all the clipped money to be brought into the mint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Causes of the slow Progress of Opulence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>It is surprising for nations to continue to be poor for so long when we consider the immediate effects of the division of labour in improving the arts.
This is caused by natural impediments and the oppression by the government.
Lack of Division of Labor or Teamwork A barbarous people are ignorant of the effects of the division of labour. It takes a long time before a person can produce more than is necessary for his daily subsistence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Division Of Labour Must Be Proportional To The Extent Of Commerce</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>The division of labour must always be proportioned to the extent of commerce.
If 10 people only want a certain commodity, its manufacture will never be as divided as one that had 1,000 wanting it. The division of labour always becomes more perfect by the easy method of transportation in a country. The progress of commerce must be stopped if the road:
 is infested with robbers, and is deep and transportation is not easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Natural Wants of Mankind</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Cheapness or plenty is the most proper way of procuring wealth and abundance.
Cheapness is the same thing with plenty. Water is so cheap because it is so plentiful. Diamonds are so dear because of their scarcity (Their real use seems not yet discovered).
To ascertain the most proper method of obtaining these conveniences, we should:
 consider what are the natural wants of mankind which are to be supplied, show wherein opulence consists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Opinion that no Expense at Home can be hurtful</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>The absurd notion that national opulence consists in money has another bad effect &amp;ndash; it makes people think that whatever people spend locally cannot reduce public opulence.
Dr. Mandeville created a system that private vices are public benefits. It believes that what we spend at home is all spent among ourselves and that none of it goes out of the country.
But if everyone wears, tears, and spends his stock, without doing any industry, then the nation is made so much the poorer at the end of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Opulence from the Division of Labour</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Translators Note: The beginnings of the Wealth of Nations is from this Chapter to Part 4. We can conclude that the rest is to form his work on Jurisprudence
 In an uncivilized nation where labour is undivided, everything is provided for by the natural needs of mankind.
Yet, when the nation is cultivated and labour divided, a more liberal provision is allotted them. This is how a common day-labourer in Britain has more luxury than an Indian sovereign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Causes the Division of Labour</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>The division of labour cannot be the effect of human prudence. The Sesostris made a law that every man should follow the employment of his father. But this :
 is not suitable to the dispositions of human nature and can never long take place.  Everyone is fond of being a gentleman, whatever his father&amp;rsquo;s employment. The strongest and those above the weak in society must have as many under as to defend their station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What regulates the Price of Commodities?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-2/section-2/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Every commodity has two different prices which are apparently independent, but connected:
 The natural price The market price  These are regulated by certain circumstances.
The Natural Price People must make as much by their employment to maintain them while they are employed. An arrow-maker must be sure to exchange as much surplus product to maintain him for the time he took to make the arrows.
But there is a big difference in the different trades.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
