<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Money on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Money on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Measure Of Values</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-1/</guid>
      <description>The first chief function of money is to express the comparative value of commodities as the universal measure of value.
Money becomes the measure of commodities because all commodities are products of human labour. Money therefore is the measure of labour time.The expression of the value of a commodity in gold — x commodity A = y money-commodity — is its money-form or price.
1 ton of iron = 2 ounces of gold expresses the value of iron to society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-2/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 2 THE MEDIUM OF CIRCULATION
A. The Metamorphosis of Commodities
We saw in a former chapter that the exchange of commodities implies contradictory and mutually exclusive conditions. The differentiation of commodities into commodities and money does not sweep away these inconsistencies, but develops a modus vivendi, a form in which they can exist side by side. This is generally the way in which real contradictions are reconciled. For instance, it is a contradiction to depict one body as constantly falling towards another, and as, at the same time, constantly flying away from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Functions of Money</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-3/</guid>
      <description>Money is the measure of value and the medium of circulation. Gold (or silver) is therefore money.
A. Hoarding Buying and selling leads to the continuous circulation of money.
But as soon as buying and selling stops, money stops circulating.
At one time, money must be attracted in order to act as circulating coin.
At another, circulating coin must be repelled in order to act again as more or less stagnant money.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
