<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Influence of Society on Morality as Culture on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Influence of Society on Morality as Culture on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Friendship and Kindness</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-2/chapter-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-2/chapter-1b/</guid>
      <description>18 Among well-disposed people, the necessity or convenience of mutual accommodation frequently produces a friendship like the friendship of those born to live in the same family.
Colleagues in office, partners in trade, call one another brothers. They frequently feel as brothers towards each other.
 Their good agreement is an advantage to all. Their disagreement is a sort of a small scandal.  The Romans expressed this sort of attachment by the word necessitudo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Order How Individuals are Recommended by Nature to our care</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-2/chapter-1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-2/chapter-1a/</guid>
      <description>Introduction 4 The Stoics said that every man is first and principally recommended to his own care. Every man:
 is fitter and abler to take care of himself than of any other person, and feels his own pleasures and pains more sensibly than those of others.  His own sensations are his original sensations. These are the substance.
The sensations of others are the reflected or sympathetic images of those sensations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Order of How Societies are recommended to our Beneficence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-2/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-2/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>26 The principles that direct the order of how individuals are recommended to our beneficence, also direct the order of how societies are recommended to our beneficence. The most important societies are the first and principal ones recommended to our beneficence.
27 Ordinarily, our conduct influences the mood of the society in which we live and have been born and educated. Our society is accordingly, most strongly recommended to us by nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Benevolence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-2/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-2/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>44 Our effective good offices can very seldom be extended beyond our own country. But our goodwill has no boundary. It may embrace the immensity of the universe. We cannot conceive of any innocent and sensible being:
 whose happiness we should not desire, or whose misery we should not be averse to, when distinctly brought home to the imagination.  The idea of a mischievous, though sensible, being, naturally provokes our hatred.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
