<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Laws Related to Defense on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-9/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Laws Related to Defense on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-9/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Republics provide for their Safety</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-9/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-9/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>A small republic is destroyed by a foreign force.
A large one is ruined by an internal imperfection.
Democracies and aristocracies are equally liable to these.
This is why mankind has been obliged to live constantly under the government of a single person until they developed a confederate republic. Such a constitution has:
 all the internal advantages of a republican government the external force of a monarchical government  A confederate republic is a convention by which petty states agree to become members of a larger one, which they intend to establish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Republics provide for their Safety</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-9/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-9/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 4: How Despotic Governments provide for their Security Republics provide for their security by uniting.
Despotic governments do it by separating, and by keeping themselves single. They sacrifice a part of the country; and, by rav aging and desolating the frontiers, they render the heart of the empire inaccessible. This practice is more tolerable in large than in middling states.
A despotic government does all the mischief to itself that could be committed by a strong, cruel enemy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
