<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Classical Economics Unified With Modern Data Science on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/pantrynomics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Classical Economics Unified With Modern Data Science on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/pantrynomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Market Equilibrium Fallacy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/pantrynomics/market-equilibrium-fallacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/pantrynomics/market-equilibrium-fallacy/</guid>
      <description>The biggest fallacy of Economics is Market Equilibrium which is taught in basic economics or &amp;lsquo;Econ101&amp;rsquo; everywhere as the supply and demand curve forming an &amp;lsquo;X&amp;rsquo; and meeting in a state called &amp;lsquo;exact equilibrium&amp;rsquo;. Smith exposed this as mercantile sophistry in the 18th century, then called the &amp;lsquo;balance of trade&amp;rsquo;. To prove that this idea of &amp;lsquo;balance&amp;rsquo; is the same in essence with the &amp;lsquo;equilibrium&amp;rsquo; of economics, let&amp;rsquo;s compare the philosophy behind both ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Invisible Hand of the Tao</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/pantrynomics/invisible-hand-of-tao/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/pantrynomics/invisible-hand-of-tao/</guid>
      <description>The invisible hand concept by Adam Smith is one of the most important ideas in our proposed economic science, making up the Second Law of Value which then leads to the effort theory of value which replaces the arbitrary marginal pricing of Neoclassical Economics.
As it is so fundamental, it has to be thoroughly explained. Unfortunately, the invisible hand concept has been corrupted so much by Paul Samuelson in order to advance his own corrupt neoclassical synthesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Four Laws of Value and Four Kinds of Prices</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/pantrynomics/four-laws-of-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/pantrynomics/four-laws-of-value/</guid>
      <description>I shall endeavour to explain [exchangable value] as fully and distinctly as I can for which I must very earnestly entreat reader&#39;s patience and attention: his patience in order to examine something which might appear unnecessarily tedious; his attention to understand what may, perhaps, after the fullest explication which I am capable of giving of it, appear still obscure. I am always willing to run some hazard of being tedious in order to be sure that I am perspicuous; and after taking the utmost pains that I can to be perspicuous, some obscurity may still appear to remain upon a subject in its own nature extremely abstracted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Universal Revenue</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/pantrynomics/basic-universal-revenue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/pantrynomics/basic-universal-revenue/</guid>
      <description>Pantrynomics introduces the concept of resourcization or the use of resource credits which are social contracts that give right to assets or resources (products and services) in lieu of money.
The credits allow the unsold productivity of a slowing-down economy to be stored to avoid a crash, just as monetization does the opposite and speeds up an economy by converting productivity into money via sales.
Resource credits are implemented generally through Basic Universal Revenue that will give nonmonetary rewards (as food) to productive people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternatives to Money as Store of Value</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/pantrynomics/alternatives-to-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/pantrynomics/alternatives-to-money/</guid>
      <description>Both Economics and Mercantilism use money as their store of value and tool of trade. Mercantilism was also called the Commercial system and now takes the form of E-commerce.
To buy anything online, you need a credit card or any electronic system to transfer cash payments. Prior to commercialization, the universal method was barter. For example, the Mongols and the Inca were able to sustain their empires by bartering goods and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISAIAH: Impartial Spectator Automated Intelligence Aggregation Host</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/pantrynomics/isaiah/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/pantrynomics/isaiah/</guid>
      <description>Pantrynomics solves all economic problems by adding barter and points-based valuation to the current money-based valuation. The points-based valuation represents the effort theory of value which we derived from Adam Smith:
Labour..is the only universal, as well as the only accurate measure of value.. by which we can compare the values of different commodities at all times and at all places.. From century to century, corn is a better measure than silver, because, from century to century, equal quantities of corn will command the same quantity of labour more nearly than equal quantities of silver.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
