<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 5: The Influence of Society on Morality as Culture on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 5: The Influence of Society on Morality as Culture on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Differences</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-2b/</guid>
      <description>17 In the same way, the different situations of ages and countries give different:
 characters to their citizens, and sentiments about the praiseworthiness of those characters, according what is usual.  The politeness highly esteemed, and perhaps thought as effeminate adulation in Russia, would be seen as rudeness and barbarism at the French court.
A Polish nobleman might consider a certain frugality as excessive parsimony. But it might be regarded as extravagance by a citizen of Amsterdam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom and Fashion in the Arts</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-1b/</guid>
      <description>6 According to the ancient rhetoricians, a certain measure of verse was appropriated by nature to each species of writing. Each measure was naturally expressive of the writing&amp;rsquo;s character or feeling. They said that one verse was fit for grave, and another for gay works. These could not be interchanged without the greatest impropriety. However, modern writing contradicts this principle even though modern writing appears extremely proper. The burlesque verse in English is the heroic verse in French.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Influence of Custom on Morals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-2a/</guid>
      <description>11 Our feelings on beauty are so much influenced by custom and fashion, that the beauty of conduct is also influenced. However, this influence seems much less than it is everywhere else.
 Custom and fashion can make any physical thing agreeable, no matter how absurd. But custom and fashion can never make a character like Nero or Claudius agreeable  Nero will always be dreaded and hated. Claudius will always be scorned and derided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Influence of customs on beauty</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-1a/</guid>
      <description>1 The custom and fashion also have a big influence on our moral sentiments. They are the chief causes of many irregular moral opinions in different ages and nations. They dominate even our judgments concerning beauty.
2 When two objects have frequently been seen together, the imagination acquires a habit of passing easily from the one to the other. If the first appears, we assume that the second will follow. They naturally put us in mind of one another and our attention glides easily along them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
