<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Social Superphysics on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/social/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Social Superphysics on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/articles/social/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Social Status and Social Climbers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/social/social-status-climbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/social/social-status-climbers/</guid>
      <description>The phenomenon of social status and social climbers are sourced from vanity or an ego that is too strong.
&#34;The vain man sees the respect which is paid to rank and fortune, and wishes to usurp this respect, as well as that for talents and virtues. His dress, his equipage, his way of living, accordingly, all announce both a higher rank and a greater fortune than really belong to him; and in order to support this foolish imposition for a few years in the beginning of his life, he often reduces himself to poverty and distress long before the end of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Morality?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/social/what-is-morality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/social/what-is-morality/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, we explained that everything in existence has a dharma which represents the design or plan made by its inventor or creator. A smartphone is designed to withstand being dropped a few feet, but not many meters. A basketball, on the other hand, is designed to withstand being dropped from long distances. We can say that the dharma of a smartphone in this sense is different from that of a basketball.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Impartial Spectator?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/social/what-is-the-impartial-spectator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/social/what-is-the-impartial-spectator/</guid>
      <description>Aside from the division of labor, Adam Smith is famous for his concept of the impartial spectator. This spectator is the thing that guides us to do the right thing and avoid doing wrong. Many people would equate it to conscience, even if Smith mentioned that it is not so:
These must be left to the decision of the man within the breast, the supposed impartial spectator, the great judge and arbiter of our conduct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smith = Hume = Socrates</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/social/hume-smith-socrates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/social/hume-smith-socrates/</guid>
      <description>People&amp;rsquo;s confusion regarding Smith&amp;rsquo;s works, such as his stand on capitalism, arises because he did not define nor explain self-interest, private ownership, and why a person should have the profits of one&amp;rsquo;s own work.
It is but equity that those who feed, clothe and lodge the the people, should have such a share* of the produce of their own labour  Capitalism violates the concept of profit-sharing by giving all the profits* to the investor or owner.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
