<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Consequences Of The Principles Of Different Governments on The Simplicity Of Civil And Criminal Laws on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Consequences Of The Principles Of Different Governments on The Simplicity Of Civil And Criminal Laws on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In what Governments the Sovereign may be Judge</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>MACHIAVEL says that Florence lost its liberty because its people did not judge cases of high-treason as a body, as was customary at Rome. Instead, they had eight judges.
Machiavel says that the few are corrupted by a few.
I agree to his maxim.
When a few people decide, the political interest prevails over the civil because it is always inconvenient for the people to be judges in their own cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insufficiency of the Japanese Laws</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>EXCESSIVE punishments may even corrupt a despotic government as seen in Japan.
There, almost all crimes are punished with death because disobedience to the great Japanese emperor is reckoned an enormous crime. The question is not so much to correct the delinquent, as to vindicate the emperor&amp;rsquo;s authority.
These notions:
 are derived from servitude come mainly from the emperor being the universal proprietor.  These render almost all crimes to be directly against his interests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Consequences of the Principles of the three Governments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 9: The Severity of Punishments in different Governments. THE severity of punishments is fitter for despotic governments, whose principle is terror, than for a monarchy or a republic, whose spring is honour and virtue.
In moderate governments, the love of one’s country, shame, and the fear of blame, are restraining motives, capable of preventing a multitude of crimes. Here the greatest punishment of a bad action is conviction. The civil laws have, therefore, a softer way of correcting, and do not require so much force and severity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The just Proportion betwixt Punishments and Crimes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>IT is an essential point, that there should be a certain proportion in punishments, because it is essential that a great crime should be avoided rather than a smaller, and that which is more pernicious to society rather than that which is less.
“An impostor, who called himself Constantine Ducas, raised a great insurrection at Constantinople. He was taken and condemned to be whipt; but, upon informing against several persons of distinction, he was sentenced to be burnt as a calumniator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Simplicity of civil Laws in different Governments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>MONARCHIES have more complex laws than despotic governments because monarchies need courts of judicature which decide on cases.
The decisions must be preserved and learnt so that:
 we may judge in the same manner to-day as yesterday the lives and property of the citizens may be as certain and fixed  In monarchies, the administration of justice decides:
 whatever belongs to life and property and honour  This creates the demand for very scrupulous enquiries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Simplicity of civil Laws in different Governments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 21: The Clemency of the Prince CLEMENCY is the characteristic of monarchs. In republics, whose principle is virtue, it is not so necessary.
In despotic governments, where fear predominates, it is less customary, because the great men are to be restrained by examples of severity. It is more necessary in monarchies, where they are governed by honour, which frequently requires what the very law forbids. Disgrace is here equivalent to chastisement; and even the forms of justice are punishments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spirit of the Roman Senate</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-6/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>UNDER the consulate of Acilius Glabrio and Piso, the Acilian law was made to prevent the intriguing for places.
Dio says that the senate engaged the consuls to propose it, by reason that C. Cornelius, the tribune, had resolved to cause more severe punishments to be established against this crime; to which the people seemed greatly inclined.
The senate rightly judged, that immoderate punishments would strike indeed a terror into people’s minds, but must have also this effect, that there would be nobody afterwards to accuse or condemn; whereas, by proposing moderate penalties, there would be always judges and accusers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
