<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 7: Moral Systems on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 7: Moral Systems on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Different Accounts On the Nature of Virtue</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1a/</guid>
      <description>1 Virtue is the temper of mind in the excellent and praise-worthy character. The nature of virtue may be reduced to three classes:
 The proper direction of all our feelings. These feelings may be virtuous or vicious according to:   their objects and how much they pursue them.  Virtue therefore consists in propriety.
2
Virtue is in the judicious pursuit of our own private interest and happiness through our selfish feelings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stoicism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1b/</guid>
      <description>19 Zeno was the founder of the Stoicism. According to him, every animal was by nature:
 recommended to its own care, and endowed with self-love  It causes every animal to preserve its existence as best as it can.
20 The self-love of man embraced his entire mind and body and desired their preservation. Whatever supported this state was naturally chosen. Whatever destroyed it, was rejected. These make us prefer health, strength, agility, and ease of body, and the eternal conveniences which promoted these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suicide</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1c/</guid>
      <description>Suicide is rooted on pride 35 Suicide was never very common among the Greeks. I cannot remember any illustrious Greek hero who died by his own hand, other than Cleomenes.
Aristomenes&#39; death is as much beyond the period of true history as that of Ajax. The common story of Themistocles&#39; death was within that period.
However, it bears all the marks of a most romantic fable.
Of all the Greek heroes written by Plutarch, Cleomenes is the only one who died by suicide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaches of Moral Rules</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-4/</guid>
      <description>19 Therefore, there were three kinds of breaches of moral duty which came before the confessor&amp;rsquo;s tribunal, and fell under the casuists&#39; awareness.
20
  Breaches of the rules of justice   These rules are all express and positive. Their violation is naturally attended with:
 the consciousness of deserving punishment and the dread of suffering punishment from God and man.  21
 Breaches of the rules of chastity   In all grosser instances, these are real breaches of the rules of justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Licentious Systems</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>93 All these systems suppose that there is an essential distinction between vice and virtue. There is a real and essential difference between:
 the propriety and impropriety of any feeling, benevolence and any other principle of action, and real prudence and shortsighted folly or precipitate rashness.  All of them mainly contribute to:
 encourage the praise-worthy disposition, and discourage the blamable disposition.  94 It might be true that some of them:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-love</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-3/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-3/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
1 After the inquiry on the nature of virtue, the next important question in Moral Philosophy is about the principle of approbation. The principle of approbation is the power of the mind which renders certain characters agreeable or disagreeable to us. It makes us:
 prefer one tenour of conduct to another, denominate the one right and the other wrong, consider the one kind of conduct as the object of approbation, honour, and reward, and consider the other kind of conduct as the object of blame, censure, and punishment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of Stoicism and other Propriety-based Moral Philosophies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1d/</guid>
      <description>46 The Stoics believed that those who had not attained perfect virtue might have some proficiency in virtue. They organized those proficiencies into different classes, according to their level of advancement. They called the imperfect virtues not as rectitudes, but as proprieties, fitnesses, decent and becoming actions.
 Cicero called these officia. Seneca more exactly called them convenientia  Cicero&amp;rsquo;s Offices wrote about the doctrine of those imperfect, but attainable virtues as &amp;lsquo;the practical morality of the Stoics&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems Based on Feelings</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-3/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-3/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>17 Moral systems based on feelings can be divided into two classes.
18
  According to some, the principle of approbation is founded on a particular faculty of perception.   This is exerted by the mind at the view of actions or affections.
 Some actions affect this faculty agreeably and are stamped as right, laudable, and virtuous. Some actions affect it disagreeably and are stamped as wrong, blamable, and vicious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems Which Make Reason the Principle of Approbation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-3/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-3/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Hobbes&#39; Doctrine 8 Mr. Hobbes&#39; doctrine is that:
 a state of nature is a state of war before civil government was created, there could be no peaceful society  According to him, therefore:
 to preserve society was to support civil government to destroy civil government was to end society  But the existence of civil government depends on the obedience paid to the supreme magistrate. The moment he loses his authority, all government is ended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems which make Virtue consist in Benevolence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>72 The system which makes virtue consist in benevolence is very ancient, but not as ancient as those of the Greeks. It was the doctrine of most of the Eclectics, after the age of Augustus. They pretended to follow the opinions of Plato and Pythagoras. Thus, they are commonly known as Platonists.
73 According to them in the divine nature, benevolence or love was the sole principle of action which directed all the other attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems which make Virtue consist in Prudence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>55 Epicurus&#39; system is the most ancient one that renders virtue as prudence. His enemies allege him to have borrowed his philosophy&amp;rsquo;s leading principles from his predecessors, particularly from Aristippus. Despite this, it is very probable that at least his way of applying those principles was original.
56 According to him, bodily pleasure and pain were the sole ultimate objects of natural desire and aversion. These required no proof. Pleasure might sometimes be avoided because it might cause us to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Questions in a Theory of Moral Sentiments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-1/</guid>
      <description>1 Almost all of the remarkable theories on the nature of our moral feelings are partly correct and partly wrong due to their imperfect view of nature.
2 There are two questions regarding moral principles:
 What is their definition of virtue? What is the conduct that makes up the praise-worthy character?   This character is the natural object of esteem, honour, and approbation. By what faculty in the mind recommends this character to us?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
