<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Economist by Xenophon on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/the-economist/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Economist by Xenophon on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/the-economist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>There are two sorts of people:  Those who spend large sums on money in building useless houses Those who spend far less but furnish it with all they need.  Here is one of the essentials of economy.
Mirroring them are two other sets of persons: The first possessors of furniture of various kinds, which they cannot, however, lay their hands on when the need arises.
They hardly know if they have got all safe and sound or not: whereby they put themselves and their domestics to much mental torture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Wealth?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Wealth is anything that is Useful and Beneficial Socrates: &#34;Economy&#34; is the name of a particular kind of knowledge or science, just like the words &#34;medicine,&#34; &#34;carpentry,&#34; &#34;building,&#34; &#34;smithying,&#34; &#34;metal-working,&#34; etc. In the case of the arts just named, we can state the proper work or function of each, can we (similarly) state the proper work and function of economy?
 Critobulus: A good economist at any rate must be able to manage his own house or estate well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
