<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Origin of the French Civil Laws on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Origin of the French Civil Laws on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A new Reason of the Disuse of the Salic and Roman Laws, as also of the Capitularies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>The principal cause for the disuse of the Salic and Roman laws, and the Capitularies was the great extent given to judiciary combats.
The Salic laws did not admit of this custom and so they became useless and fell into oblivion. The Roman laws also rejected this custom. Their whole attention was then taken up in establishing the law of judicial combats, and in forming a proper digest of the several cases that might happen on those occasions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 17: Particular Notions of our Ancestors</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>IT is astonishing that our ancestors should:
 rest the honour, fortune, and life of the subject, on things that depended less on reason than on hazard, and incessantly make use of proofs incapable of convicting, and that had no manner of connexion either with innocence or guilt.  The Germans were never subdued and so enjoyed excessive independence. Different families waged war with each other, to obtain satisfaction for murders, robberies, or affronts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 18: In what Manner the Custom of judicial Combats gained Ground</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>We can infer from Agobard’s letter to Lewis the Debonnaire that the custom of judicial combats was not established among the Franks. After having represented to that prince the abuses of the law of Gundebald, he desires* that private disputes should be decided in Burgundy by the law of the Franks.
But the trial by combat at that time in France has been the cause of some perplexity. The law of the Salian Franks did not allow of this kind of trial but the Ripuarian Franks did.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 23: The Code of Laws on judicial Combats</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>SOME perhaps will have a curiosity to see this abominable custom of judiciary combat reduced to principle, and to find a code of such extraordinary laws.
Men, though reasonable in the main, reduce their very prejudices to rule. Nothing was more contrary to good sense, than those combats: Yet when once this point was laid down, a kind of prudential management was used in carrying it into execution.
In order to be thoroughly acquainted with the jurisprudence of those times, it is necessary to read with attention the regulations of St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 25: The Bounds prescribed to the Custom of judicial Combats</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-25/</guid>
      <description>WHEN pledges of battle had been received upon a civil affair of small importance, the lord obliged the parties to withdraw them.
If a fact was notorious;* for instance, if a man had been assassinated in the open market-place, then there was neither a trial by witnesses, nor by combat; the judge gave his decision from the notoriety of the fact.
When the court of a lord had often determined after the same manner, and the usage was thus known,† the lord refused to grant the parties the privilege of duelling, to the end that the usages might not be altered by the different success of the combats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 40: How the Judiciary Forms were borrowed from the Decretals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-40/</guid>
      <description>But how comes it, some will say, that when the institutions were laid aside,
The judicial forms of the canon law were preferred to those of the Roman law because they had constantly before them the ecclesiastic courts, which followed the forms of the canon law.
They knew of no court that followed those of the Roman law. Besides, the limits of the spiritual and temporal jurisdiction were then very little understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 41: Flux and Reflux of the ecclesiastic and temporal Jurisdiction</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-41/</guid>
      <description>THE civil power was in the hands of an infinite number of lords. This made it easy for the ecclesiastic jurisdiction to gain daily a greater extent.
But as the ecclesiastic courts weakened those of the lords, and contributed thereby to give strength to the royal jurisdiction, the latter gradually checked the jurisdiction of the clergy.
The parliament, which in its form of proceedings had adopted whatever was good and useful in the spiritual courts, soon perceived nothing else but the abuses which had crept into those tribunals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 44: The Proof by Witnesses</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-44/</guid>
      <description>THE judges, who had no other rule to go by than the usages, inquired very often by witnesses into every cause that was brought before them.
The usage of judicial combats beginning to decline, they made their inquests in writing.
But a verbal proof committed to writing, is never more than a verbal proof; so that this only increased the expences of law proceedings. Regulations were then made which rendered most of those inquests useless; public registers were established, which ascertained most facts, as nobility, age, legitimacy and marriage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 45: The Customs of France</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-45/</guid>
      <description>FRANCE was governed by written customs. The particular usages of each lordship constituted the civil law.
Every lordship had its civil law, according to Beaumanoir, and so particular a law, that this author who is looked upon as a luminary, and a very great luminary, of those times, says, he does not believe that throughout the whole kingdom there were two lordships intirely governed by the same law.
This prodigious diversity had a two-fold origin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4: How the Roman Law was lost among the Franks but preserved among the Goths and Burgundians</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>France was under the Franks governed by:
 the Roman law the Theodosian code the different laws of the Barbarians, who settled in those parts.  Under the Franks, the Salic law was established for the Franks, and the Theodosian code for the Romans.
In that subject to the Visigoths, a compilation of the Theodosian code, made by order of Alaric, regulated disputes among the Romans;
the national customs which Euric caused to be reduced into writing, determined those among the Visigoths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences between the Salian Franks, the Ripuarian Franks, and other barbarous Nations.</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>The Salic law did not allow negative proofs. The laws of almost all nations allow the accused to deny the accuser. But the Salic law did not.
The law of the Ripuarian Franks was quite different as it allowed negative proofs. The accused could clear himself by swearing among witnesses that he had not committed the crime. The number of witnesses increased in proportion to the importance of the affair. Sometimes it amounted to 72.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epoch of the Reign of St. Lewis</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-29/</guid>
      <description>ST. LEWIS abolished the judicial combats in all the courts of his demesne. But he did not suppress them in the courts of his barons, except in the case of appeal of false judgment.
A vassal could not appeal the court of his lord of false judgment, without demanding a judicial combat against the judges who had pronounced sentence.
But St. Lewis introduced the practice of appealing of false judgment without fighting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Codes of Barbarian Laws, and the Capitularies were lost</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>THE Salic, the Ripuarian, Burgundian, and Visigoth laws, gradually became disused among the French.
Fiefs became hereditary and arriere-fiefs extended. Many usages were introduced which made these laws obsolete. Disputes were still regulated by fines. But the value of money changed and so the fines were also changed.
France was divided into petty lordships, which acknowledged feudal dependence which made it very difficult for only one law to be authorised. Officers could no longer be sent into the provinces to inspect the administration of justice and political affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Institutions of St. Lewis fell into Oblivion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-37/</guid>
      <description>The origin, progress, and decline of institutions happened within a very short period.
The code called St. Lewis’s institutions, was never designed as a law for the whole kingdom, though such a design is mentioned in the preface. It is a general code which determines:
 civil affairs, the disposal of property by will or otherwise, the dowries and advantages of women, and emoluments and privileges of fiefs, with the affairs relative to the police, &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Proceedings at Law became secret and incur costs</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-34/</guid>
      <description>DUELS had introduced a public form of proceeding. Beaumanoir says:
The witnesses should give their testimony in open court.  Boutillier’s commentator says that he had learned of ancient practitioners and from some old manuscript law books that criminal processes were anciently done in public similar to the public judgments of the Romans.
This was because they did not know how to write. Writing fixes the ideas, and preserves the secret.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Roman Law kept its Ground in the Demesne of the Lombards</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>The law of the Lombards was impartial. The Romans were under no temptation to quit their own for it.
The motive which prevailed with the Romans under the Franks to make choice of the Salic law, did not take place in Italy; hence the Roman law maintained itself there, together with that of the Lombards.
It even fell out, that the latter gave way to the Roman institutes, and ceased to be the law of the ruling nation; and though it continued to be that of the principal nobility, yet the greatest part of the cities formed themselves into republics, and the nobility mouldered away of themselves, or were destroyed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judicial Combats and Appeal of false Judgment</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-27/</guid>
      <description>Judicial combats ended the affair forever. It was incompatible with a new judgment, and new prosecutions. This made appeals unknown in France. Appeals were established by the Roman and Canon laws to a superior court, in order to re-judge the proceedings of an inferior court.
Appeals were strange to a warlike nation entirely governed by honour. An appeal among the Franks was a challenge to fight with arms, a challenge decided by blood, and not by an invitation to a paper quarrel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observations on Appeals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-30/</guid>
      <description>Appeals were challenges to a combat. They must have been made immediately on the spot.
Beaumanoir says:
“If the party leaves the court without appealing he loses his appeal, and the judgment stands good.” This continued still in force, even after all the restrictions of judicial combat.  THE villain could not bring an appeal of false judgment against the court of his lord. This we learn from Défontaines, and is confirmed moreover by the institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origin of the Point of Honour</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>WE meet with inexplicable enigmas in the codes of the laws of the Barbarians.
The law of the Frisians allows only half a sou in composition to a person that had been beaten with a stick; Yet for ever so small a wound it allows more. By the Salic law, if a freeman gave three blows with a stick to another freeman, he paid three sous; if he drew blood, he was punished as if he had wounded him with steel, and he paid fifteen sous: thus the punishment was proportioned to the greatness of the wound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Causes of the Disuse of the Barbarian Laws, Roman Law, and Capitularies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>WHEN the German nations subdued the Roman empire, they learned to write so they imitated the Romans and wrote down their own usages and digested them into codes.
The reign of Charlemagne was followed by:
 unhappy reigns the Norman invasions, and the civil wars.  These plunged the conquering nations again into the darkness and caused reading and writing to be neglected. These led to the written laws of the Barbarians, the Roman law, and the capitularies to fall into oblivion in France and Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rules established in the judicial Combat</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>WHEN there happened to be several accusers, they were obliged to agree among themselves that the action might be carried on by a single prosecutor;
If they could not agree, the person before whom the action was brought, appointed one of them to prosecute the quarrel.  When a gentleman challenged a villain, he was obliged to present himself on foot with buckler and baston;
But if he came on horseback, and armed like a gentleman, they took his horse and his arms from him; and stripping him to his shirt, they compelled him to fight in that condition with the villain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Appeal of Default of Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-28/</guid>
      <description>THE appeal of default of justice was when the court of a particular lord deferred, evaded, or refused to do justice to the parties.
During the time of our princes of the second race, though the count had several offices under him, their person was subordinate, but not their jurisdiction. These officers in their court-days, assizes, or placita, gave judgment in the last resort as the count himself; all the difference consisted in the division of the jurisdiction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Different Character of the Laws of the German People</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>AFTER the Franks left their own country, they compiled the Salic laws with the help of their own sages. The Ripuarian Franks under Clovis joined the Salians and preserved its own customs. Theodoric, king of Austrasia, ordered them to be written. He also collected the customs of those Bavarians and Germans who were dependent on his kingdom.
Germany was weakened by the migration of so many people. The Franks conquered all before them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The judiciary Combat between one of the Parties, and one of the Witnesses</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-26/</guid>
      <description>BEAUMANOIR informs us that a person who saw a witness going to swear against him, might elude the second, by telling the judges, that his adversaries produced a false and slandering witness;
If the witness was willing to maintain the quarrel, he gave pledges of battle. They troubled themselves no farther about the inquest; for if the witness was overcome, it was decided, that the party had produced a false witness, and he lost his cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The laws of Barbarians</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>The laws of these Barbarians were distinguished in the fact that they were not confined to a certain district.
 The Frank was tried by the law of the Franks The Aleman was tried by the law of the Alemans The Burgundian was tried by the law of the Burgundians The Roman was tried by the Roman law.  Those conquerors were so far from forming their laws to an uniform system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin of Chivalry</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>Male connections with females are founded on:
 the pleasure of enjoyment the happiness of loving and being beloved and the ambition of pleasing the ladies because they are the best judges of some of those things which constitute personal merit.  This general desire of pleasing produces gallantry. It is not love itself, but the delicate and perpetual dissembler of love. According to the different circumstances of every country and age, love inclines more to one of those three things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The public Prosecutor</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-36/</guid>
      <description>The Salic, Ripuarian, and other barbarous laws punished crimes with pecuniary fines. They did not have a public officer who does criminal prosecutions. And indeed the issue of all causes being reduced to the reparation of damages, every prosecution was in some measure civil, and might be managed by any one.
On the other hand, the Roman law had popular form for the prosecution of crimes, which were inconsistent with the office of a public prosecutor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Revival of the Roman Law, and the Result thereof. Change in the Tribunals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-28/chapter-42/</guid>
      <description>UPON the discovery of Justinian’s digest towards the year 1137, the Roman law seemed to rise out of its ashes.
Schools were then established in Italy, where it was publicly taught. They had already the Justinian code, and the Novellae. This code was so favourably received in Italy as to eclipse the law of the Lombards.
The Italian doctors brought the law of Justinian into France, where they had only the Theodosian code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
