<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pantrynomic Solutions on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pantrynomic Solutions on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Multilateral Pool Clearing Can Solve Currency Crises and Bilaterialism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/multilateral-pool-clearing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/multilateral-pool-clearing/</guid>
      <description>This is the simplified version of EF Schumacher&amp;rsquo;s Multilateral Clearing which was used by Keynes for his International Clearing Union and Bancor proposal in Bretton Woods, which were not accepted as they would regulate world trade. We build on Schumacher&amp;rsquo;s ideas and merge them with those of Adam Smith to create a multilateral free trade system which is based on gold or grains, as an implmentation of cross-border Pantrynomics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Restore the Gold Standard through Clearing Funds</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/how-to-restore-the-gold-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/how-to-restore-the-gold-standard/</guid>
      <description>Our proposed Pool Clearing system, derived from EF Schumacher and Adam Smith, can prevent currency attack and commodity speculation since forward contracts will not be transferrable and private currency trading will not be allowed. This is because the clearing funds will do the work of providing liquidity and transferring working capital to the producers and exporters.
But how will the system work for overseas investments?
If a Japanese investor wants to invest his JPY 1b in Vietnam using the current financial system, he will convert it to USD which the Vietnamese banks will convert into VND.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are Resource Credits?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/resource-credits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/resource-credits/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we were invited to join the SIS Online Hackathon, wherein the organizers were looking for a tech solution for B2B cash management. The Covid pandemic has wreaked havoc on cash and many customers are unable to pay their suppliers.
Fortunately, our proposed economic system, called The Pantry Hub, derived from Adam Smith, is purpose-built to predict and solve such problems. In fact, we have been warning of a huge global economic crisis as early as 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Points Banking?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/points-banking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/points-banking/</guid>
      <description>In previous posts, we explained two alternative subsystems for a financial or monetary crisis:
 Basic Universal Revenue (BUR) for creating basic value as food Resource Credits (RC) for keeping companies afloat and avoiding bankruptcy  Both BUR and RC have a common denominator which is their values are pegged to rice so that BUR is in ultimately in grams of rice just as RC is in kilos of rice or wheat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Can Fairtax Solve Tax Evasion and Budget Deficits?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/fairtax/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/fairtax/</guid>
      <description>Update June 2020: In 2015, our model predicted a huge global crisis starting in 2019 to be felt many years afterwards. This is now known as the Covid-19 pandemic. Our model predicts inflation next, as a result of governments applying sophistical mercantile solutions, now known as &amp;ldquo;bailouts&amp;rdquo;, on supply and demand problems. These bailouts will be paid for by either inflation (as college debt, rising bills, rent, etc) or by increased taxation, both will lead to unrest (as seen in the US riots) or a change in government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Survive in the Music Industry</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/how-to-survive-in-the-music-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/how-to-survive-in-the-music-industry/</guid>
      <description>Taylor Swift&amp;rsquo;s op-ed in The Wall Street Journal shows her continued optimism in the music industry despite its continued downturn caused by the popularity of digital music. She defends her optimism by viewing music as valueable art which can still sell, especially if the buyer falls in love with an artist.
The Pantrynomics of Music While many musicians are alarmed at the decline of the price of their valuable art, Adam Smith assures us that its decline is actually natural:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to prevent Inequality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/how-to-solve-inequality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/solutions/pantrynomics/how-to-solve-inequality/</guid>
      <description>According to Socrates, inequality takes root most commonly when a society transitions from intellectual rule to an oligarchy:
An Oligarchic State is not one, but two States, the one of poor, the other of rich men. They are living on the same spot and always conspiring against one another. Their fondness for money makes them unwilling to pay taxes. Under such a constitution, the same persons have too many callings. They are husbandmen, tradesmen, warriors, all in one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
