<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 4: Human Bondage, or the Strength of the Emotions on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 4: Human Bondage, or the Strength of the Emotions on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>APPENDIX</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-4/appendix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-4/appendix/</guid>
      <description>What have said in this Part concerning the right way of life has not been arranged, so as to admit of being seen at one view, but has been set forth piece—meal, according as I thought each Proposition could most readily be deduced from what preceded it. I propose, therefore, to rearrange my remarks and to bring them under leading heads.
  All our endeavours or desires so follow from the necessity of our nature, that they can be understood either through it alone, as their proximate cause, or by virtue of our being a part of nature, which cannot be adequately conceived through itself without other individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Definitions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-4/definitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-4/definitions/</guid>
      <description>Preface bondage is the human infirmity in moderating and checking the emotions. When a man is a prey to his emotions, he is not his own master. He lies at the mercy of fortune. He is often compelled, while seeing that which is better for him, to follow that which is worse. I will show in this part of my treatise:
 why this is so, and what is good or evil in the emotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 1 to 10</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-4/propositions-1-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-4/propositions-1-13/</guid>
      <description>1. No positive quality possessed by a false idea is removed by the presence of what is true, in virtue of its being true. 2. Imagination is an idea which indicates the human body&amp;rsquo;s present disposition, than the nature of the external body not distinctly, but confusedly. Whence it comes to pass, that the mind is said to err. 2. We are only passive, in so far as we are apart of Nature, which cannot be conceived by itself without other parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 14-19</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-4/propositions-14-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-4/propositions-14-19/</guid>
      <description>A true knowledge of good and evil cannot check any emotion by virtue of being true, but only in so far as it is considered as an emotion.  Desire arising from the knowledge of good and bad can be quenched or checked by many of the other desires arising from the emotions whereby we are assailed.  Desire arising from the knowledge of good and evil, in so far as such knowledge regards what is future, may be more easily controlled or quenched, than the desire for what is agreeable at the present moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 20 to 27 </title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-4/propositions-20-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-4/propositions-20-27/</guid>
      <description>The more every man endeavours, and is able to seek what is useful to him—in other words, to preserve his own being—the more is he endowed with virtue; on the contrary, in proportion as a man neglects to seek what is useful to him, that is, to preserve his own being, he is wanting in power.  No one can desire to be blessed, to act rightly, and to live rightly, without at the same time wishing to be, act, and to live—in other words, to actually exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 28</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-4/propositions-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-4/propositions-28/</guid>
      <description>28. The mind&amp;rsquo;s highest good is the knowledge of God, and the mind&amp;rsquo;s highest virtue is to know God. 29. No individual thing, which is entirely different from our own nature, can help or check our power of activity, and absolutely nothing can do us good or harm, unless it has something in common with our nature.  A thing cannot be bad for us through the quality which it has in common with our nature, but it is bad for us in so far as it is contrary to our nature.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
