<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 4 on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 4 on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Discipline</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-4/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-4/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>When everyone went out, there could be no military discipline.
They were all on the same level. Discipline was unnecessary because their common cause was so well discerned. When the highest orders went out, a principle of honour would supply the place of discipline. But when this office fell on the lowest order, the most severe and rigid discipline became necessary. Accordingly, discipline has been introduced into all standing armies. Generally, they should be kept under such authority as to be more afraid of their general and officers than of the enemy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Militias</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-4/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-4/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>In the beginning of society, the state&amp;rsquo;s defence required no police, nor particular provision for it.
The people rose up to oppose any attempt made against them. The chief in peacetime naturally preserved his influence in wartime.
But after the division of labour took place, some needed to stay at home to be employed in agriculture and other arts, while the rest went out to war.
Cultivation naturally fell to the meanest rank after the introduction of:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing Armies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-4/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-4/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>In this way, standing armies came to be introduced.
Armies should be raised:
 in the most convenient way, and with the least possible hurt to the country.  Many standing armies may be exclaimed against. But they must be introduced in a certain period of society. A militia commanded by landed gentlemen in possession of the nation&amp;rsquo;s public offices would never sacrifice the country&amp;rsquo;s liberties for anyone. Such a militia would be the best security against a foreign standing army.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
