<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Rise and Fall of the Roman Empire on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Rise and Fall of the Roman Empire on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Augustus</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>Sextus Pompeius possessed Sicily and Sardinia, was master at sea, and saw himself at the head of a great multitude of fugitives, and persons devoted to death by proscriptions, whose last hopes depended on their valour. Octavius contended with him, in two very laborious wars; and after a variety of ill success, vanquished him by the abilities of Agrippa.
Most of the conspirators ended their lives in a miserable manner; and it was natural that persons who headed a party, so frequently harrassed by wars, in [88] which no quarter was afforded, should die a violent death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remarks on the Emperors, from Caius Calicula to Antoninus</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>CALICULA succeeded Tiberius, and it was said of him, that there never was a better slave, nor a worse master: and indeed these two circumstances are very consistent; for the same turn of mind which inclines a person to be strongly affected at unlimited power in his sovereign, makes him to be no less in love with it, when he rises to empire himself.
Caligula restored the assemblies of the people, which Tiberius had prohibited; and abolished the arbitrary law and constructions of treason established by that emperor: from which proceeding we may observe, that the beginnings of a bad reign sometimes resemble the conclusion of a good one; for a wicked prince may, from a principle of contradiction to the motives of his predecessor’s conduct, be spirited to actions which the other performed from a virtuous inducement; and we owe to this very principle a number of good as well as bad regulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rome after the Death of Cæsar</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>It was impossible for the republic to be re-established. There was no longer any tyrant, and yet liberty was extinguished because the causes of its destruction still continued to prevent its revival.
The assassins only had a plan of a conspiracy, but did not know how to make it effective. After the assassination, they all retired to the capital. The next day, Lepidus, who was fond of commotions, took the Forum with a band of soldiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sylla, Pompey, and Caesar</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>I will not discuss the horrors of the wars between Marius and Sylla. Appian has collected all the dreadful particulars into this history:
Both chiefs were jealous, ambitious, barbarous, and furious. The new citizens, and the ancient, no longer considered each other as members of the same republic, but gave a loose to a series of hostilities, so peculiar in their nature, as to comprehend all the miseries of a civil and foreign war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiberius</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>AS a river, sometimes, with a slow and silent progress, undermines the banks that have been thrown up to restrain its current, and at last overwhelms them in a moment, and sheds an inundation over the fields they formerly preserved; in the same manner, the supreme authority, which gained an insensible growth under Augustus, bore down all before it in the succeeding reign of Tiberius.
A law at that time subsisted, which made it treason to form any injurious attempt against the majesty of the people: Tiberius assumed to himself the interpretation and enforcement of this law, and extended it not only to the cases for which it was originally calculated, but to every conjuncture that could possibly be favourable to his hatred or suspicions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes in the State</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>THE emperors, to prevent the continual treasons of the army, associated into the government proper persons in whom they might confide; and Dioclesian, under pretext of the weight and multiplicity of the public affairs, established a law, that there should always be two Emperors and as many Cæsars. He judged, that, by this proceeding, the four principal armies being possessed by the partners in the empire, would naturally intimidate one another, and that the inferior armies being too weak to have any thoughts of raising [124] their chiefs to the imperial dignity, their custom of election would be gradually discontinued, and entirely abolished at last.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerations on the State of the Empire from Antoninus to Probus</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>IN this period, the Stoics propagated their doctrines in the empire with great popularity; and it seems as if nature herself had been industrious to produce this admirable sect, which resembled those plants the earth causes to spring up in places never visited by the sunbeams.
This sect furnished the Romans with their best emperors; none but Marcus Aurelius could extinguish the remembrance of the first Antonine who adopted him; and we find ourselves affected with a secret pleasure when we speak of this emperor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disorders in the Eastern Empire</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>THE Persians, during this period, were in a much happier situation than the Romans; they had little reason to be apprehensive of the northern people † , because that part of mount Taurus which extends between the Caspian and Euxine seas separated them from those nations, and they effectually shut up a very narrow pass ‡ , which was the only practicable avenue for the cavalry; in every other part the Barbarians were obliged to descend from frightful precipices § , and to quit their horses in which all their military strength consisted; and besides these impediments they were blocked in by the Araxes, a river of great depth, and which flows from west to east, all the passages of which were easy to be defended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Mithridates Could Resist the Romans</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>AMONG the several kings whom the Romans invaded, Mithridates was the only one who made a courageous defence, and exposed them to danger.
His dominions were situated to wonderful advantage for carrying on a war with them: they bordered on the inaccessible countries of mount Caucasus, peopled with savage nations, whom that prince could call to his assistance; they thence extended along the sea of Pontus, which Mithridates covered with his ships, and he was incessantly purchasing new armies of Scythians: Asia was open to his invasions; and he was rich, because his cities, situated on the Pontus Euxinus, carried on an advantageous traffic with nations less industrious than themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Romans Conquered all Nations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>DURING the course of so mighty a prosperity, in which it is usual for mankind to forget themselves, the senate continued to act with the same depth of judgment; and whilst their armies were spreading an universal terror, they would not suffer those to rise who were once depressed.
A tribunal arose which judged all nations: At the close of every war they determined the rewards or punishments which every one had merited: They took away from the vanquished people, part of their lands, and gave them to their allies, in which they did two things; they engaged, in the interests of Rome, princes from whom they had little to fear, and much to hope; and they weakened others from whom they had nothing to hope, and every thing to fear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Romans raised themselves to Empire</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>AS the people of Europe, in this age, have very near the same arts, the same arms, the same discipline, and the same manner of making war; the prodigious fortune to which the Romans attained, seems incredible to us. Besides, power is at this time divided so disproportionably, that it is not possible for a petty state to raise itself, merely by its own strength, [16] from the low condition in which Providence has placed it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justinian&#39;s Conquests and Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>The barbarians broke all at once like a flood into the empire. They mutually incommoded one another, and all the politics of those times consisted in setting them at variance together. This was a circumstance easy to accomplish since their avarice and fierce dispoposition greatly contributing to make it practicable.
The largest of them was therefore destroyed before they could settle themselves. This was how the Eastern empire still subsisted for some time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some new maxims received by the Romans</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>SOMETIMES the pusillanimous spirit of the emperors † , and frequently the defenceless state of the empire made the people employ their money to appease the nations that threatened to invade them; but the desired peace could never be effectually purchased, because those who sold it could, whenever they pleased, oblige the Romans to buy it again.
It is much better to hazard an unsuccessful war, than to part with great sums for a precarious peace; for a prince is always suspected when it is known he will make a long resistance before he can be vanquished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Corruption of the Romans</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>I think that the sect of Epicurus, which began to be propagated at Rome, towards the close of the republic, was very prejudicial to the minds and genius of the people.
The Greeks had been infatuated with its doctrines long before. Consequently, they were corrupted much earlier than the Romans. Polybius says that oaths, in his time, could not induce any person to place confidence in a Greek, whereas they were considered by a Roman as inviolable obligations upon his conscience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Destruction of the Eastern Empire</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>How could the Greek empire possibly subsist so long?
The Arabs invaded the empire and conquered several provinces. Their chiefs became competitors for the Khalisa, and the flame of their first zeal only burst out in civil dissensions.
The Arabs also conquered Persia andthe Greeks were no longer obliged to keep the principal forces of the empire stationed on the banks of the Euphrates.
Callinicus, an architect, came from Syria to Constantinople.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Divisions which always subsisted in the City</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>WHILST Rome was conquering the world, a hidden war was carrying on within its walls: these fires were like those of volcanos, which break out the instant they were sed by some combustible substance.
After the expulsion of the kings, the government became aristocratical: the patrician families only, obtained all the employments and dignities in the * state, and consequently all † honours civil and military.
The patricians being determined to prevent, if possible, the return of the kings, endeavoured to soment the restless principles which now prevailed in the minds of the people; but they did more than they would willingly have done: by attempting to inspire them with a hatred for kings, they fired them with an inordinate thirst for liberty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gauls and Pyrrhus: Parallels between Carthage and Rome and The War of Hannibal</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>THE Romans were engaged in several wars against the Gauls: a thirst of glory, a contempt of death, and an inflexible resolution of conquering, were equal in both nations, but the weapons they used were different; the bucklers of the latter was small, and their swords [19] unfit for execution; and, indeed, the Gauls were cut to pieces by the Romans, much after the same manner as the Mexicans, in these latter ages, by the Spaniards; and a surprizing circumstance is, that though these people were combating perpetually with the Romans, they yet suffered themselves to be destroyed one after another, without their ever being sensible of, enquiring after, or obviating the cause of their calamities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grandeur of Attila and Why the Western Empire was overturned before the Eastern</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>Christianity was established when the empire was declining. The Christians reproached the Pagans for that decay. The Pagans retorted the charge on Christiantiy.
The Christians replied that Dioclesian ruined the empire, by associating his three colleagues because each emperor would be as expensive, and maintained as great armies as could have subsisted had there been but one sovereign.
As a consequence, those who furnished the contributions being unequally proportioned to the number of the receivers, the charges became so excessive that the lands were forsaken by the husbandmen, and for want of cultivation lay waste, and were covered with wild and barren forests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Infancy of Rome and the Wars it sustained.</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>We are not to form to ourselves an idea of the city of Rome, in its infancy, from the cities which exist at this time, except we have in view those of the Crim Tartars, built for the stowing and securing of plunder, cattle, fruits, and other produce of the country.
The ancient names of the chief places in Rome, are all relative to this use.
Rome didn&amp;rsquo;t even have streets unless we call their central roads as such.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of War of the Romans</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>AS the Romans devoted themselves entirely to war, and considered it as the only science, they therefore bent all their thoughts, and the genius with which they were informed to the improvement of it doubtless a god, says * Vegetius, inspired them with the idea of the legion.
They judged that it would be necessary to arm the soldiers who composed the legion with weapons whether offensive or defensive, of a stronger and † heavier kind than those of any other nation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Greece, of Macedonia, of Syria, and of Egypt, after the Depression of Carthage</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>I IMAGINE Hannibal did not abound in witticisms, especially in favour of Fabius and Marcellus against himself. I am sorry to see Livy strew his flowers on these enormous colossuses of antiquity: I wish he had done like Homer, who neglects embellishing them, and knew so well how to put them in motion.
Besides, what Hannibal is made to speak, ought to have common sense: but if, on hearing the defeat of his brother, he said publicly, that it was the prelude of the ruin of Carthage; could any thing have a greater tendency to drive to despair a people, who had placed their confidence in him, and to discourage an army which expected such high recompences after the war?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The weakness of the Eastern Empire</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>Amidst the general confusion of affairs, Phocas became unsettled in his new dignity. Heraclius came from Africa and murdered him and found the provinces invaded and the legions destroyed.
As soon as he remedied these disasters, the Arabians extended the Islamic empire founded by Mohammed.
No people ever made so rapid a progress. They immediately conquered Syria, Palestine, Egypt, and Africa, and then turned against the Persians.
God permitted his religion to be laid low, in so many places where it once had been predominant; not that it now ceased to be the object of his providential care, but because it always either in its state of glory or depression produces its natural effect, which is the sanctification of the soul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Causes which destroyed Rome</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-29/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>WHILST the sovereignty of Rome was confined to Italy, it was easy for the commonwealth to subsist.
Every soldier was at the same time a citizen. Every consul raised an army, and other citizens marched into the field under his successor: as their forces were not very numerous, such persons only were received among the troops, as had possessions considerable enough to make them interested in the preservation of the city.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
