<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 7: Essential Education on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-7/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 7: Essential Education on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dialectics as an Essential Study</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-7/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-7/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Motion has many forms. Two of them are obvious to ordinary people. There are others which may be left to wiser persons. These two are the study of motions from sight and sound*. The eyes are designed to look up at the stars, just as the ears are designed to hear harmonious motions. These are sister sciences, as the Pythagoreans say.    Translator&amp;rsquo;s Note: The study of visible motion deals with particles, the study of audible motion deals with waves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Subjects: Astronomy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-7/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-7/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>The Patterns of Geometry Can Be Seen In Astronomy* *Translator&amp;rsquo;s Note: As later proven by Isaac Newton who invented calculus from geometric patterns through the observation of heavenly bodies
We propose geometry as a second branch of knowledge which our youth will study. We make astronomy the third. I am strongly inclined to it. The observation of the seasons, months, and years is as essential to the general as it is to the farmer or sailor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Subjects: Math and Geometry</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-7/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-7/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Aside from Music and Gymnastic, Math, Geometry, Astronomy, and Dialectic Must be Taught to Guardians How will such guardians be produced? The process is not the turning over of an oyster-shell. This is an allusion to a game where two parties fled or pursued depending on whether an oyster-shell thrown in the air fell with the dark or light side. The process is to turn a soul from twilight into the true day of being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Allegory of the Cave (Enlightenment)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-7/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-7/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Unenlightened Humans Let me show how far our nature is enlightened or unenlightened. Imagine humans living in a underground cave. Its mouth is open towards the light which reaches all along the cave.
They:
 have lived inside the cave from childhood have their legs and necks chained so that they cannot move can only see in front of them  The chains prevent them from moving their heads. Above and behind them a fire is blazing at a distance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
