<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Section 2: Indirect Sympathy as Justice on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Section 2: Indirect Sympathy as Justice on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of Justice and Beneficence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-2/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-2/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Beneficence cannot be extorted by force, but justice can 1 Only beneficent actions from proper motives seem to require reward because only such actions:
 are the approved objects of gratitude, or excite the observer&amp;rsquo;s sympathetic gratitude.  2 Only hurtful actions from improper motives seem to deserve punishment because only such actions:
 are the approved objects of resentment, or excite the observer&amp;rsquo;s sympathetic resentment.  3 Beneficence is always free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sense of Justice, Remorse, and the Consciousness of Merit</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-2/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-2/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Justice requires a lowered ego 11 Only the just indignation for evil done to us is the only proper motive for us to:
 hurt our neighbour and incite us to do evil to another  By nature, everyone:
 is first and principally recommended to his own care is fitter to take care of himself than of any other person. prefers his own happiness  But no impartial spectator can go along with this at the expense of the happiness of others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Utility of the sense of justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-2/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-2/section-2/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Society requires the virtue called Justice which is sustained by the utility afforded by society 15 It is thus that man, who can subsist only in society, was fitted by nature to that situation for which he was made. Everyone in society needs each other&amp;rsquo;s assistance and protection. The society flourishes and is happy if the necessary assistance is reciprocally afforded from love, gratitude, friendship, and esteem. All its members are:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
