<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 5: The Power of the Understanding or of Human Freedom on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 5: The Power of the Understanding or of Human Freedom on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Axioms</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-5/axioms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-5/axioms/</guid>
      <description>The remaining portion of my Ethics is concerned with the way leading to freedom. For this, I shall treat the power of the reason, showing: how far it can control the emotions, and what is the nature of Mental Freedom or Blessedness. We can then see how much more powerful the wise man is than the ignorant. I do not intend:
 to point out the method and means for perfecting the understanding This question is in the area of Logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 1-</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-5/propositions-11-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-5/propositions-11-20/</guid>
      <description>11. In proportion as a mental image is referred to more objects, so is it more frequent, or more often vivid, and occupies the mind more. 12. The mental images of things are more easily associated with the images referred to things which we clearly and distinctly understand, than with others. 13. A mental image is more often vivid, in proportion as it is associated with a greater number of other images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 1-10</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-5/propositions-1-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-5/propositions-1-10/</guid>
      <description>As thoughts and the ideas of things are arranged and associated in the mind, so are the modifications of body or the images of things precisely in the same way arranged and associated in the body.
  If we remove a disturbance of the spirit, or emotion, from the thought of an external cause, and unite it to other thoughts, then will the love or hatred towards that external cause, and also the vacillations of spirit which arise from these emotions, be destroyed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 21-</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-5/propositions-21-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-5/propositions-21-28/</guid>
      <description>The mind can only imagine anything, or remember what is past, while the body endures.
  Nevertheless in God there is necessarily an idea, which expresses the essence of this or that human body under the form of eternity. Proof: God is the cause of the existence of this or that human body and also of its essence (1.25.).
  Therefore, this essence must necessarily:
 be conceived through the very essence of God (1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 29-32</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-5/propositions-29-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-5/propositions-29-32/</guid>
      <description>Whatsoever the mind understands under the form of eternity, it does not understand by virtue of conceiving the present actual existence of the body, but by virtue of conceiving the essence of the body under the form of eternity.  Note.—Things are conceived by us as actual in two ways; either as existing in relation to a given time and place, or as contained in God and following from the necessity of the divine nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 33-42</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-5/propositions-33-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-5/propositions-33-42/</guid>
      <description>God&amp;rsquo;s intellectual love, arising from intuition, is eternal.
  The mind is subject to those emotions which are attributable to passions, only while the body endures. Proof: Imagination is the idea wherewith the mind contemplates a thing as present (2.17 note). Yet this idea indicates rather the present disposition of the human body than the nature of the external thing (2.16. Coroll. 2). Therefore, emotion (see general Def. of Emotions) is imagination, as it indicates the present disposition of the body.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
