<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Section 3: The Variations of Sympathy on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Section 3: The Variations of Sympathy on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Corruption of Morality by this disposition to admire the rich and despise the poor</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-3/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-3/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>The similarity between the respect for greatness and respect for virtue corrupts morality.
28 We have a disposition to:
 admire, and almost to worship, the rich and the powerful, and neglect or despise persons of poor and mean condition.  Both of these are necessary to establish and maintain:
 the distinction of ranks and the order of society.  However, it is also the most universal cause of the corruption of our moral sentiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Our sympathy with sorrow falls much shorter of the sorrow felt by sufferer</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-3/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-3/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Our Sympathy with the Sorrow of Others is Stronger than Our Sympathy with the Joy of Others because pain is a stronger sensation than pleasure (which can even be a source of envy) 1 Our sympathy with sorrow has been more noticed than our sympathy with joy. In its most proper and primitive signification, the word &amp;lsquo;sympathy&amp;rsquo; denotes our fellow-feeling with the sufferings of others, not with their enjoyments.
Joseph Butler was an ingenious and subtle philosopher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin of Ambition and Distinction of Ranks</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-3/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-1/section-3/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Our sympathy with the false idea of the happiness of the rich and the great is the basis of ambition 16 We parade our riches and hide our poverty because people sympathize more with our joy than our sorrow.
We are most mortified to:
 expose our distress in public, and feel that no one conceives half of what we suffer.  We pursue riches and avoid poverty chiefly from this regard to mankind&amp;rsquo;s sentiments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
