<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 10: The Soul on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 10: The Soul on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reincarnation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>The Story of Er I will tell you of the heroic tale of Er the son of Armenius, a Pamphylian by birth. He was slain in battle. Ten days later when the bodies of the dead are decomposing, his body was found unaffected by decay. It was carried home to be buried.
On the 12th day, as he was lying on the funeral pile, he returned to life and told them what he had seen in the other world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shallow Philosophy and Religion as Poetry</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Imitation is Thrice removed from the truth. One of the many excellences in our State is the rejection of imitative poetry. All poetical imitations are ruinous to the understanding of the hearers. The knowledge of their true nature is the only antidote to them. I have always had an awe and love of Homer. He is the great teacher of the poets on tragedy. But a man is not to be revered more than the truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Immortality of the Soul</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>The Just Are Rewarded, and the Unjust are Punished in the Next Life Glaucon: You have not mentioned the greatest prizes and rewards which await virtue.  Socrates: Virtue is great prize in itself. If there are greater prizes, then they must be of an inconceivable greatness. Forty years is surely a little thing compared with eternity. Then just say that there is nothing to reward virtue in the future. An immortal being would rather think of eternity than this short life.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
