<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Essassani on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Essassani on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Definitions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/definitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/definitions/</guid>
      <description>Word Definition     abundance The ability to do what you need to do, when you need to do it. (Money is merely one of innumerable ways to express &amp;amp; experience abundance.)   anxiety The energy of excitement, but filtered through a belief in something undesirable or unpreferred. (&amp;ldquo;Anxiety&amp;rdquo; is &amp;ldquo;Excitement&amp;rdquo; with a negative judgement. Remove the negative judgment, and you have &amp;ldquo;Excitement&amp;rdquo;. )   discernment Discernment is selecting and acting on your preference from the available options   judgment is going a step-further and invalidating what you do NOT prefer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Definitions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/life/</guid>
      <description>The Uniqueness of Each Incarnation Each Soul extends portions of itself into time &amp;amp; space as particular incarnations. Just as many fingers extend out from the same one hand, there are many incarnations at many points in time and space, all emanating from the same Soul.
From the point of view of your Soul (outside time &amp;amp; space) all these incarnations (past incarnations, present incarnation, future incarnations) are all simultaneously occurring NOW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow your excitement</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/excitement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/excitement/</guid>
      <description>Finding your Purpose in Life Act on it! Excitement is caused by a resonance with your Higher Self.
Excitement is a &amp;ldquo;sign&amp;rdquo; that the activity you are contemplating is aligned with your Higher Self, and this alignment is what causes the excitement. This naturally leads you to what you are &amp;ldquo;meant&amp;rdquo; to be doing - what your Soul &amp;ldquo;hopes&amp;rdquo; your free-will chooses to do. This is your &amp;ldquo;Purpose&amp;rdquo;. So this is the simple yet effortlessly-effective way to find your life&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Purpose&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metaphysics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/metaphysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/metaphysics/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Receiving&amp;rdquo; the Reality you Desire A radio does not have to create the program it wishes to hear. It merely needs to receive an already-existing program. It makes itself an effective receiver by matching frequencies, synchronizing frequencies - creating a similarity of vibrations - with the program it wishes to receive.
Likewise, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to create the reality you desire, because it already exists - among the infinite probable realities all simultaneously co-existing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutrality, Positivity, and Negativity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/neutral/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/neutral/</guid>
      <description>Neutral Props In a theater that shows many plays, there may be some props back-stage that are frequently used for several different plays. For each play that prop has a special meaning, but outside that play, the prop has no innate intrinsic built-in meaning. All the props are basically without meaning.
From this innate absence of meaning, we can assign any meaning we want to them.
Likewise, all the events that you experiencing as &amp;ldquo;happening&amp;rdquo; in your life are &amp;ldquo;neutral props&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/time/</guid>
      <description>There is only ONE MOMENT in all creation - the eternal NOW.
&amp;ldquo;Time&amp;rdquo; is an illusion created by consciousness.
In a film projector, the individual frames of the film are shown in a rapid steady sequence - one frame at a time. This rapid steady sequence of STILL frames creates the ILLUSION of flowing time.
But in truth, all the actual frames that are used all exist simultaneously. There is the illusion of &amp;ldquo;time&amp;rdquo; only when the film projector displays those frames - one frame at a time - in a rapid steady sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/other/alien/essassani/basics/</guid>
      <description>The Essassani are a 5th dimensional civilization which is based on unconditional love, ecstasy, fun, following your excitement, being totally non-judgmental, and giving validity and equality to the uniqueness of each individual in their society*.
 *Superphysics note: Superhysics is based on David Hume&amp;rsquo;s maxim that mentality creates reality. This is how the Essassani maxims, such as &amp;lsquo;believing is seeing&amp;rsquo; caught our attention. However, no one seems to be keen enough to notice that their principles are designed for 5th dimensional beings and not 4th dimensional ones like humans.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
