<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Laws in General on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Laws in General on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Four Laws of Nature</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-1/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-1/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Antecdent to the above-mentioned laws are those of nature.
 They get their force entirely from our frame and existence. To know these laws, we must see man before the establishment of society.  The laws received in such a state would be those of nature. The most natural law is to love the Creator, though it is not the first in sequence.
Man, in a state of nature, would have the faculty of knowing before he had acquired any knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Laws Depend on the Nature of the People</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-1/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-1/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>AS soon as mankind enter into a state of society, they lose the sense of their weakness. Equality ceases, and then commences the state of war.
Each particular society begins to feel its strength. This leads to a state of war between different nations.
The individuals likewise of each society become sensible of their force: hence the principal advantages of this society they endeavour to convert to their own emolument; which constitutes a state of war between individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Relation of Laws to different Beings</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-1/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-1/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Laws generally are the necessary relations arising from the nature of things. In this sense, all beings have their laws.
 The Deity has his laws. The material world has its laws. Animals have their laws. Humans have their laws, created by their intelligence.  Some people assert absurdly that the various effects in this world were spontaneously produced by a blind fatality.
But this blind fatality cannot create intelligent beings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
