<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Section 2 of the Simplified Lectures on Jurisprudence by Adam Smith on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Section 2 of the Simplified Lectures on Jurisprudence by Adam Smith on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guardian and Ward, Domestic Punishments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-2/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-2/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>When a father dies leaving his children young, they should be taken care of. Even in the times of exposition, when an infant was some time kept, it was thought cruel to put him to death: the child was destitute there were then no hospitals or places of charity: it must therefore be put into the custody of some person.
The law fixed the father’s side nearest relation to care for the child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Husband and Wife</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-2/chapter-1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-2/chapter-1a/</guid>
      <description>Each person is a member of a family which is made up of three kinds of relations:
 Husband and wife Parent and child Master and servant  First of these is husband and wife.
In every animal species, the connection between male and female is necessary for the propagation and support of the species.
Quadrupeds, whenever the female impregnates, have no farther desire for each other. The support of the young is no burden to the female, and there is no occasion for the assistance of the male.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master and Servant</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-2/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-2/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Master and servant is the third relation of a family. The same principle which gave the husband authority over the wife, also gave the father authority over the son. The husband&amp;rsquo;s power was softened through his wife’s friends. She could complain to them. The father was softened by the same means.
But it was not so with the servants who had nobody to complain to. The master had the power of life and death over them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parent and Child</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-2/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-2/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>We come now to consider the history of parentage, being the second relation in which we were to consider man as a member of a family.
The authority of the father over his children, both with respect to liberty and property, was at first absolute. He was at liberty to choose whether he would bring up his children or not, and it was accounted no injustice to refuse to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polygamy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-2/chapter-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-2/chapter-1b/</guid>
      <description>In many countries, men took as many wives as they could maintain.
Voluntary divorce has inconveniences. Yet it is still within justice that a man should divorce his wife and take another for less reasons than adultery, because they make them quite unhappy together though either of them might live well elsewhere.
The same is the case with polygamy. If a woman consents to be one of five or more wives and the law allows it, then there is no injury done to her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slavery</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-2/chapter-3b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/jurisprudence/part-1/section-2/chapter-3b/</guid>
      <description>Slaves may be acquired five ways.
 By being captives in war.   If the conqueror does not kill them, he has a right to make them slaves.  By being children of slaves. By being guilty of crimes.   They becames slaves to the person injured or to the public.  By being in debt in the ancient state of the Roman Republic.   If they could not pay their debt, it was thought reasonable they should work for it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
