<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Pantrynomics on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Pantrynomics on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pantrynomics Textbook</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/pantrynomics-textbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/pantrynomics-textbook/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve started the long process of building a textbook, which actually is supposed to be a user&amp;rsquo;s manual for the developers and operators of our proposed economic system called the Pantry Hub.
-- After we discovered the four laws of value, it became irresistable how we could organize all of Pantrynomics elegantly under them. Everything in econometrics, open market operatins, supply and demand, taxation, etc can be put under four huge headings!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Demand Capital Trade Industry Tool</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-demand-capital-trade-industry-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-demand-capital-trade-industry-tool/</guid>
      <description>According to Adam Smith, a crisis begins when a country&amp;rsquo;s industry does not match its capital, just as when an inexperienced entrepreneur launches a business out of speculation:
 The 2008 Financial crisis was caused by securitization unnaturally increasing industry on paper The Asian Financial Crisis was caused by hot money unnaturally increasing industry in Asia. This led to non-performing loans Black Wednesday in 1992 was caused by John Major overvaluing the pound to promote a rosy British industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Modern Economic Table</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-modern-economic-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-modern-economic-table/</guid>
      <description>The Modern Economic Table is a flowchart invented by Francois Quesnay of the Physiocrats in the 18th century. It serves as a proof of how real wealth is generated from agriculture and mining or the productions of the earth instead of from manufacturing and services which merely add value.
Of course, this is not totally true. It is true that raw materials and agriculture are important, but it is also possible for services and processing to be just as important, or even more important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eagle</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-eagle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-eagle/</guid>
      <description>The previous post explained how the error in Einstien&amp;rsquo;s E = mc2 led to the universal equation of Superphysics.
By fixing Einstein&amp;rsquo;s error, the speed of light no longer becomes a constant. Without this constant, the principles of motion no longer gets a linear speed limit. They can now extend onto the metaphysical dimension where motion manifests as the movement of minds and feelings which are never constant nor strictly linear by nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Alternative to GDP</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-alternative-to-gdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-alternative-to-gdp/</guid>
      <description>Pantrynomics will use Purchasing Power as its alternative to GDP, as explained in The Digression on the Value of Silver of the Wealth of Nations.
In that Digression, Adam Smith proved that money supply, as the prices of gold and silver, are not correlated with a society&amp;rsquo;s wealth or poverty. Instead, he wanted to prove that it is the money price of some rude produce relative to the main food grain (such as wheat), which is the clearest indicator of a society&amp;rsquo;s wealth or poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Business Usually Seen as Immoral?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/why-business-is-immoral/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/why-business-is-immoral/</guid>
      <description>Summary: Businesses are based on money which really is just quantitative information, unable to carry qualitative information such as morality. Contracts on the other hand can carry such information and are a better foundation of sustainable business.
 In some societies, especially Eastern ones, business is usually looked down upon. In ancient China and Japan, merchants were not respected and were even oppressed.
In fact, both China and Japan closed off their doors to foreign trade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Quantitative Easing Failed</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/why-quantitative-easing-failed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/why-quantitative-easing-failed/</guid>
      <description>Japan launched Quantitative Easing (QE) as part of Abenomics which was announced in 2012, just as the US launched theirs after the 2008 Financial Crisis. Both actions failed to drive economic growth* for both countries and merely resulted in additional public debt.
 *The growth in the US really came from Trump&amp;rsquo;s fiscal reforms and trade war
 To explain why QE was used and why it failed, we need to go back to 1913.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 1772 Credit Crunch</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-1772-credit-crunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-1772-credit-crunch/</guid>
      <description>In 1772, a credit crisis originating in London hit and spread over Europe and affected the American colonies.
The cause was the creation and over-circulation of bounced checks then known as redrawn bills of exchange. Speculators used these bills to gamble with bank money and the deposits of other people. The end result was a loss of capital, creating a credit crunch, which led to an economic downturn hitting Europe and too-big-to-fail companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effort Theory of Value</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-effort-theory-of-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-effort-theory-of-value/</guid>
      <description>Summary: The effort theory of value is the foundation of Pantrynomics and is derived entirely from Adam Smith&amp;rsquo;s wheat-based valuation in the Wealth of Nations Book 1 Chapter 5. Instead of pegging value to metal coins, it pegs it to the abstract difficulty, stress, or hardship of a task to produce a product or service, which is then relativistically pegged to food, through basic universal revenue and the Economic Table of the Physiocrats</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problems with Money</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/problems-with-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/problems-with-money/</guid>
      <description>People have loved money ever since it was invented. The philosophers David Hume and Socrates, on the other hand, were not so keen on money because of its drawbacks.
Money builds ego Having a lot of money gives theego power over other egos, giving a feeling of superiority to the monied-ego, leading to arbitrary actions which encroaches on other egos, creatinginjusticeand eventually,evil.
A dirt-poor evil bum can hurt a few people, but an ultra rich evil man can hurt so many.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Consumption Motive?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/what-is-the-consumption-motive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/what-is-the-consumption-motive/</guid>
      <description>The consumption or demand motive is one of the most important maxims of Adam Smith&amp;rsquo;s economic system, aside from the Effort Theory of Value. This maxim states that all economic activity is rooted in the people or the demanders in society and not in the producers or suppliers*. This is easily seen in the concept of the human family which is the smallest and most common type of society. We see parents work to provide or produce food for their children who are their consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neoclassical Economics vs Classical Economics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/neoclassical-vs-classical-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/neoclassical-vs-classical-economics/</guid>
      <description>Pantrynomics is our revival of Classical Economics, backed up by actual data which is visualized through data science and analytics. This data spans 2,500 years, from Xenophon&amp;rsquo;s The Economist up to the latest GDP data.
In contrast, Modern Economics only began from the Marginal Revolution of the 1870&amp;rsquo;s. This makes it a toy idea that crashed quickly after 50 years as the Great Crash and Depression. Nowadays, this toy idea manifests as gaming via game theory, the stock market, and cryptocurrencies, all coming from the mercantile game of buying low and selling high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplified Buddhist Economics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/buddhist-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/buddhist-economics/</guid>
      <description>Modern Economics Buddhist Economics     Motive Maximize Consumption in order to maximize Production Minimuze Consumption in order to make Production sustainable   Priority Material Development Human Development   Employment Maximization of Employment for Maximized Production Full Employment (Mothers can leave work to care for their children)   Energy Use High Low   Environmental Policy Exploit Natural Resources Conserve Natural Resources   Spirituality None High    The Buddhist Concept of Work “Right Livelihood” is one of the requirements of the Buddha’s Noble Eightfold Path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Systems for Mars</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/economic-system-for-mars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/economic-system-for-mars/</guid>
      <description>Jeff Bezos recently announced his vision of moving polluting industries to the moon in order to save the Earth, using his reusable rockets. His logic is that the gravity in the moon is 1/6 of that of the Earth and so moon-based industries will require less energy.
It&amp;rsquo;s surprising that no one has pointed out to him that his rockets emit pollution and CO2. It would take so many polluting rocket launches to move heavy industries to the moon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to be Rich</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/how-to-be-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/how-to-be-rich/</guid>
      <description>In The Wealth of Nations, Adam Smith gave tips on wealth-generation:
1. Build capital, not expense Capital is anything that produces value. It can be a physical thing like a machine that produces a valuable product or a metaphysical thing like skill, knowledge, relationships, trust, and integrity. Expense is spending that does not return any value. An example is consumption.
Capitals are increased by parsimony and decreased by prodigality and misconduct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Producer&#39;s &amp; Consumer&#39;s Surplus and Deadweight Loss</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/producers-consumers-surplus-deadweight-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/producers-consumers-surplus-deadweight-loss/</guid>
      <description>According to Economics, a market dis-equilibrium creates three inefficiencies:
 Producer’s Surplus — defined as “the difference between how much of a good the producer is willing to supply versus how much he receives,” or the gain the producer receives Consumer’s Surplus —defined as a situation when “the price that consumers pay for a product or service is less than the price they’re willing to pay,” or a bargain Deadweight loss — defined as “a cost to society created by market inefficiency”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Inverted Yield Curve</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/inverted-yield-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/inverted-yield-curve/</guid>
      <description>To understand the inverted yield curve, we have to understand the nature of bonds.
What are bonds? A bond is a loan to government, giving them private capital to spend for public uses.
However, unlike a normal loan which is paid back in full and can be ended, a bond is a perpetual debt. The investor enters this perpetual lending scheme by buying the bond and then exits at at maturity or by selling his bond back to the market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Six Types of Effort in Pantrynomics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-six-types-of-effort/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-six-types-of-effort/</guid>
      <description>Useful work or effort is one of the foundations of Pantrynomics and is based entirely on Adam Smith’s Effort Theory of Value. This is totally different from Economics and Mercantilism which uses money as the basis through marginal pricing theory.
Since effort is very important, its definition becomes very important. In our theory, we have defined human effort, whether physical or mental, as ultimately rooted in psychological or metaphysical toil and trouble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Seven Obstacles to Agricultural Development</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/seven-obstacles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/seven-obstacles/</guid>
      <description>In The Lectures on Jurisprudence, Adam Smith enumerated the obstacles to agriculture:
  Lack of cultivation by the big land owners
  Payment of the rent in kind
  The farmer has less produce to pay as rent after a bad harvest, but he will have a bit more money to pay because the scarcity will increase the money price of his little harvest.
 Additional taxes by the government (kings)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masayoshi Son: The Last Capitalist</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-last-capitalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-last-capitalist/</guid>
      <description>In my earlier post, I mentioned that our model designated 2019 as the start of the crisis years which will be a general economic downturn culminating as a global stagflation. This period will be a time for mentality change specifically with thecapitalist system which is really just the perfection of the old mercantile system. Capitalism &amp;lsquo;arbitrages&amp;rsquo; equity while mercantilism &amp;lsquo;arbitrages&amp;rsquo; commodities.
First, Some History.. The mercantile system was created when paper money and instruments were invented by the Dutch in the 17th century, who got the idea from the Jews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Factors that Affect Wages and Profits</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/five-factors-affecting-wages-profits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/five-factors-affecting-wages-profits/</guid>
      <description>Are you looking for a career that gives a high salary or deciding what kind of business to establish? Adam Smith enumerated five factors that affect wages and profits:
 The agreeableness or disagreeableness of the employments  A job&amp;rsquo;s difficulty, cleanliness, and/or honorableness can lead to different wage and profit levels
The difficulty and cost of learning them  A job that requires a high degree of techincal skill will lead to higher wages than one that is simple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Reform Principles of Adam Smith</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/land-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/land-reform/</guid>
      <description>In Book 3, Chap 2, Adam Smith writes that people should own land only as they can productively use:
A great proprietor is seldom a great improver. In the disorderly times which created those barbarous institutions, the great proprietor was employed in defending his own territories and extending his jurisdiction over his neighbours. He did not have time to cultivate and improve the land. When law and order was established and afforded him this leisure, he often did not have the inclination nor the needed abilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Development From Zero via Adam Smith</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/economic-development-from-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/economic-development-from-zero/</guid>
      <description>Update Apr 2021: This post was made in 2015 because the model predicted a huge crisis starting in 2019 that could eventually collapse some societies.
 The main advantage of Pantrynomics over Economics is that it is based on the dynamics of the human mind as explained by David Hume which was later applied by Adam Smith into his Theory of Moral Sentiments and The Wealth of Nations.
To David Hume and Eastern philosophy, the mind is a metaphysical thing, different from the physical brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tao as One&#39;s Life Purpose</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-tao-as-life-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-tao-as-life-purpose/</guid>
      <description>The core flaw of Economics, which is also the source of the unsustainability of &amp;ldquo;economic&amp;rdquo; systems, is that it focuses on utility or pleasure from external objects as their ultimate goals. According to Adam Smith, this is wrong because utility is merely the effect of existence and is part of the deception of Nature (which in Eastern Philosophy is called Maya).
It is this deception which rouses and keeps in continual motion the industry of mankind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Defines Capitalism?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/what-defines-capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/what-defines-capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Summary: We define Capitalism as an economic system that uses outside ownership to amass private profits.
 A major topic of debate among economists is whether Adam Smith was a proponent of capitalism.
We argue that he was not, simply because his core ideas are very different from those of capitalism, which is merely mercantilism with superficial changes. The source of the confusion is the unclear definition of the word &amp;lsquo;capitalism&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Skyscraper Curse of Economics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-skyscraper-curse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/the-skyscraper-curse/</guid>
      <description>The Economist showed an interesting graphic of the correlation of skyscrapers and economic crises in a phenomenon known as the Skyscraper Curse. A question was posed: &amp;ldquo;Does this frenzy of building augur badly for the world economy?&amp;rdquo;, to which we answer &amp;ldquo;Yes, because of Economics&amp;rdquo;.
To explain why skyscraper booms are generally bad, we explain their nature using our Dialectical method, or by finding out the metaphysical causes to physical economic effects, as used by David Hume and Adam Smith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Timeline of Economic Crises</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/timeline-of-crises/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/timeline-of-crises/</guid>
      <description>Year Event     235-284 AD Crisis of the Third Century   1544–1551 The Great Debasement   1621–1623 Kipper und Wipper   1637 Tulip mania crash   1720 South Sea bubble crash   1720 Mississippi bubble crash   1763 Amsterdam banking crisis   1769–1784 Bengal bubble crash   1772 Crisis of 1772   1780–1795 Dutch Republic financial collapse   1785 Panic of 1785   1789 Copper Panic of 1789   1792 Panic   1796–1797 Panic   1813 Danish state bankruptcy   1815–1816 Post-Napoleonic Irish grain price and land use shocks   1819 Panic   1825 Panic   1837 Panic   1845–1856 European Potato Failure    Great Irish Famine   1847 Panic   1857 Panic   1866 Panic   1869 Black Friday   1873 Panic   1882 Paris Bourse crash   1884 Panic   1886 Arendal crash   1890 Baring crisis   1890–1893 Encilhamento   1893 Panic   1893 Australian banking crisis   1894 Black Monday   1896 Panic   1901 Panic   1907 Panic   1907 Panic   1910 Shanghai rubber stock market crisis   1910–11 Panic   1917–1924 Early Soviet hyperinflation   1921–1923 Weimar Republic hyperinflation   1927 Shōwa financial crisis   1929 Wall Street Crash   1973 Oil crisis   1973–1974 Stock market crash   1973–1982 Steel crisis   1973–1975 Secondary banking crisis   1975–1982 Latin American debt crisis   1976 British sterling crisis   1979 Oil crisis   1980–1994 Brazilian hyperinflation   1982 Chilean crisis   1983 Black Saturday   1986–1995 Savings and loan crisis   1987 Black Monday   1988–1992 Norwegian banking crisis   1990–1992 Japanese asset price bubble crash   1991 Indian economic crisis   1991–1992 Swedish financial crisis   1992-1993 Finnish banking crisis   1992 Black Wednesday   1992–1994 Yugoslav hyperinflation   1992–1994 Yugoslav hyperinflation   1994 Bond market crisis   1994 Venezuelan banking crisis   1994–1996 Mexican peso crisis   1997 Asian financial crisis   1998 1998 Russian financial crisis   1998–99 Ecuador financial crisis   2000–2004 Dot-com bubble crash   2001 Turkish economic crisis   2002 South American economic crisis   2002 Uruguay banking crisis   2003 Myanmar banking crisis   2004 Argentine energy crisis   2007 Chinese stock bubble crash   2007– Zimbabwean hyperinflation   2007–2008 Global Financial crisis     2008 Latvian financial crisis 2008–2009 Belgian financial crisis 2008–09 Russian financial crisis 2008–2009 Ukrainian financial crisis 2008–2011 Icelandic financial crisis 2008–2011 Irish banking crisis 2008–2014 Spanish financial crisis</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Timeline of Economic Thought</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/timeline-of-economic-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/timeline-of-economic-thought/</guid>
      <description>The differences in the economic philosophies of different time periods can be attributed to the main ideas or mentalities prevalent during those times, as the effect of new experiences or &amp;lsquo;impressions&amp;rsquo; on the mind. We chronologically list the main events that may have caused people to have those new experiences from which they developed new ideas.
Proto-mercantile: The Rise Of The Merchants (1204-1420) The Venetians give Europe the first taste of commerce and manufactures |</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Smith&#39;s Four Taxation Maxims</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/adam-smith-taxation-maxims/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/adam-smith-taxation-maxims/</guid>
      <description>Adam Smith gave four maxims on taxation in The Wealth of Nations that have been largely forgotten today. Taxes should be fair, non-arbitrary, cost-effective and convenient.
1: People should contribute towards supporting their government in proportion to their respective abilities The rich or those who have the ability topay more should pay more than those who are less able to. Smith&amp;rsquo;s pro-poor taxation policies are found in Book 5, Chapter 2, and are as clear as day:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Smith&#39;s Mistake in the Wealth of Nations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/adam-smith-mistake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/adam-smith-mistake/</guid>
      <description>Adam Smith wrote the Wealth of Nations as an attack on Mercantilism which has since evolved into Neoclassical Economics. Despite his attack, it&amp;rsquo;s very strange for him to entrust an entire country&amp;rsquo;s external trade to foreign merchants:
If the society has insufficient capital to cultivate all its lands and to completely process all its rude produce, there is even a big advantage that its rude produce should be exported by a foreign capital.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backward vs Advanced Society</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/backward-vs-advanced/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/backward-vs-advanced/</guid>
      <description>Adam Smith classified the mentality of societies as either savage, barbaric, or advanced. He classified their economic state as either backward, stagnating, or advancing.
He called savage and barbaric ones as rude:
A rude society has more variety in individual occupations. but less variety when all occupations are taken together. Every man does almost everything which any other man does. Every man has a considerable degree of knowledge, ingenuity, and invention, but no one has a great degree of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barter Disadvantages Addressed</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/barter-disadvantages-addressed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/barter-disadvantages-addressed/</guid>
      <description>The following are the common disadvantages of barter:
Lack of Double Coincidence of Wants Persons must have matching requirements for barter to work
Our Response This is only true for bilateral barter or trade involving two persons. Smith&amp;rsquo;s system is multilateral wherein trade is circular and not direct.
The following workmen are necessary to make the shears used to clip the wool to make the coat: The miner, builder of the furnace for smelting the ore, The feller of the timber, The burner of the charcoal used in the smelting-house, The brick-maker and the brick-layer, The workers who attend the furnace The mill-wright, forger, and smith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to be a Wealthy Country</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/how-to-be-a-wealthy-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/how-to-be-a-wealthy-country/</guid>
      <description>According to Adam Smith, there are three basic factors needed to be a major economic power:
 The people must have a good moral system The people must not be stupid The country must have access to the ocean  A fourth optional factor would be having natural resources.
Economic power is in the value that a society creates. This produced value is transmitted through exchange which is facilitated by morals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import Substitution versus Export Promotion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/import-substitution-vs-export-promotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/import-substitution-vs-export-promotion/</guid>
      <description>Import substitution is an economic policy that replaces imports with local manufactures. It was popularized by Argentina in the 1970&amp;rsquo;s and subsequently spread around the world. Its main goal is to lower a country’s expenses.
Adam Smith would categorize it as a policy by poor and austere societies:
In every civilized society which has the distinction of ranks, there were always two systems of morality: the strict or austere which is generally admired and revered by the common people, and the liberal or loose system which is commonly adopted by people of fashion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kinds of Three Trades</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/three-kinds-of-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/three-kinds-of-trade/</guid>
      <description>Adam Smith gave three kinds of trades:
1. Local or Home Trade This is the trade done within a nation&amp;rsquo;s borders. This generally supports the most people. Ancient and Medieval China was able to sustain itself with local trade alone.
2. Direct Foreign Trade 3. Indirect or Roundabout Foreign Trade Of course, no country can do everything by itself, that’s why Smith wrote:
The most round-about foreign trade of consumption therefore may be as necessary as the most direct foreign trade in terms of supporting the productive labour of the country and the value of its produce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Adam Smith would be against Brexit</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/brexit-adam-smith/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/brexit-adam-smith/</guid>
      <description>Adam Smith would be against Brexit because the European Union (EU)is an internal free trade zone and Britain derives a lot of benefits from it.
However, this does not mean that Smith would be pro-EU, because while there is free trade within it, there are oppressive regulations and subsidies that make it hard for outsiders and outside trade to penetrate fortress Europe.
Rather, Smith would be for a World Union (WU) where all countries have free trade and immigration with each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do humans need and use money?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/why-humans-need-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/why-humans-need-money/</guid>
      <description>While building our alternative economic system, we experimented with different features and models. We tried social ecommerce, barter, ecommerce with barter, moneyless gift system, timebanking, moneyless with ecommerce, and finally moneyless with ecommerce and barter.
Barter and moneyless is feasible but only for the small scale. We realized that the new system still needed money simply because it would be very difficult to mitigate the risk with long-distance barter and poits transactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Inflation and Deflation?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/inflation-deflation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/inflation-deflation/</guid>
      <description>The Four Laws of Value explained the metaphysics of value and why a pantrynomy&amp;rsquo;s* goal is zero inflation.
 *An economy within the tao
 Economics shallowly defines &amp;lsquo;inflation&amp;rsquo; as a rise in prices, and &amp;lsquo;deflation&amp;rsquo; as its decline. This definition obviously does not hold because Japan has been in deflation for a long time and yet its prices, such as rent and consumer prices, remain high.
What really &amp;lsquo;deflated&amp;rsquo; was economic activity, arising from Japan&amp;rsquo;s declining population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/dcti-scenarios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/dcti-scenarios/</guid>
      <description>Hunter-Gatherer Scenario
Figure 1. A single hunter who consumes all the work of his industry
This scenario illustrates the Value-Trade Theory in the simplest form without trade. To meet the hunger (demand) of the hunter, he must gather his equipment and skill (capital) to hunt an animal (industry), which he will consume to satisfy his hunger.
consciousness http://humanityframework.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/cognition.gif
Advancing Society Scenario
Figure 2. A simple scenario illustrating how societies with fixed capital (light blue and light green &amp;ndash; skill, equipment, division of labor, etc) augments circulating capital (dark blue &amp;ndash; raw materials, finished products, money) in order to create wealth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/how-to-prevent-stagnation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/how-to-prevent-stagnation/</guid>
      <description>how to prevent stagnation
&amp;ldquo;In a country fully peopled.. the competition for employment would necessarily be so great as to reduce the wages of labour to what was barely sufficient to keep up the number of labourers, and, the country being already fully peopled, that number could never be augmented. In a country fully stocked in proportion to all the business it had to transact, as great a quantity of stock would be employed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining Rent, Wages, Profits, and Donations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/defining-rent-wages-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/defining-rent-wages-profit/</guid>
      <description>An important feature of Smith&amp;rsquo;s Political Economy (and the science of Pantrynomics which we created from it) is the classification ofall revenue into either rent, wages, and profit.
Such classification is not so important to Economics which focuses on the quantity or dollar value of revenue instead of its quality. This classification is difficult nowadays when other kinds of revenue have been introduced, such as interest income, different kinds of taxes, royalties, revenue from membership fees, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Competition</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/free-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/free-competition/</guid>
      <description>Free competition does not mean the competitors need to be equal. Instead, the freedom of each competitor needs to be guaranteed by the government. For example, the competitors in a beauty contest might not be equal in height, weight, skin color, or hair length, etc. Nevertheless, their freedom to be in the competition, to wear their costumes, show their skills, answer questions, should be guaranteed by the organizers.
This guarantee of freedom in commercial competition was removed by French economist JB Say through the concept of laissez faire from the Physiocrats which he corrupted to mean total deregulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Economic Karma?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/economic-karma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/pantrynomics/economic-karma/</guid>
      <description>The previous post pointed out that Smith was one of the few Western intellectuals to hint at the concept of dharma, or the natural and sustainable activities of humans, and apply it both for moral and economic purporses.
Instead of the word dharma, however, he named his concept the invisible hand. This had economic applications in The Wealth of Nations and moral applications in The Theory of Moral Sentiments.
Weaponizing the Invisible Hand The main difference between Smith&amp;rsquo;s invisible hand and Eastern dharma is that the former has moral, spiritual, and practical uses, while the latter emphasizes only its moral and spiritual use.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
