<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 3 on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 3 on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Definitions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/definitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/definitions/</guid>
      <description>Defintions of the emotions  Desire is the actual essence of man, in so far as it is conceived, as determined to a particular activity by some given modification of itself.   Pleasure is the transition of a man from a less to a greater perfection.
  Pain is the transition of a man from a greater to a less perfection.
  Wonder is the conception of anything, wherein the mind comes to a stand, because the particular concept in question has no connection with other concepts (cf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 1 to 8</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/propositions-1-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/propositions-1-8/</guid>
      <description>Postulates  The human body can be affected in many ways which increases or reduces its power of activity. It can also be affected in other ways which do not change this power.  Note: This postulate or axiom rests on Postulate 1 and Lemmas 5 and 7, which is after 2.13. The human body can undergo many changes.
Nevertheless, it can retain:
 the impressions or traces of objects (cf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 15 to 24</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/propositions-15-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/propositions-15-24/</guid>
      <description>Anything can, accidentally, be the cause of pleasure, pain, or desire. Proof: Let it be granted that the mind is simultaneously affected by two emotions, of which one neither increases nor diminishes its power of activity, and the other does either increase or reduce the said power (3. Post. 1).  Corollary: Simply from the fact that we have regarded a thing with the emotion of pleasure or pain, though that thing be not the efficient cause of the emotion, we can either love or hate it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 25 to 31</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/propositions-25-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/propositions-25-31/</guid>
      <description>We endeavour to affirm, concerning ourselves, and concerning what we love, everything that we can conceive to affect pleasurably ourselves, or the loved object. On the contrary, we endeavour to negative everything, which we conceive to affect painfully ourselves or the loved object.  We endeavour to affirm, concerning that which we hate, everything which we conceive to affect it painfully. Contrariwise, we endeavour to deny, concerning it, everything which we conceive to affect it pleasurably.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 33 to 37</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/propositions-33-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/propositions-33-37/</guid>
      <description>When we love a thing similar to ourselves we endeavour, as far as we can, to bring about that it should love us in return.  The greater the emotion with which we conceive a loved object to be affected towards us, the greater will be our complacency.  If anyone conceives, that an object of his love joins itself to another with closer bonds of friendship than he himself has attained to, he will be affected with hatred towards the loved object and with envy towards his rival.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 38 to 52</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/propositions-38-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/propositions-38-52/</guid>
      <description>If a man has begun to hate an object of his love, so that love is thoroughly destroyed, he will, causes being equal, regard it with more hatred than if he had never loved it, and his hatred will be in proportion to the strength of his former love. Proof: If a man begins to hate that which he had loved, more of his appetites are put under restraint than if he had never loved it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 53 to 59</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/propositions-53-59/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/propositions-53-59/</guid>
      <description>When the mind regards itself and its own power of activity, it feels pleasure: and that pleasure is greater in proportion to the distinctness wherewith it conceives itself and its own power of activity.  The mind endeavours to conceive only such things as assert its power of activity.  When the mind contemplates its own weakness, it feels pain thereat.  Corollary: This pain is more and more fostered, if a man conceives that he is blamed by others; this may be proved in the same way as the corollary to 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propositions 9 to 14</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/propositions-9-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/spinoza/simple-ethics/part-3/propositions-9-14/</guid>
      <description>The mind, both in so far as it has clear and distinct ideas, and also in so far as it has confused ideas, endeavours to persist in its being for an indefinite period, and of this endeavour it is conscious.  An idea, which excludes the existence of our body, cannot be postulated in our mind, but is contrary thereto.  Whatsoever increases or diminishes, helps or hinders the power of activity in our body, the idea thereof increases or diminishes, helps or hinders the power of thought in our mind.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
