<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Material Superphysics on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/material/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Material Superphysics on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/articles/material/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aether</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/material/aether/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/material/aether/</guid>
      <description>The aether is the highest layer in the universe. It holds crosses existence and covers up pre-existence. You can think of it as the mind of Brahma or the RAM of a computer that generates its own virtual reality.
It manifests as the Higgs Field in Physics. A unit example is a human mind.
In terms of creation, this layer is the first layer that precedes physical manifestation.
   Name Traditional Name Force Particle Quantum     Material Earth Strong Gluon Quantum of matter or Qom    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Qosts Can Make Fusion a Reality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/material/fusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/material/fusion/</guid>
      <description>The previous post explained the concept of Qosts or the quantum of space time. These are points in spacetime that gather energy to create mass in order to create discrete things. These create spacetime by their mutual repulsion and, thus, are essential in levitation and teleportation.
  These can also be employed to harness energy, as opposed to creating it, in two ways:
  By tapping into the repulsion of qosts that lead to the accelerated expansion of space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiant</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/material/radiant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/material/radiant/</guid>
      <description>The radiant layer is the third layer in the universe. It manifests as energies that spread out in space at the speed limit of spacetime (known to physics as the speed of light).
It manifests as light, magnetism, and electricity.
In terms of creation, this layer is the third layer that spreads across the space created by the spacetime layer.
   Name Traditional Name Force Particle Quantum     Radiant Fire Electromagentism Electron, Photon, etc Quantum of electricity or Qoe, Quantum of light or Qol    Unlike the spacetime layer that has a very large space of influence, this layer has a limited space to influence, which manifests as &amp;lsquo;fields&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radioactive</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/material/radioactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/material/radioactive/</guid>
      <description>The radioactive layer is the fourth layer in the universe. It downgrades the radiant energies and particles into material ones.
It manifests as radioactivity
In terms of creation, this is the fourth layer that processes energies and matter into other kinds
   Name Traditional Name Force Particle Quantum     Radioactive Water Weak W Z Bosons Quantum of radioactivity or Qor    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Material</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/material/material/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/material/material/</guid>
      <description>The material layer is the lowest layer in the universe and manifests as physical objects. A unit example is a rock.In terms of creation, this layer is the final layer in the journey of dynamic energy and entropy towards stasis and is where mind is at its most dormant state.
   Name Traditional Name Force Particle Quantum     Material Earth Strong Gluon Quantum of matter or Qom    The conversion from dormant mind into active mind then takes place in stars.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
