<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Superphysics on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Superphysics on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is Superphysics?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/what-is-superphysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/what-is-superphysics/</guid>
      <description>From the time of Descartes to Kant, philosophy dominated the study of human knowledge in the West. It included metaphysics and was only countered by religion.
Science was then called Natural Philosophy which dealt with natural physical phenomena in line with metaphysical principles. For example, Newton&amp;rsquo;s Principia cited God as the source of nature&amp;rsquo;s movements.
But by the 19th century, the Europeans separated Natural Philosophy from Philosophy. It mutated into materialist science which was totally separate from metaphysics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Red Herring, Ad hominem, and Other Fallacies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/red-herring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/red-herring/</guid>
      <description>People sometimes use strange jargon like “red herring” or ‘Occam’s razor” when they try to disprove arguments that they don’t like. Such words then force the other side to do research on what those jargon mean. This can potentially waste a lot of time since there are a lot of fallacies. These fallacies were merely created by academics for the sake of creating something, just as mathematicians create paradoxes, and theoretical physicists create useless theories because thinking is part of their job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Qualimath?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/what-is-qualimath/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/what-is-qualimath/</guid>
      <description>Waves need linear algebra to notate and compute. However, jumping directly into linear algebra might be too complicated for most people. For example, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be so easy for most people to understand the video below:
  The problem is that pure math is quantitative in nature and not qualitative. Because of this, everything has to be defined beforehand. For example, in the video, Maxwell’s equation is given as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI is Autonomous Intelligence, Not Artificial</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/ai-is-autonomous/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/ai-is-autonomous/</guid>
      <description>The tech world was abuzz with the word artificial intelligence or AI in 2016 after Google released Tensorflow in late 2015.
AI is a big field which includes machine learning and data mining. Many startup companies market themselves as being AI-based. Most of the time, they just use a machine learning algorithm to produce different outputs which might not be useful.
What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with artificial? The problem is that intelligence is merely the ability to connect ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feelings vs Sentiments vs Emotions vs Sensations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/feelings-sentiments-emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/feelings-sentiments-emotions/</guid>
      <description>While simplifying Adam Smith&amp;rsquo;s Theory of Moral Sentiments, I had to think a lot whether to change &amp;lsquo;sentiments&amp;rsquo; into &amp;lsquo;feelings&amp;rsquo; especially since the latter is nowadays more commonly used than the former.
Feelings vs Sentiments &amp;lsquo;Sentiment&amp;rsquo; is Latin for feeling.
&amp;lsquo;Feeling&amp;rsquo; is Old English for the ability of the heart to perceive, as opposed to:
 &amp;lsquo;sight&amp;rsquo;, the ability of the eye &amp;lsquo;think&amp;rsquo;, the ability of the brain &amp;lsquo;hearing&amp;rsquo;, the ability of the ear  Thus, &amp;lsquo;sentiment&amp;rsquo;, being Latin, is merely more formal and scientific than &amp;lsquo;feelings&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kant versus Hume</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/kant-versus-hume/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/kant-versus-hume/</guid>
      <description>Hume was very much against shallow, unenlightened philosophers who wrote a lot of nonsense.
Kant is one such philosopher.
Hume already said that there was no such thing as a priori knowledge, but Kant refuted this by saying some were a priori. In reality, Kant was referring to belief and not knowledge.
Major Difference 1: A Priori; Belief Versus Knowledge There are a priori beliefs that you do not know where it came from (like why Person 1 likes chocolate instead of crisps, but Person 2 likes crisps instead of chocolate)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moral Consequentialism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/moral-consequentialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/moral-consequentialism/</guid>
      <description>Our proposed moral system, derived from Adam Smith, David Hume, and Socrates, is based on a clear definition of morality as happiness for the most entities possible for the longest time possible.
The &amp;ldquo;most entities possible&amp;rdquo; encompasses moral space, while &amp;ldquo;for the longest time possible&amp;rdquo; encompasses moral time. The end goal of maximizing moral space and time, by specifying &amp;ldquo;most&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;longest&amp;rdquo;, is the attainment of the state of peace. This ultimate state then answers the purpose of creation and closes the loop of existence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;God&#39; is Existence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/god-is-existence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/god-is-existence/</guid>
      <description>The question &amp;lsquo;Does God exist?&amp;rsquo; can be answered by &amp;lsquo;Can you perceive Existence?&amp;rsquo;.
Earlier, we said that:
 every physical perception has a metaphysical idea-equivalent each idea produces an opposite idea: beauty has ugliness, health has disease a mind is an arena to experience such perceptions and ideas  So where does our idea of God come from?
The human mind naturally creates the idea of God to have an extremely positive counterweight to extremely negative perceptions such as typhoons, life, death, wealth, goodness, evil, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything is an Idea and a Mind</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/everything-is-an-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/everything-is-an-idea/</guid>
      <description>The previous post explained that the Creator of the universe created the universe from Its Own metaphysical ideas and feelings, just as a novelist writes a novel from a stream of ideas and feelings coming from his metaphysical mind.
The purpose of ideas is to create experience. However, experience can only exist if there is an experiencer. Thus, there are only two things in this &amp;lsquo;matrix&amp;rsquo; of Existence:
 the experiencer the experience of ideas and feelings  Before existence began, the Absolute Creator had nothing to create those experiencer and experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Consciousness?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/what-is-consciousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/what-is-consciousness/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, we explained that there are only two things in Existence:
 experience experiencer  Then we said that a mind is a piece of the Experiencer where It does the experiencing.
Here we add that the Experiencer itself is called Consciousness which resides in the arena of the mind. Thus, consciousness and mind go together. An active mind always has consciousness, but a consciousness does not always have an active mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ideology Matrix</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/ideology-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/ideology-matrix/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people confuse socialism, left wing, democracy, and communism with each other. This is because ideas from one generation are commonly usurped by later generations according to their different experiences, rather than creating new names for new ideas arising from those new experiences.
A modern day example is the mobile phone and smartphone. A mobile phone means mobile telephone. When computer-abilities were added to it, it became a ‘smartphone’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Socratic Dialectics?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/socratic-dialectics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/socratic-dialectics/</guid>
      <description>The Dialectics of Socrates, or David Hume&amp;rsquo;s science of man, is a system of analysis based on the metaphysical nature or dharma or tao of anything that exists in reality, with the goal of solving real problems in order to keep up with that nature, dharma, or tao.
Socrates calls this dharma or tao as the first principle or true nature of anything.
Dialectic alone goes directly to the first principle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re in a Matrix!</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/we-are-in-a-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/superphysics/we-are-in-a-matrix/</guid>
      <description>We know the existence of thing through our perceptions of it. Each perception has two aspects:
 physical metaphysical  For example, when we see a mug, we have both the physical perception of a mug and a metaphysical idea of a mug nearly at the same time.
This means that the mug exists in two layers of reality:
 the physical mug exists in physical reality, which we see the metaphysical mug exists in &amp;lsquo;metaphysical reality&amp;rsquo;, as our idea of what a mug is  Sometimes, we perceive something totally new.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
