<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Relation of Taxation To Liberty on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Relation of Taxation To Liberty on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How the Deception is preserved</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>IN order to make the purchaser confound the price of the commodity with the tax, there must be some proportion between the tax and the value of the commodity. This is why there shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be an excessive duty on cheap merchandise.
In some countries, the duty exceeds 18 times the value of the commodity. In this case, the prince removes the disguise. His subjects plainly see they are dealt with unreasonably.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is tax farming or commission better?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>THE managing of the revenues by commission is like the conduct of a good father of a family, who collects his own rents himself with economy and order. It:
 allows the prince to press or retard the levy of the taxes, either according to his own wants or to those of his people saves the state the immense profits of tax collectors [tax farmers], who impoverish it a thousand ways lets the prince prevent the people from being mortified with the sight of sudden fortunes lets the public money pass through few hands, go directly to the treasury, and consequently makes a quicker return to the people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relation between the Weight of Taxes and Liberty</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>IT is a general rule that taxes:
 can be higher the more liberty a person has, and should be lower the more enslaved a person is.  This has always been and always will be the case. It is a rule derived from nature that never varies.
We find it in all parts, in England, in Holland, and in every state where liberty gradually declines, till we come to Turkey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxes in Countries where Part of the People are Villains or Bondmen</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>THE state of villainage is sometimes established after a conquest. In that case the bondman or villain that tills the land ought to have a kind of partnership with his master. Nothing but a communication of loss or profit can reconcile those who are doomed to labour to such as are blessed with a state of affluence.
Chapter 4: A Republic in the like Case WHEN a republic has reduced a nation to the drudgery of cultivating her lands, she ought never to suffer the free subject to have a power of increasing the tribute of the bondman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Abuse of Liberty, Muslim Conquest</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>The great advantages of liberty causes that liberty itself to be abused.
 A moderate government produces admirable effects and so this moderation is laid aside A moderate government produces great taxes, and so they want raise even more They received such gifts from liberty, but they go to slavery who never gives such  Liberty produces high tax revenues The effect of high tax revenues is slavery Slavery reduces tax revenues    The eastern monarchs exempt every year some of their provinces from paying tribute as a favour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Muslim Conquest and Tax Exemption</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>This excess of taxes helped the Muslims carry on their conquests.
 The people were subjected to a simple tribute, paid and collected with ease. They were far happier in obeying a barbarous nation than a corrupt government that enslaved them.  Chapter 17: Troop Increase The Muslim conquest induced our princes to keep up an exorbitant number of troops. As soon as one prince augments his forces, the others do the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Public Revenues</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-13/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>THE public revenues are a portion that each subject gives of his property, in order to secure or enjoy the remainder.
To fix these revenues properly, the necessities of the state and those of the subject should be considered.
Imaginary wants are those which flow from the passions and the weakness of the governors. This arises from:
 the vain conceit of some extraordinary project, the inordinate desire of glory, a certain impotence of mind incapable of withstanding the impulse of fancy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
