<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 3 on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 3 on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Suicide</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/9-suicide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/9-suicide/</guid>
      <description>Philosophy is the sovereign antidote to superstition and false religion. Plain good-sense and the practice of the world can serve most purposes of life, but are ineffective against them.Both history and daily experience has instances of capable men who are enslaved by the grossest superstition.
Even gaiety and sweetness of temper afford no remedy to so virulent a poison. Women often feel many of their joys blasted by this importunate intruder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Immortality Of The Soul</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/10-immortality-of-the-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/10-immortality-of-the-soul/</guid>
      <description>It is difficult to prove the Immortality of the Soul by reason alone. The arguments for it are derived from metaphysical, moral, or physical topics. But in reality, it is the gospel alone that has brought life and immortality to light.
 Metaphysical topics are founded on the supposition that the soul is immaterial, and that it is impossible for thought to belong to a material substance.  But just metaphysics teach us:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avarice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/7-avarice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/7-avarice/</guid>
      <description>Comic writers exaggerate every character. This moral kind of painting for the stage has been often compared to the painting for cupolas and cielings, where the colours are over-charged, and every part is drawn excessively large, and beyond nature. The figures seem monstrous and disproportioned, when seen too nigh;
but become natural and regular, when set at a distance, and placed in that point of view, in which they are intended to be surveyed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Study of History</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/6-study-of-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/6-study-of-history/</guid>
      <description>I fully recommend the study of history as an occupation to my female readers. It is:
 the best suited to their sex and education much more instructive than their ordinary books of amusement more entertaining than those serious compositions in their closets  History can teach them two important truths that can give them peace:
 Both sexes are far from being such perfect creatures The male-world is not only governed by love, but is often overcome by avarice, ambition, vanity, and a thousand other passions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love And Marriage</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/5-love-marriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/5-love-marriage/</guid>
      <description>Why do women complain so much about everything that goes wrong in a marriage? Do they mean, that they are the parties principally concerned, and that if a backwardness to enter into that state should prevail in the world, they would be the greatest sufferers?
Or, are they sensible, that the misfortunes and miscarriages of the married state are owing more to their sex than to ours?
I hope they do not intend to confess either of these two particulars, or to give such an advantage to their adversaries, the men, as even to allow them to suspect it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impudence and Modesty</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/4-impudence-modesty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/4-impudence-modesty/</guid>
      <description>The common complaints against Providence are ill-grounded.
Good or bad fortune is caused by the good or bad qualities of people. There are many instances to the contrary. But these are few, relative to the actual distribution of prosperity and adversity and to the common course of human affairs.
We will get love and esteem if we have benevolence and love. This is the chief circumstance in life. It facilitates every enterprize and undertaking besides the satisfaction, which immediately results from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Middle Station Of Life</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/3-the-middle-station-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/3-the-middle-station-of-life/</guid>
      <description>The Moral of the following Fable will easily discover itself, without my explaining it.
One Rivulet met another, who had been long united in strictest Amity. He said Haughtily:
“What, Brother! Still in the same State? Still low and creeping? I have become a great river able to rival the Danube or the Rhine if the friendly Rains continue. Those rains have favour’d my Banks, but neglected yours. Are you not ashamed when you see me?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moral Prejudice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/2-moral-prejudice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/2-moral-prejudice/</guid>
      <description>Some men try to distinguish themselves by ridiculing everything that was sacred and venerable to mankind.
They rail against Reason, Sobriety, Honour, Friendship, Marriage perpetually. They even regard public spirit and nationalism as fake.
If the schemes of these anti-reformers were to be implemented, the bonds of society will break. and make way for licentious mirth and gaiety.
 Drunken frollics would be preferred to friendship. Dissolute prodigality would drain away every valuable thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay Writing</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/1-essay-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/hume/essays/part-3/1-essay-writing/</guid>
      <description>The elegant people who are not immersed in the animal Life, employ themselves in the Operations of the Mind. They may be divided into:
 the learned
 These have chosen the higher and more difficult Operations of the Mind, which require Leisure and Solitude, and cannot be brought to Perfection, without long Preparation and severe Labour.
 the conversible
 These join to
 a sociable disposition, and a taste of pleasure, an inclination to the easier and more gentle exercises of the understanding,  with</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
