<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Principles Of Despotism, Monarchy, Republic on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Principles Of Despotism, Monarchy, Republic on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Honour in a Despotism, Principles of Despotism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-3/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-3/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>Honour is not the Principle of a despotic Government.
In a despotism, mankind is all equal no one person can prefer himself to another
Yet, they are all slaves, they can give themselves no sort of preference., as honour has its laws and rules; as it knows not how to submit; as it depends, in a great measure, on a man’s own caprice, and not on that of another person;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Laws from the Nature of Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-3/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-3/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>A monarchical or despotic government does not need the support of probity. The force of laws and the prince’s arm are sufficient to maintain the whole. But in a popular state, virtue is necessary. This is confirmed unanimously by historians and is extremely agreeable to the nature of things.
A leader of a popular government needs virtue more than a monarch who can execute the laws by himself. A monarch can fix his mistakes by himself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtue in a Monarchy, Principle of a Monarchy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-3/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-3/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 5: Virtue is not the Principle of a monarchical Government Monarchies, policy effects great things with as little virtue as possible.
Thus, in the nicest machines, art has reduced the number of movements, springs, and wheels.state subsists independently of the love of our country, of the thirst of true glory, of self-denial, of the sacrifice of our dearest interests, and of all those heroic virtues which we admire in the ancients, and to us are known only by story.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
