<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 3-Economic Development on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 3-Economic Development on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dynasties and the Development of Europe</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-4c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-4c/</guid>
      <description>16 I cannot help remarking, that very old families are very rare in commercial countries.
Such are families which have possessed some large estate from father to son for many generations. In countries which have little commerce, such as Wales or the Scottish highlands on the contrary, they are very common. The Arabian histories seem to be all full of genealogies. There is a history written by a Mongol Khan which contains nothing else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Free Cities to Independent Republics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-3b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-3b/</guid>
      <description>The Weakness of the King (Conservatives) Led to the Rise of the Free Traders (Liberals) 9 The kings who hated their barons gave the most liberal grants to their burghs.
For example, King John of England was a most munificent benefactor to his towns.
Philip 1st of France lost all authority over his barons.
 Louis 6th was the son of Philip 1st  According to Father Daniel, towards the end of the reign of Philip 1st, Louis 6th consulted with the bishops on how to restrain the great lords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Commerce of the Towns Improved the Countryside</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>The Benefits of Trade and Manufactures 1 The increase and riches of commercial and manufacturing towns contributed to the improvement and cultivation of their countries in three ways.
2 They afforded a great and ready market for the country&#39;s rude produce. This benefit extended to all the countries they dealt with. To those other countries, those towns afforded a market for their rude or manufactured produce. They encouraged the industry and improvement of all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metayers and Sharecropping</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-2b/</guid>
      <description>11 A species of farmers known as Metayers in France gradually succeeded the ancient slaves.
They are called Coloni Partiarii in Latin. They were so long in disuse in England that I know no English name for them at present. The proprietor furnished them with the whole stock needed for cultivating the farm. After setting aside what was necessary for keeping up the stock, the produce was divided equally between the proprietor and the farmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Development of European manufacturing</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-3c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-3c/</guid>
      <description>16 A taste for the finer and more improved manufactures was introduced by foreign commerce into countries which had no such works.
When this taste created a big demand, the merchants naturally tried to establish the same manufactures in their own country to save transportation costs. Hence, the origin of the first manufactures for distant sale that were established in Western Europe after the fall of the Roman empire. No large country ever did or could subsist without some manufacturing industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Discouragement of Agriculture after the Fall of the Roman Empire</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Engrossing of Land through the Law of Primogeniture and Entails 1 The confusions which followed the defeat of the Western Roman empire defeat to the Germans and Scythians lasted for many centuries.
The violence interrupted the commerce between the towns and the countryside. The towns were deserted and the countryside was left uncultivated. Western Europe, which enjoyed opulence under the Roman empire, sunk into the lowest state of poverty and barbarism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin of Feudalism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-4b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-4b/</guid>
      <description>7 The power of the ancient barons was founded on the great proprietors&#39; authority over their tenants and retainers.
 They became the judges in peace and the leaders in war of all who dwelt on their estates. They could maintain order and execute the law within their respective demesnes.  Each of them could turn the whole force of the people against the injustice of anyone.
No other persons had sufficient authority to do this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of Cities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>The Origin of Free-Traders 1 After the fall of the Roman empire, the people of cities and towns were not more favoured than those of the countryside. They were very different from the first inhabitants of the ancient Greek and Italian republics.
Those of Greece and Italy were composed chiefly of the proprietors of lands. They built their houses near each other with a wall for common defence.
After the fall of the Roman empire, those proprietors lived in castles on their own estates in the midst of their own tenants and dependants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Natural Progress of Opulence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-3/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>The Trade Between the Towns and the Countryside 1 The great commerce of every civilized society is the one done between the people of the town and those of the countryside.
It consists in the exchange of rude for manufactured produce either immediately as barter, or with money or some paper which represents money. The countryside supplies the town with food and raw materials.
The town repays this supply by sending back manufactured products.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
