<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Laws That Form Political Liberty, As Relative To The Subject on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Laws That Form Political Liberty, As Relative To The Subject on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How dangerous it is, in Republ= ics, to be too severe in punishing the Crime of High-Treason</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>AS soon as a republic has compassed the = destruction of those who wanted to subvert it, there should be an end of te= rrors, punishments, and even of rewards.
Great punishments, and consequently grea= t changes, cannot take place without investing some citizens with an exorbi= tant power. It is therefore more adviseable, in this case, to exceed in len= ity, than in severity; to banish but few, rather than many; and to leave th= em their estates, instead of making a vast number of confiscations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liberty is favoured by the Nature and Proportion of Punishments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>LIBERTY is in its highest perfection whe= n criminal laws derive each punishment from the particular nature of the cr= ime. There are then no arbitrary decisions; the punishment does not flow fr= om the capriciousness of the legislator, but from the Edition: current; Page: [243] very nature of the = thing; and man uses no violence to man.
There are four sorts of crimes. Those of= the first species are prejudicial to religion; the second, to morals; the = third, to the public tranquility; and the fourth, to the security of the su= bject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Crime against Nature</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>GOD forbid that I should have the least = inclination to diminish the public horror against a crime which religion, m= orality, and civil government, equally condemn. It ought to be proscribed w= ere it only for its communicating to one sex the weaknesses of the other, a= nd for leading people, by a scandalous prostitution of their youth, to an i= gnominious old age. What I shall say concerning it will no ways diminish it= s infamy, being levelled only against the tyranny that may abuse the very h= orror we ought to have against the vice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Liberty of the Subject</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>IT is not sufficient to have treated of = political liberty as relative to the constitution; we must examine it likew= ise in the relation it bears to the subject.
We have observed, that, in the former ca= se, it arises from a certain distribution of the three powers; but, in the = latter, we must consider it in another light. It consists in security, or i= n the opinion people have of their security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Manner of governing in Monarchies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/chapter-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/chapter-25/</guid>
      <description>THE royal authority is a spring that oug= ht to move with the greatest freedom and ease. The Chinese boast of one of = their emperors, who governed, they say, like the heavens; that is, by his example.
There are some cases in which a sovereig= n ought to exert the full extent of his power, and others in which he shoul= d reduce it within narrower limits. The sublimity of administration consist= s in knowing the proper degree of power which should be exerted on differen= t occasions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things that strike at Liberty in Monarchies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>LIBERTY often has been weakened in monar= chies by a thing of the least use in the world to Edition: current; Page: [266] the prince: this is the= naming of commissioners to try a private person.
The prince himself derives so very littl= e advantage from those commissioners, that it is not worth while to change,= for their sake, the common course of things. He is morally sure that he ha= s more of the spirit of probity and justice than his commissioners, who thi= nk themselves sufficiently justified by his nomination and orders, by a vag= ue interest of state, and even by their very apprehensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-12/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>MARSYAS dreamt that he had cut Dionysius&amp;rsquo;s throat. Dionysius put him to death, pretending that = he would never have dreamt of such a thing by night if he had not thought o= f it by day. This was a most tyrannical action; for, though it had been t= he subject of his thoughts, yet he had made no attempt towards it. The laws do not take = upon them to punish any other than overt acts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
