<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>England&#39;s Treasure on Foreign Trade on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in England&#39;s Treasure on Foreign Trade on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Allowing Foreign Coins to enter at higher rates relative to our Standard will not Increase our Treasure</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>The discreet Merchant [trade financer] carefully learns the value of the foreign money that he receives according to their weight and fineness compared to ours. This will help him know his profits or losses.
We sell our valuable goods to diverse places that have nothing useful to sell to us. That&amp;rsquo;s why we require payment in ready money. We then use this money to buy the useful goods of other Countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion on Foreign Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>As a summary, the rule in our forraign trade is that:
 our coin is undervalued in the foreign exchange in a country where our exports are less than the value of our imports from that country our coin is overvalued in the foreign exchange in a country where our exports are more than the value of our imports from that country  The foreign exchange for trade financing has a high, at par, or low rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debasing our Money cannot enrich the Nations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>The nation&amp;rsquo;s money can be commonly altered in three ways:
 When the value of the coins are altered When the weight of the coins are altered, yet retain their former rates When the standard is debased or enriched in the fineness of the gold and silver, yet the money continues in their former values.  We always see people trying to supply the want for money, while keeping its plenty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foreign Trade is the only way to improve the price of our Lands</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Money supply makes all things dear or cheap. This money is either gotten or lost in foreign trade by the over or under-balancing of foreign trade.
If we melt down our gold into coin, it would create a lot of money for a time. But we would not be richer. This money will be sent overseas if we:
 buy too many foreign goods, or maintain a war where we supply our armies with foreign goods bought with our money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much Treasure a Prince can save yearly</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>How much of the Prince&amp;rsquo;s treasure should be spent yearly?
If a Prince has £2,000,000 yearly revenue, and spend but £1, why should he not spend the other?
The affairs of Princes is far different from normal people. A King&amp;rsquo;s revenue is very great, yet if the Kingdom&amp;rsquo;s gain is small, this gain must ever give rule and proportion to that Treasure, which may conveniently be laid up yearly,
If he amasses more money than is gained by the over-balance of his foreign trade, he shall ruin his Subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Revenues of Princes can be raised</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>The Revenues of Princes depend on their riches and on the trade of their respective dominions. These depend on the constitution of the Countreys, the government, laws, and customs of the people. The Prince can only alter these with much difficulty and danger.
 Some Kings have their Crown Lands, Church lands, Customs, Tolls and Imposts on all imports and exports, Loans, Donations and Subsidies. Other States omit the last three and focus on the former as sales taxes and fees on the marriage money of women, licence mony upon all Victualling houses and Inkeepers, head mony, Custom upon all Corn, Wine, Oyl, Salt and the like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to enrich our Country</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Chap 2: How to enrich our Country and Increase our Wealth A Kingdom might be enriched by gifts received, or by government-to-government transactions. Yet these are things uncertaim and of small consideration when they happen.
The ordinary means therefore to encrease our wealth is by Forraign Trade wherein we must ever observe this rule: to sell more than we buy of theirs in value.
If we sell our excess worth £2,200,000 pounds to foreign countriess and buy foreign goods worth £2,000,000 pounds, we will get richer by £200,000 in money because the part of our stock not returned to us in goods must necessarily return in money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it necessary for Princes to Have a Store of Treasure?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>Is Treasuring by the Prince necessary?
Some people depend so much on their rulers that they call it baseness for their Prince to keep Treasure. They prefer that their Prince rely on the produce of the land instead of money, as proven in Caesar, Alexander, and others who achieved victories by lavish gifts and liberal expences.
They say that King David&amp;rsquo;s money passed on to Solomon was used mostly for pomp and vain delights, except the ones spent to build the Temple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selling Our Money in the Merchandise Trade increases our Wealth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Our annual consumption of foreign goods is £2,000,000. Our sales are £200,000. If we add £300,000 in money to our sales, how can we earn more money?
The Carrying Trade We can earn more money by bringing in more foreign goods to be re-sold overseas, since we would not need them locally.
 If we send £100,000 money to Amsterdam to buy Pepper then send it to Italy, it must yield £200,000, doubling the money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Excesses and evils in the Nation which decay not our Trade nor Treasure</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>If we mistake the nature of the disease, then we will not be able to have cures.
People want to to turn lending into charity and make the Rich lend to the poor freely because it would please God, and be profitable to the Commonwealth. What is the proof that trade decreases as interest rates increase?
It is true that some men overtrade. They buy Lands or lend their Money when they are grown rich, old, or some other occasion at high interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bankers and Merchants Exchange</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>The Author Gerard Malynes writes of the admirable feats done by Bankers and Exchangers in using the power of the Exchange.
But he has disguised his own knowledge with sophistry to further some private ends by hurting the public good. He should be discovered and prevented.
The admirable feats to be done by Exchange:
 To invest their money wherever in the world there is a gain in exchange To get rich but never meddle with any Prince&amp;rsquo;s commodities To buy any Prince&amp;rsquo;s commodity using public funds instead of their private money To grow rich and live safely at sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The different effects of Natural and Artificial Wealth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>In the latter end of Chapter 3, I wrote about Natural and Artificial Wealth. I showed how much Art adds to Nature.
But we need to set these particulars apart, so that we can better discern their operations in a Commonwealth.
Their effect is seen in the difference between Turkey and Italy. But it is also obvious in the difference between Great Britain and the Netherlands.
England&amp;rsquo;s natural wealth creates a certain disposition in the people and strength of the Kingdome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Diversity of Gain by Foreign Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>In the course of foreign trade, there are three sorts of gain.
 The gain of nation  This happens when the merchant (who is the principal Agent therein) loses. A nation may be happy while the merchant is not.
If the East-India Company sends out £100,000 to India and gets £300,000, the nation&amp;rsquo;s wealth is tripled. These Merchants shall lose at least £50,000 if bulky goods were traded according to their sale and use in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Merchant who merely Exchanges money by Bills cannot Affect our Wealth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>Some Merchants deal only on the advantages in the Exchange. They do not sell nor buy goods into the nation. This causes people to say that the money of such Exchangers does not make up the balance of our foreign trade.
They say that sometimes when our sterling money is undervalued and delivered here for Amsterdam at 10% less than the equal value of the respective Standards, the said mere Exchanger may take here £1,000 and carry over only £900, enough to pay his Bill of Exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The order and means whereby we may draw up the balance of our Foreign Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>The Balance of our Forraign Trade is the true rule of our Treasure.
How can the said ballance may bedrawn up at all times, when it shall please the State to discover how we prosper or decline in this great and weighty business, wherein the Officers of his Majesties Customes are the onely Agents to be employed, because they have the accounts of all the wares which are issued out or brought into the Kingdom</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Qualities which are required in a perfect Foreign Trade Merchant</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>We can show our nationalism through our own actions, instead of waiting for the actions of others.
I hope that you, my son, will be a merchant like me.
herein are my thougths free from all Ambition, although I rank thee in a place of so high esteem; for the
A Merchant is the Steward of the Kingdom&amp;rsquo;s Stock, by way of foreign commerce
a work of no less Reputation than Trust, which ought to be performed with great skill and conscience, that so the private gain may ever accompany the publique good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spanish Treasure cannot be kept from other Kingdoms by any Spanish prohibition</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>The gold and silver mines in the West-Indies owned by the King of Spain have the greatest value of all mines.
This allows the King of Spain to rule over many good Italian states and enlarge his dominions by a continual war through the power of his money. His money is dispersed into so many countries. Yet it is united in supplying his wants both for war and peace in a plentiful manner from all the parts of Christendom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Statute of Employments by Foreigners cannot Increase our Wealth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Keeping our money in the nation is just as useless as debasing our money because the causes of their preservation and production are the same in nature. The statute to allow free importation aims to employ foreign goods into our commodities. They say that the statute&amp;rsquo;s intent is for encourage imports to be employed in our commodities which will then be exported at a higher value than imports. It might seem as a good policy to increase our wealth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The undervaluing of our Money by Bills of Exchange cannot decrease our treasure</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/mun/englands-treasure/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>The Merchant&amp;rsquo;s Exchange by Bills lets them send money from one country to another country and receive it again at certain times at agreed rates. The lender and borrower do not need to transport metal money from state to state. These Exchanges are made between man and man.
They are not contracted at the equal value of the money, according to their respective weights and fineness, because the money-sender respects the debt and the terms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
