<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Supersociology on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/supersociology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Supersociology on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/solutions/supersociology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dogmism: Breaking the Cycle of Extremism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/supersociology/dogmism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/solutions/supersociology/dogmism/</guid>
      <description>Islamic terrorism became known worldwide because of the 9/11 attacks, which overshadowed previous attacks from the 1970’s. Since then, terrorism has been unfortunately and unfairly connected to Islam.
This connection is easily brought back up to mind and conversation whenever a terrorist attack occurs, whether it was rooted in Islam or not. Whenever a terrorist attack occurs, the common expectation nowadays is for it to be caused by a disgruntled Muslim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Council of Opposition</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/supersociology/council-of-opposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/solutions/supersociology/council-of-opposition/</guid>
      <description>In Hume&amp;rsquo;s essay of the ideal commonwealth, he writes his plan for the ideal government:
 The people are split into 100 counties which are split into 100 districts The people vote for a district representative. This creates 100 district representatives per district and a total of 10,000 district representatives The 100 district reps vote for 1 senator to represent their country.  Its unique feature is The Court of Competitors which we rename as The Council of Opposition and is made up of the losers of the senatorial race who lose by landslide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are Confirmation Elections?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/supersociology/confirmation-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/solutions/supersociology/confirmation-elections/</guid>
      <description>David Hume&amp;rsquo;s Ideal Commonwealth shows a federalized plan of government unified under an executive senate and a representative legislature. It includes an election system that is based on votes from the representatives instead of popular votes.
In Lectures on Jurisprudence, Adam Smith shows the advantages of the Swiss voting system:
When there are 100 votes and three candidates A, B, and C, the most odious candidate might get elected. There might be 34 votes for A,and 33 for B, and 33 for C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Solve Police Brutality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/supersociology/how-to-solve-police-brutality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/solutions/supersociology/how-to-solve-police-brutality/</guid>
      <description>This week, Minneapolis voted to replace its Police force with Community-based law enforcement. The reasoning is that their police force was abusive and ineffective.
However, from the nature of things, this is the wrong solution. If you had a personal chauffer (driver) who was reckless and has caused the deaths of others, you do not ban all chauffers and make people drive their own cars. Some people might suggest re-training the chauffers to make them more careful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constitutional Virtues</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/solutions/supersociology/constitutional-virtues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/solutions/supersociology/constitutional-virtues/</guid>
      <description>According to David Hume, a society is bound together by laws from a justice system. These laws were originally created to make people useful to each other and to maintain peace and order.
Initially, these were dictated arbitrarily by a chieftain or king. In time, as the society progressed, those laws were decided by the people themselves through a parliament or senate. This allowed the laws to suit the people and their changing situation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
