<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Simplified Tao Te Ching on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Simplified Tao Te Ching on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: What is the Tao?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-01-tao/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-01-tao/</guid>
      <description>The Great Tao is simplified to the &#39;Brahma&#39; to unify it with Hinduism.The &#34;One&#34; is simplified to the &#39;Supreme Tao&#39; which represents the superme consciousness. In this way, Brahma and the Supreme are analogous to the mind and consciousness, in the same way that a computer has a RAM and CPU -- Simplification Table  Tao Te Ching Hindu version Superphysics version Computer Analogy     Tao Dharma True Nature Design Specfications   tao rta dharma Mother Nature Design Constraints   The Great Brahma Totality of Existence RAM   The One Saguna Brahma Supreme Entity CPU   Mystery Maya Illusion Hardware limitations     Chapter 1: The Names of the Tao 1 The Tao is &amp;lsquo;nature&amp;rsquo; and has two versions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: The Tao or True Nature is Nothingness</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-02-nothingness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-02-nothingness/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 4: The Tao is Nirguna or Nothingness  1 The Tao is like the emptiness of a vessel. In our use of it, we must be on our guard against all fullness. How deep and unfathomable it is, as if it were the Honoured Ancestor of all things!
2 We should blunt our sharp points, and unravel the complications of things. We should attemper our brightness, and bring ourselves into agreement with the obscurity of others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 3: Perfection</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-03-perfection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-03-perfection/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 7: The Impartial Spectator 1 The Tao thus creates Heaven and earth to last eternally for the sake of the Tao or True Nature, and not for the tao or Mother Nature.
2 Therefore, the knower of the Tao puts his own person last position, yet will be in the foremost position. He treats his self as if it were another self* in order to realize his Tao or True Nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 4: Creation and the Two Forces</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-04-two-forces/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-04-two-forces/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 32: The Process of Creation 1 The Tao or True Nature, considered as unchanging, has no name.
2 In its primordial simplicity it may be small. Yet the whole world dares not deal with (one embodying) it as a minister. If a king could guard and hold the Tao, everything would spontaneously submit themselves to him.
3 Heaven and Earth (under its guidance) unite together and send down the sweet dew, which, without the directions of men, reaches equally everywhere as of its own accord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 5: The Supreme Tao or the One</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-05-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-05-one/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 14: The Supreme Tao or the One has Physical and Metaphysical Dimensions 1 We look at it, and we do not see it, and we name it &amp;lsquo;the Uniformity.&amp;rsquo;
We listen to it, and we do not hear it, and we name it &amp;lsquo;the Inaudible.&amp;rsquo;
We try to grasp it, and do not get hold of it, and we name it &amp;lsquo;the Subtle.&amp;rsquo;
With these three qualities, it cannot be made the subject of description; and hence we blend them together and obtain &amp;lsquo;The One&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 6: Brahma</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-06-brahma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-06-brahma/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 24: Brahma 1 There was something undefined and complete, coming into existence before Heaven and Earth.
It was still and formless, standing alone, and undergoing no change. It reaches everywhere yet in no danger of being exhausted! It may be regarded as the Mother of all things.
2 I do not know its name, but I call it as an effect of the Way or Course of the Tao. Making an effort further, I call it Brahma [originally &amp;lsquo;The Great&amp;rsquo;].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 7: The Parts of the Brahma</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-07-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-07-parts/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 11: The Aether The 30 spokes of a wheel unite in the one hub. A wheel&amp;rsquo;s usefulness is in this empty space in the hub.Clay is made into pots. A pot&amp;rsquo;s usefulness is in its empty hollowness.
An apartment has its door and windows cut out from the walls. An apartment&amp;rsquo;s usefulness is in the empty space inside it.
Therefore, what is empty is useful, what is not empty is to be worked on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 8: Karma and Ego</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-08-karma-ego/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-08-karma-ego/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 36: Karma 1 Before a man:
 inhales, he must first exhale.  weakens another, that other must be strong first. overthrows another, that other must be raised first. despoils another, that other must have gifts first.  This is called &amp;lsquo;Hiding the light of his procedure.&amp;rsquo;
2 The soft overcomes the hard; and the weak the strong.
3 Fishes should not be taken from the deep. Instruments for the profit of a state should not be shown to the people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 9: Types of People</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-09-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-09-types/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 38: Benevolence, Righteousness, Propriety 1 Those who possessed in highest degree the attributes of the Tao did not seek to show them. Therefore, they possessed them in the fullest measure.
Those who possessed those attributes in a lower degree sought how not to lose them. Therefore, they did not possess them in the fullest measure.
2 Those who possessed in the highest degree those attributes:
 did nothing with a purpose, and had no need to do anything  Those who possessed them in a lower degree:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 10: The Masters of the Tao</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-10-masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-10-masters/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 15: The Masters of the Tao 1 The skillful masters of the Tao in the old times had a subtle and exquisite penetration to comprehend its mysteries. They were also deep as to be beyond men&amp;rsquo;s knowledge. But I will describe them.
2 They looked :
 shrinking like those who wade through a stream in winter irresolute like those who are afraid of all around them grave like a guest in awe of his host evanescent like ice that is melting away unpretentious like wood that has not been fashioned into anything vacant like a valley, and dull like muddy water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 11: Self-Realization</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-11-realization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-11-realization/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 16: Meditation and Fellow-feeling with Everything leads to the Tao 1 The state of nothingness should be brought to the utmost degree.
The state of stillness should be guarded with unwearying vigour.
All things alike go through their processes of activity. Afterwards, they return to their original state.
When plants have displayed their luxuriant growth, they return to their root. This returning to their root is what we call the state of stillness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieving the Tao</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-12-with-the-tao/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-12-with-the-tao/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 62: The Reward of the Tao or True Nature 1 The Tao or True Nature has, of all things, the most honoured place.
2 Its admirable words can purchase honour. Its admirable deeds can raise their performer above others. Even men who are not good are not abandoned by It.
3 The offering of symbols of rank to the sovereign, who occupies his place as the Son of Heaven, might be so big as to fill both hands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 13: Wealth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-13-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-13-wealth/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 53: Excess Wealth is Contrary to the Tao or True Nature 1 If I suddenly became known and put into a position to conduct a government according to the Brahma, I would be most afraid of a boastful display.
2 The Brahma is very level and easy. But people love the by-ways.
3 The people&amp;rsquo;s courtyards and buildings are all well-kept. But their fields are ill-cultivated and their granaries very empty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 14: Society</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-14-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-14-society/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 29: Society 1 If any one should wish to get the kingdom or society for himself and to effect this by what he does, I see that he will not succeed.
A society is a spirit-like thing. It cannot be got by active doing.
 He who wins it destroys it. He who holds it in his grasp loses it.  2 The course and nature of things is such that:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part: Federal States</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-15-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-15-state/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 57: The State Should Have Concise but Efficient Laws 1 A state may be ruled by measures of correction. Weapons of war may be used with crafty dexterity. But the kingdom is made one&amp;rsquo;s own only by freedom from action and purpose.
2 The multiplication of prohibitive laws increases the poverty of the people.
The more implements to add to their profit that the people have, the greater disorder is there in the state and clan;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 16: Taonomics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-16-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-16-economics/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 75: Economic Policy 1 The people suffer from famine because of the multitude of taxes consumed by their superiors.
2 The people are difficult to govern because of the excessive agency of their superiors in governing them.
3 The people make light of dying because of the greatness of their labours in seeking for the means of living. It is this which makes them think light of dying. Thus, it is that to leave the subject of living altogether out of view is better than to set a high value on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 17: Requirements for Philosophers and Philosopher-Kings</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-17-reqs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-17-reqs/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 49: Equipoise 1 The sage has no invariable mind of his own. He makes the mind of the people his mind.
2 I am good to those who are good to me and to those who are not good to me. Thus, all get to be good.
I am sincere to those who are sincere with me and to those who are not sincere with me. Thus, all get to be sincere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 18: Virtues in Adversity: Patience, Frugality, Humility</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-18-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-18-war/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 67: Patience, Frugality, Humility 1 All the world says that, while my Tao or personal True Nature is great, it appears to be inferior to other systems of teaching.
But it is just its greatness that makes it seem to be inferior. If it were like any other system, only its smallness would be known for a long time! 2 But I have three precious things which I prize:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 19: Knowledge, Laws, and Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-19-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/laotzu/tao-te-ching/part-19-justice/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 70: Laws Should be Understandable 1 My words are very easy to know, and very easy to practise. But there is no one in the world who is able to know and able to practise them.
2 There is an originating and all-comprehending principle in my words, and an authoritative law for the things which I enforce. It is because they do not know these, that men do not know me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
