<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Laws Which Establish Political Liberty, With Regard To The Constitution on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Laws Which Establish Political Liberty, With Regard To The Constitution on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Liberty</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>The laws that establish political liberty, as it relates to the constitution, and thos= e by which it is established, as it relates to the citizen. The former shal= l be the subject of this book; the latter I shall examine in the next.
Chapter 2: Different Meanings of Liberty Liberty is the word that has the most meanings and has made the most impressions on the human mind. Some have taken it as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Constitution of England</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>IN every government there are three sorts of power: the legislative; the executive in respect to things dependent o= n the law of nations; and the executive in regard to matters that depend on= the civil law.
By virtue of the first, the prince or magistrate enacts temporary or perpetual laws, and amends or abrogates those = that have been already enacted. By the second, he makes peace or war, sends= or receives embassies, establishes the public security, and provides again= st invasions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Government of the Kings of Rome, and in what Manner the three Powers were there distributed</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>THE government of the kings of Rome had = some relation to that of the kings of the heroic times of Greece. Its subve= rsion, like the latter=E2=80=99s, was owing to its general defect, though, = in its own particular nature, it was exceeding good.
In order to give an adequate idea of thi= s government, I shall distinguish that of the first five kings, that of Ser= vius Tullus, and that of Tarquin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Government of the Roman Provinces</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>SUCH was the distribution of the three p= owers in Rome. But they were far from being thus distributed in the provinc= es: liberty prevailed in the center, and tyranny in the extreme parts.
While Rome extended her dominions no far= ther than Italy, the people were governed as confederates, and the laws of = each republic were preserved. But, when she enlarged her conquests, and the= senate had no longer an immediate inspection over the provinces, nor the m= agistrates residing at Rome were any longer capable of governing the empire= , they were obliged to send pr=C3=A6tors and proconsuls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The judiciary Power in the Roman Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>THE judiciary power was given to:
 the people, the senate, the magistrates, and particular judges.  How were their civil affairs distributed?
The consuls had the judiciary power after the expulsion of the kings, as the praetors were judges after the consuls. Servius= Tullus had divested himself of the power of determining of civil causes, which was not resumed by the consuls, except in some very rare cases, for that reason cal= led extraordinary=C2=A7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The legislative Power in the Roman Republic</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>THERE were no rights to contest under th= e decemvirs; but, upon the restoration of liberty, jealousies revived; and,= so long as the patricians had any privileges left, they were sure to be st= ripped of them by the plebeians.
The mischief would not have been so great had the plebeians been satisfied with this success; but they also injured= the patricians as citizens. When the people assembled by curi=C3=A6, or ce= nturies, they were composed of senators, patricians, and plebeians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Monarchies we are acquainted with</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>THE monarchies that we know do not have liberty for their direct view. The only aim is the glory of:
 the subject, the state, and the sovereign.  But from hence there results a spirit of liberty, which, in those states, is capable of archieving as great things, and of contributing as much, perhaps, to happiness, as liberty itself.
Here the three powers are not distributed and founded on the model of the constitution above-mentioned: they have each a particular distribution, according to which they border more or less on political liberty; and, if they did not border upon it, monarchy would degenerate into despotic government.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
