<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 4: The Influence of Material Objects on Morality as Utility on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 4: The Influence of Material Objects on Morality as Utility on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Extensive Influence of the Beauty From Utility</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-4/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-4/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>1 Utility is one of the principal sources of beauty.
A house&amp;rsquo;s convenience gives regular pleasure to the spectator. He is as much hurt when he sees its inconvenience, such as: windows of different shapes, or the door in a wrong place. The fitness of any system or machine for its intended purpose gives a certain propriety and beauty on the whole. It renders its very thought agreeable.
2 David Hume has recently answered most deeply, clearly, eloquently, and elegantly why utility pleases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Morality from Utiltiy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-4/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/simple-theory-of-moral-sentiments/part-4/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>12 The following can promote or disturb individual and societal happiness:
 the characters of people contrivances of art the institutions of government.  The prudent, equitable, active, resolute, and sober character promises prosperity and satisfaction to:
 the person himself, and everyone connected with him.  This has all the beauty as the most perfect machine invented for that purpose.
On the contrary, the rash, insolent, slothful, effeminate, and voluptuous brings:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
