<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Superphysics on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/social/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Superphysics on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/social/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is Society and Social Networkism?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/social/social-networkism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/social/social-networkism/</guid>
      <description>Overhauled on July 1, 2021 to harmonize Socrates with Hume and Smith
 Our proposed science of pantrynomics is based on a new paradigm that sees individual entities as naturally part of a larger group of entities called a society.
Unlike normal definitions of society*, our definition describes a society* as a kind of metaphysical organism or mind that is made up of individual minds that agree to be part of that society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Law of Social Cycles by Socrates</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/social/law-social-cycles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/social/law-social-cycles/</guid>
      <description>According to Socrates, all societies have alternating cycles that begin with democracy that switches to tyranny, then aristocracy, then oligarchy, and finally back to democracy.
 A democracy is dominated by working-class people. Its positive aspect is social justice, while its negative is chaos and mob rule. This chaos leads people to want order, paving the way for tyranny A tyranny is dominated by warriors, leaders, and generals. Its positive aspect is peace and order, while its negative is abuse and corruption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Pre-Crisis Years (2016-2018)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/social/precrisis-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/social/precrisis-years/</guid>
      <description>Our model, derived from the principles laid by David Hume, Adam Smith, and Socrates, designated 2019 as the spark of a global stagflation. This stagflation will increase from 2020 onwards up to 2030 when it will reach its peak, culminating in some kind of conflict. A stagflation is a phenomenon which has low employment and output while having high prices at the same time.
A Primer: The Metaphysics of Societies According to Eastern social cycle theory, history repeats itself because humans are bound by Nature which is dualistic in itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Collective Wave of Human Desire</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/social/collective-wave-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/social/collective-wave-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>Buying and selling are rooted in waves of desires, which manifest objectively as prices-particles, just as a subjective beauty contest is decided by objective beauty-points from judges.
The ideas of GDP, Inflation, and Wealth then all extend from prices. Pantrynomics is the branch of Social Superphysics that deals with the changing waves of demand in order to match supply to it as quickly as possible by using social contracts and pool clearing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
