<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Laws on Religion on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-25/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Laws on Religion on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-25/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Changing a Religion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-25/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-25/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>A PRINCE who undertakes to destroy or to change the established religion of his kingdom, must greatly expose himself. If his government is despotic, he runs a much greater risk of seeing a revolution arise from such a proceeding, than from any tyranny whatsoever, and a revolution is not an uncommon thing in such states. The reason of this is, because a state cannot change its religion, manners and customs, in an instant, and with the same rapidity as the prince publishes the ordinance which establishes a new religion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religious Ministers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-25/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-25/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>THE first men, says Porphyry, sacrificed only vegetables. In a worship so simple, every one might be priest in his own family.
The natural desire of pleasing the Deity multiplied ceremonies. From hence it followed, that men employed in agriculture became incapable of observing them all, and of filling up the number.
Particular places were consecrated to the gods; it then became necessary that they should have ministers to take care of them; in the same manner as every citizen took care of his house and domestic affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religious Sentiments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-25/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-25/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>THE pious man and the atheist always talk of religion; the one speaks of what he loves, and the other of what he fears.
Chapter 2: Motives to Religion THE different religions do not give to those who profess them equal motives of attachment. This depends greatly on the manner in which they agree with the turn of thought and perceptions of mankind.
 We are extremely addicted to idolatry, yet we have no great inclination for the religion of idolaters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
