<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 9: The Decline of Society on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-9/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 9: The Decline of Society on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-9/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Shadow of Shallow Pleasures</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-9/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-9/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Now comes the third trial. A sage* whispers to me that the pleasure of the wise is true and pure. All others are a shadow only. Surely this is the greatest and most decisive of falls? Pleasure is opposed to pain. There is a neutral state which is neither pleasure nor pain. It is intermediate, and a rest of the soul between either. Sick people say that nothing is more pleasant than health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three Pleasures: Wisdom, Honor, Gain</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-9/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-9/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>The first proof of happiness is the rankings of the States:  the royal timocratical oligarchical democratical tyrannical.  This is the order of their virtue as well. The son of Ariston (the best) has decided that:
 the best and justest is also the happiest. This is he who is the most royal man and king over himself, the worst and most unjust man is also the most miserable. This is he who being the greatest tyrant of himself is also the greatest tyrant of his State.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tyrant</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-9/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-9/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Last of all comes the tyrannical man. We must determine the nature and number of the appetites first. Everyone has the unnecessary pleasures and appetites which I think are unlawful. But in some persons, they are controlled by the laws and by reason. The better desires prevail over them—either they are wholly banished or they become few and weak. While in the case of others they are more and are stronger.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
