<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Corruption Of Despotism, Monarchy, and the Republic on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-8/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Corruption Of Despotism, Monarchy, and the Republic on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-8/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Danger of the Corruption of the Principle of monarchical Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-8/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-8/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>THE danger is not when the state passes from one moderate to another moderate government, (as from Edition: current; Page: [151] a republic to a monarchy, or from a monarchy to a republic,) but when it precipitates fro m a moderate to a despotic government.
Most of the European nations are still g overned by the principles of morality. But if, from a long abuse of power, or the fury of conquest, despotic sway should prevail to a certain degree, neither morals nor climate would be able to withstand its baleful influence : and then human nature would be exposed, for some time at least, even in t his beautiful part of the world, to the insults with which she has been abu sed in the other three.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sure Methods of preserving the three Principles</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-8/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-8/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>I shall not be able to make myself right ly understood, till the reader has perused the four following chapters.
Chapter 16: Distinctive Properties of a Republic IT is natural for a republic to have only a small territory. Otherwise, it cannot long subsist.
In a large republic, there are wealthy men of less moderation. there are trusts too considerable to be placed in any single subject; he has interests of his own; he soon begins to think that he may be happy and gl orious by oppressing his fellow-citizens; and that he may raise himself to grandeur on the ruins of his country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Corruption of Democracy, Aristocracy, Monarchy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-8/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-8/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>The principle of democracy is corrupted when:
 the spirit of equality is extinct the spirit of extreme equality exists  The people would think that they are on a level with those who command them. They would then want to:
 manage everything themselves, debate for the senate, execute for the magistrate, and decide for the judges.  When this is the case, virtue can no longer subsist in the republic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Empire of China</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-8/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-8/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>Our missionaries inform us that:
 the Imperial Chinese government is admirable it has a proper mixture of fear, honour, and virtue.  Consequently, I must have given an idle distinction, in establishing the principles of the three governments.
But I cannot conceive what this honour can be, among a people who act only through fear of being bastinaded.
Our merchants* do not give us such accounts of the virtue so much talked of by the missionaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spirit of extreme Equality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-8/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-8/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>AS distant as heaven is from earth, so is the true spirit of equality from that of extreme equality. The former does not imply that every body should command, or that no one should be commanded, but that we obey or command our equals. It endeavours not to shake off the authority of a master, but that its masters should be none but its equals.
In the state of nature, all men are born equal.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
