<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Supersociology on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/supersociology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Supersociology on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/articles/supersociology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is Social Topographic Behavior?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/supersociology/social-topographic-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/supersociology/social-topographic-behavior/</guid>
      <description>David Hume explained, in &amp;ldquo;National Characters&amp;rdquo;, that the natural environment of a society plays are role in its behavior. If a person were shaped by nature and nurture, then a society&amp;rsquo;s character is likewise shaped by its natural environment and the social cycles that nurture it.
Lord Bacon observed that the inhabitants of the warm south are generally more ingenious than those of the cold north. But where the native of a cold climate has genius, he rises to a higher pitch than can be reached by the southern wits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Regulation Requires Fellow-Feeling</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/supersociology/self-regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/supersociology/self-regulation/</guid>
      <description>Many liberals advocate the self-regulation as an alternative to regulation by governments and institutions. They usually borrow passages from Adam Smith who said that the government should not lay its hand on the freedom of individuals to act as they see fit. They say that invisible hand of self-interest is much better at regulating the self:
Every individual works to render the society’s annual revenue as great as he can. He generally does not intend to promote the public interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Feudalism?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/articles/supersociology/what-is-feudalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/articles/supersociology/what-is-feudalism/</guid>
      <description>Feudalism is a way of controlling huge land areas where each land is divided into fiefs under a lord who is under a king, who is really the strongest lord. Thus, it can be viewed as a delegated way of governance. Forms of feudalism were practiced in Persia, India, and Turkey. The opposite of feudalism is the republican city-states of Greece and Rome.
Feudalism&amp;rsquo;s key characteristic is that the land stays with the nobility&amp;rsquo;s family forever and is not subdivided.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
