<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Laws Directly Derived From The Nature Of Government on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Laws Directly Derived From The Nature Of Government on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Laws Directly Derived From The Nature Of Government and the Laws of a Republican government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-2/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-2/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>THERE are three species of government:
 Republican - this has the supreme power in the people Monarchical - a single person governs by fixed and established laws Despotic - a single person directs every thing by his own will and caprice   *Translator&amp;rsquo;s note: Montesquieu really classifies it as aristocracy, democracy, monarchy, and despostism.
 Chapter 2: The republican Government, and the Laws relative to Democracy A Democracy is a form of government where the people have the supreme power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Laws from the Nature of Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-2/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-2/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 3: The Laws relative to the Nature of Aristocracy In an aristocracy the supreme power is lodged in the hands of a certain number of persons.
 These are invested both with the legislative and executive authority. The rest of the people are, in respect to them, the same as the subjects of a monarchy in regard to the sovereign.  They do not vote here by lot; for this would be productive of inconveniencies only.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
