<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 4-Systems Of Political Economy on Superphysics: A New Science</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 4-Systems Of Political Economy on Superphysics: A New Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is the Political Economy?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1a/</guid>
      <description>Introduction 1 Political economy, as a science of a legislator, proposes:
 To provide a plentiful revenue or subsistence for the people by enabling them to provide it for themselves To supply the state with a revenue for the public services  It proposes to enrich both the people and the sovereign.
2 The progress of opulence in different nations has created two systems of political economy:
 The system of commerce &amp;ndash; This is the modern system best understood in our own country and in our own times The system of agriculture  Chapter 1: The Principle of the Commercial or Mercantile System 1 The popular notion that wealth consists in metal money or in gold and silver naturally arises from the double function of money as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Demand and the Demand Motive</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1b/</guid>
      <description>12 The amount of commodities human industry can buy or produce is naturally regulated by the effective demand in every country.
The effective demand the demand of the people who are willing to pay the rent, labour, and profits needed to make them and bring them to market.
Gold and silver are the commodities which best regulate themselves most exactly to this effective demand. They are most easily transported from where they are cheap, to where they are dear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumption Motive</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2g-consumption/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2g-consumption/</guid>
      <description>37 The exportation of raw materials is subjected to high duties, wherever they are not banned.
38 By the 8th George 1st chapter 15, all British exports were rendered duty-free except for:
 alum, lead, lead ore, tin, coppers, litharge of lead, tanned leather, coals, wool cards, white woollen cloths, coney hair or wool, hares&#39; wool, hair of all sorts, zinc, all kinds of skins, glue, horses.  Except for horses, all these are either:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free importation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2b/</guid>
      <description>16 Merchants and manufacturers derive the greatest advantage from this monopoly of the home-market.
The high duties on foreign wheat amount to a ban in times of moderate plenty. These duties, with the ban on the importation of foreign cattle and salt, are not so advantageous to British graziers and farmers as other bans are to British merchants and manufacturers. Manufactures, especially those of the finer kind, can be more easily transported than wheat or cattle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money supply</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1c/</guid>
      <description>19 People say that:
Consumable commodities are soon destroyed, but gold and silver are more durable. If not continually exported, gold and silver might be accumulated for ages to increase the country&#39;s real wealth. It is most disadvantageous for any country to trade such lasting commodities for such perishable ones. However, the exchange of English hardware for French wines is not disadvantageous, even if hardware is a very durable commodity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restoring Free Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2d/</guid>
      <description>40 It may be deliberated how to properly restore the free importation of foreign goods after it has been interrupted, especially when its local monopoly already employs so many people.
In this case, humanity may require that the freedom of trade should be restored slowly, with much reserve and circumspection.
If those high duties and prohibitions were all removed at once, cheaper foreign goods might enter so fast. They would deprive our people of their employment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retaliatory Restraints</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2c/</guid>
      <description>23 There are two cases when it will be advantageous to lay some burden on foreign industry to encourage domestic industry.
24 When an industry is needed for national defence. When a tax is imposed by foreign countries on certain products of the home country.
Case 1: National Defence For example, Great Britain&amp;rsquo;s defence depends very much on its sailors and shipping.
The act of navigation very properly gives British sailors and shipping the monopoly of British trade by: absolute prohibitions or heavy burdens on foreign shipping The following are the principal dispositions of this Act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Restraints on foreign imports which can be produced at home</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2a/</guid>
      <description>1 The monopoly of domestic industry is secured through high duties or import bans of foreign goods which can be produced at home.
The ban on importing foreign live cattle or foreign salt secures the monopoly of the home market for meat to British graziers. The high duties on wheat imports amount to a ban in times of moderate plenty. Such duties give a like advantage to wheat growers. The ban on woollens importation is equally favourable to woollen manufacturers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1d/</guid>
      <description>31 The importation of gold and silver is not the sole benefit from foreign trade. All nations derive two benefits from it:
 It carries out their surplus produce which has no demand at home It brings back something else for which there is a demand.  Foreign trade gives a value to their nations&#39; superfluities by exchanging them for something else.
The narrowness of the home market limits a country&amp;rsquo;s division of labour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion on Mercantilism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>1 The mercantile system proposes to enrich every country through two great engines:
 The encouragement of exportation The discouragement of importation  But the mercantile system follows an opposite plan with some commodities:
 To discourage exportation To encourage importation  It pretends that its ultimate object is always the same &amp;ndash; to enrich the country by an advantageous balance of trade.
It discourages the exportation of raw materials and the instruments of trade, in order to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foreign Economic systems</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9d-foreign-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9d-foreign-systems/</guid>
      <description>39 The political economy of modern European nations was more favourable to manufactures and foreign trade, the industry of the towns, than to agriculture, the industry of the countryside.
Other nations were more favourable to agriculture than to manufactures and foreign trade. The Policy of China 40 The policy of China favours agriculture more than all other employments.
In China, the condition of a labourer much superior to the condition of an artificer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Errors of the Physiocrats</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9c-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9c-errors/</guid>
      <description>24 According to this liberal and generous system:
A landed nation can raise its own artificers, manufacturers, and merchants best by granting the most perfect freedom of trade to the artificers, manufacturers, and merchants of all other nations. It raises the value of its own surplus produce. Its continual increase gradually establishes a fund which raises up all the artificers, manufacturers, and merchants that it needs.
25 On the contrary, a landed nation hurts its own interest when it oppresses foreign nations by high duties or prohibitions by:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Physiocrats</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9a-physiocrats/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9a-physiocrats/</guid>
      <description>Economic systems which represent the produce of land as the principal source of wealth 1 No nation has ever adopted the system which represents the produce of land as the sole source of the country&amp;rsquo;s revenue and wealth.
It presently exists only in the speculations of a few learned and ingenuous French men. It would not be worthwhile to examine at length the errors of this system which never has done and probably never will do any harm in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The unproductive class</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9b-unproductive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.one/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9b-unproductive/</guid>
      <description>14 The unproductive class is composed of merchants, artificers, and manufacturers.
It is maintained and employed at the expence of:
 the proprietor class, the cultivator class.  These two furnish the unproductive class with:
 raw materials, the fund of its subsistence, the corn and cattle it consumes while employed.  The proprietors and cultivators finally pay:
 The wages of all the unproductive class&#39; workers. The profits of all their employers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
